<?xml version="1.0"?>
<posts>
	<post id="http://news.cnet.com/8301-13577_3-20022753-36.html?part=rss&amp;amp;subj=news&amp;amp;tag=2547-1_3-0-20">
	<title>A Path the world isn't meant to see</title>
	<body>


Path.com has quite the vantage point from its San Francisco offices.
(Credit:
Caroline McCarthy/CNET)

SAN FRANCISCO--The offices of Path float 40 stories above the city in one of the upper floors of a residential tower just a block away from the waterfront, where the hallmarks of a young start-up--fridges of Red Bull, whiteboards awash in colorful scribbles, the glow of massive
Mac desktop monitors--colonize what would normally be coveted apartment space for one of San Francisco's most financially fortunate. There's a balcony with sweeping views of the Bay Bridge and the waters underneath, where on this sunny fall afternoon a lone kayaker in a bright-orange craft flits around uncomfortably close to industrial boat traffic.
Safely tucked away from the chattering, eavesdropper-friendly office spaces, neighborhood coffee shops, and bars where most San Francisco start-ups take root, Path's headquarters have a feel of forced remoteness and above-the-fray distancing. This is appropriate for Path itself: launching tonight after a deliberate attempt to stay in "stealth mode," Path is a mobile application that tries to carve a space for itself in the increasingly public world of share-everything social media by offering a service that its founders say is intended to be thoroughly private and intimate.


Path co-founder Dave Morin is best-known for having orchestrated and marketed the launch of its developer platform.
(Credit:
Dave Morin/Facebook)
 Before hearing about Path it helps to know a bit about its founders. One co-founder, Shawn Fanning, became a poster child for the Digital Age well over a decade ago as the founder of Napster (no, not the co-founder who was played by Justin Timberlake in "The Social Network") and the other, Dave Morin, was one of Facebook's most visible employees several years ago as he oversaw the launch of its groundbreaking developer platform. When Morin departed Facebook in January, leaving behind a far bigger, more powerful company than the one he'd joined late in 2006, he said he'd be working with Fanning on a new start-up. At the time, they didn't know what they'd be doing; they toyed with a few possible products before settling on the final idea.
So this is Path: it's a sort of hybrid of the mobile photo-sharing apps that have generated such a craze lately, and the private, on-the-fly group messaging services that promise an alternative to communicating in a huge social network. You share photos in a stream called a "path," but you can only share your "path" with a total of 50 people, and those 50 people must be pulled out of your
iPhone's contact list. (Android and BlackBerry versions are on the way.)
You can tag each photo--with people, with a place, and with a "thing" in it. The entire item is what Path calls a "moment." There are some unique quirks to the service: the list of contacts you see in Path isn't the people with whom you share your "path," but the people who have opted to share with you, a marked (if potentially confusing) contrast to the voyeuristic world of Twitter. When you tag a "thing" in a Path "moment," you can type in anything but are also offered a list of other things that have been tagged nearby as well as at similar hours of the day.
On this mid-afternoon in early November in the offices of a start-up with some of the sweetest views that San Francisco has to offer, Path tags that pop up include "epic sunset, hacking, Guy Fawkes, blue skies, launch night."
All in all, it's like a more tightly restricted Instagram, minus the artsy camera filters, but Morin insists that this kind of structure--tag this way but not that way, share with only this small group--isn't forced. Rather, he says, he's tapping into a natural desire to share details of the intimate and mundane that blossom early in a social-sharing service's lifespan--think back to the heyday of LiveJournal, or the community of photographers who flocked to Flickr, or the pre-celebrity era of Twitter--which typically erode as the amount of public content escalates, and along with it, the noise. He hopes that the unusual structure of Path will mean that those moments of quality and intimacy don't degrade.
"We were really interested in sort of trying to figure out a way to create something intimate on mobile that all consumers would like," Morin explains on the afternoon when CNET has dropped by for a demonstration of the still-stealthy Path. The 30-year-old presents his new company in a way that's nuanced and almost academic in comparison to the big, isn't-this-awesome onstage pitches he used to make to developers and press for Facebook Platform. He's sitting in a sparse conference room decorated only by two sunflowers floating in flat, square vases on the table.
 The soaring views of San Francisco Bay are out the window to his left, but behind a pair of wire-frame glasses, his vision is focused, undistracted, on the iPhone 4 in his hands. Scrolling through the Path app, he talks about philosophy and sociology, the books and research he's read, and the observations that he gleaned from his choice perch at Facebook that, oftentimes, even the millions of users themselves may not have realized.
"A lot of what we've built at Path is based on two peoples' research, Robin Dunbar and Daniel Kahneman," Morin said, name-checking the anthropologist of Dunbar's-number fame as well as the Nobel-laureate psychologist whose work in "hedonistic psychology" offered new insights into our perceptions of happiness. "We have two selves, a 'remembering' self and an 'experiencing' self, and they both are happy in different ways," Morin explains. "We've tried to build a product for both selves...there's a lot of experiencing in this version but there'll be a lot of remembering coming in the future." 
The distraction-soaked Web may prefer a simpler description, like that Path is a way to share photos of your cat with the people who actually would be interested in seeing photos of your cat. "I love mochas. My friends know that. My close friends know how much I love going to The Grove and having mochas," Morin says, referring to the mini-chain of coffee and sandwich shops that freckle San Francisco's caffeine-friendly landscape. "That moment on the broader social Web is probably not that interesting." The challenge, of course, is dealing with the immunity that has set in for millions of people who can no longer see a reason why their photographs of cats and mochas shouldn't be public. Convincing people that they need something when it isn't immediately evident isn't easy.
"If users want to share their photos with other networks, if they want to put them on Tumblr or Twitter, they're perfectly welcome to and we'll likely build those interfaces. They're not in version one, but we'll likely build them in," Morin said. He pauses and smiles. "We don't want to stop those people."
Missing from the room that afternoon is Fanning; he's in New York, where Morin had been as well until the prior day. The former Napster founder keeps a low profile, occupying "sort of a chairman role" and not making many appearances surrounding Path's launch, Morin said. Instead, taking his place in the conference room with Morin is Matt Van Horn, the company's vice president of business development. Eventually, they say, they want to put together a revenue strategy of premium features and possibly brand partnerships, but for now that isn't the priority.
"I'm not doing day-to-day business deals, per se, but right now I'm kind of doing anything, from anything related to fundraising to business operations to recruiting to marketing strategy, but relationships-wise--working on that stuff," Van Horn said.
Given Fanning's and Morin's tight connections in Silicon Valley, Van Horn's job has probably been made a bit easier. The company has raised a seed funding round of $2.5 million from Baseline Ventures, Index Ventures, First Round Capital, Betaworks, the Founders Fund, and a marquee list of angel investors like Saleforce's Mark Benioff; former Facebook execs Matt Cohler, Dustin Moskowitz, and Chris Kelly; Digg founder Kevin Rose; actor Ashton Kutcher; Drop.io founder Sam Lessin; and FriendFeed founder Paul Buccheit.
It's on the verge of moving into new office spaces, too, to another nearby tower with waterfront views. It's a bi-level office space; at 14 employees, they won't fill it up at first, but say there's room for a year or two's growth.
They say they want to be set up for the long haul. "I think we're building toward the trend," Van Horn says. "In 2013, there'll be more mobile Internet users than desktop Internet users." Morin jumps in and talks about how he aims for "slow growth," for giving the company and the community that they hope will bolster it some room to breathe, to unfold, to carve out its own path. Facebook itself, after all, had its roots in the austere, minimalist, and highly restricted before Morin's project, the Platform, flung the social network's meshwork of connections open to the Web at large.
"Every choice we've made has been intentional to build a 30-year brand," Morin says, pointing out the fact that they went through "a lot of negotiations" to buy the domain Path.com from a real estate developer who'd owned the domain for well over a decade.
They don't know what things will be like in 30 years, of course, or even 30 days. But here is this moment, for Path, right now: the people are a prominent founding team, big-ticket investors, and a community that has yet to form. The place is a highly competitive market flush with existing competitors, future imitators, and the temptation to cash out early rather than fight for lasting success. The "thing" that's taking over this moment, meanwhile, is the pervasive sense of being watched.
Beginning at a highly visible vantage point at the top of a tower dozens of stories above the world capital of digital media, the path of Path is paved with expectations. And, the doors back into stealth mode now firmly shut behind them, the company's founders don't have the luxury of keeping their own "path" restricted to 50 people.
</body>
	<comments>
	</comments>
	</post>
	<post id="http://news.cnet.com/8301-31021_3-20022731-260.html?part=rss&amp;amp;subj=news&amp;amp;tag=2547-1_3-0-20">
	<title>China unseats U.S. in supercomputer ranking</title>
	<body>
 The Jaguar has fallen from the top of the food chain.

When the Top 500 list of the world's most powerful supercomputers is released today, the Cray XT5 system at Oak Ridge National Laboratory and run by the University of Tennessee, called "Jaguar," will drop to No. 2 after a year of eating the lunch of every other supercomputer in the world. In its place will stand Tianhe-1A, a system built by China's National University of Defense Technology, located at the National Supercomputing Center in Tianjin.

Tianhe-1A achieved a performance level of 2.67 petaflop/s (quadrillions of calculations per second). Jaguar achieved 1.75 petaflop/s. Third place went to another Chinese-built system, called Nebulae, which achieved 1.27 petaflop/s. And while the news of China's achievement is not exactly a surprise, the supercomputing community in the U.S. is looking at it two ways: as both as an assurance that U.S. software and components are still elite in their field, and a wake-up call that the country's prestige in high-performance computing is not a given.
"This is what everybody expected. What the Chinese have done is they're exploiting the power of GPUs (graphic processing unit) which are...awfully close to being uniquely suited to this particular benchmark," said Bill Gropp, computer science professor at the University of Illinois Urbana-Champagne, and co-principal investigator of the Blue Waters project, another supercomputer in the works.

The benchmark he's speaking of is the Linpack, which tests the performance of a system for solving a dense system of linear equations. It's measured in calculations or floating point operations per second, hence flop/s. Not everyone in this field agrees it's the best possible way to compare machines, but it is one way.
By using GPUs to accelerate the performance of the Tianhe-1A, the machine can achieve more floating point operations per second.
"The way most of us look at the Chinese machine, is it's very good at this particular problem (the Linpack benchmark), but not problems the user community is interested in," said Gropp.
For those worried that this is a blow to the United States' leadership in supercomputing, it's actually not a huge cause for alarm if you consider the provenance of the pieces of the Chinese system. Tianhe-1A is a Linux computer built from components from Intel and Nvidia, points out Charlie Zender, professor of Earth Systems Science at the University of California at Irvine.




A timeline of supercomputing speed. (Click to enlarge.)
(Credit:
AMD)

"So we find ourselves admiring an achievement that certainly couldn't have been done without the know-how of Silicon Valley...and an operating system designed mostly by the United States and Europe," Zender said. "It's a time for reflection that we are now at a stage where a country that's motivated and has the resources can take off-the-shelf components and assemble the world's fastest supercomputer."
Supercomputers will likely get faster every year, points out Jeremy Smith, director of the Center for Molecular Biophysics at the University of Tennessee, so China's rise to the top this month isn't the end of the story. The list will likely be reordered again in June, when the next edition of the Top500 is released.
"What you find historically with these supercomputers is they become the normal machines five or 10 years later that everybody uses," said Smith, who oversees some projects run on Jaguar. "The Jaguar machine that we're so amazed at right now, it could be every university or company has one" eventually.
And of course these high-performance computer systems aren't just made to race each other, most scientists in the field would argue. They're made to solve complex problems, with eventual real-world consequences like climate change and alternative fuel production.
Smith argues that research like what's being done on Jaguar to solve the problem of superconductivity at high temperatures couldn't necessarily be done on Tianhe-1A effectively because it requires very efficient computing and coming up with the software on a computer to do that well is difficult.
But what China has accomplished is still important for supercomputing, argues Gropp, who called the number of flop/s Tianhe-1A achieved "remarkable."
"I don't want to downplay what they've done," he said. "It's like pooh-poohing the original Toyota. The first Toyota was a pile of junk. But a few years later they were eating our lunch."
It's not the first time that a non-U.S. machine has topped the rankings--the Japanese NEC Earth Simulator did it in 2004. The U.S. of course bounced back, and as of today has 275, or more than half of the systems, on the Top 500 list. China is next with 42 systems, and Japan and Germany are tied with 26 each. Still, there is concern that China's focused concentration of resources on supercomputing is fomenting a threat to the U.S.' long-term dominance there. But just trying to score the highest on the Linpack benchmark--something that any group of researchers with enough money could do fairly easily--is short-sighted.
"What we should be focusing on is not losing our leadership and being able to apply computing to a broad range of science and engineering problems," said Gropp, who is also deputy director of research at UI's Institute for Advanced Computing Applications and Technologies.
The Presidential Council of Advisors on Science and Technology (PCAST) is currently working on a report that addresses this exact topic, and didn't have a comment when contacted. Recently PCAST did release a draft of a document that calls for more funding for scientific computing very soon after news of Tianhe-1A's speed began to spread. And President Barack Obama weighed in briefly on the topic in a speech two weeks ago, calling for increased science funding specifically for high-performance computing.
But it's not as if the supercomputing community in the U.S has been sitting still while China sneaked up behind them. There are other projects in the works at U.S. labs that are planning on blowing Jaguar and Tianhe-1A out of the water in terms of speed.
Currently the University of Illinois Urbana-Champagne and the National Science Foundation is building Blue Waters, a supercomputer that researchers say will be the fastest in the world when it is turned on sometime next year.
The Department of Energy, which owns Oak Ridge's Jaguar supercomputer, is already looking at moving from the current peta-scale computing (a quadrillion floating point operations per second) to exa-scale computing (a quintillion floating point operations per second), a speed a thousand times faster than Jaguar is currently capable of processing at. It's a goal that's still a ways out there, but the work is under way.
"To get there in the next five to 10 years, to get to 10 million cores in one room, is a major technical challenge," noted University of Tennessee's Jeremy Smith. "It's going to be fundamentally different than before. It's a hardware problem, and getting the software working is a major challenge indeed."
For more statistics on the systems in the Top500 list, please see Top500.org.
</body>
	<comments>
		<comment id="0" responses="5">The US just seem to not get things right now. It's shameful.</comment>
		<comment id="1" responses="0">they used their "interest" very wisely :D</comment>
		<comment id="2" responses="8">I don't get this sore loser mentality. <br />The LINKPACK benchmark seems to be a good measurement as long as the American computer was on top, but if someone else surpasses it (even if LINPACK is a complete useless benchmark, but if that's the case, why was Jaguar tested under it), the practicality of the benchmark immediately become suspect.
<br />OK, let's say the Chinese computers artificially pumps bench mark results, but there's nothing preventing the US computers to do the same. It's not like the previous test was done with more than LINPACK benchmark results. BTW, isn't benchmark at the super computer realm designed to represent typical super computing needs. There's also no denying for the calculations captured by LINPACK, the Chinese system is doing better. There's no shame in recognizing that simple fact. So for at least the calculations capture by the LINPACK, the Chinese are taking the crown for this year. Can the Americans just accept that and come up with a better performing computer instead of being "sour grapes". Oh, come on, Americans, stop being sore losers, build a better computer and let the fact speak for itself.</comment>
		<comment id="3" responses="0">Sometimes what we see is not all we know. Failure mite be good thing to push us harder. No one studies the losers to beat them again.</comment>
		<comment id="4" responses="1">This puts an end to the "core war" as GPU's take their place at the top. China is doing the tough integration work that requires brilliant engineering.</comment>
		<comment id="5" responses="0">When these come out I like to point out that Linux pretty much owns supercomputing. This latest list has Linux at 91.8% of Operating System Family share, up from 91%. Top500 reports should always mention this, much like botnet reports should identify the compromised software running on the zombie PCs - but they don't.<br /><br />At lease Erica mentioned the word Linux once in the article. That's an improvement over the usual fare.</comment>
		<comment id="6" responses="0">I guess it will them count their interest on our money and government bonds better.</comment>
		<comment id="7" responses="1">I don't understand... the Linpack benchmark has been an acceptable tool for measuring super computer performance for so many years... but now that it places two Chinese super computers in the top 3 slots, we are to questioning its relevance for measuing the ability to solve the the types of problems that the user community is interested in.<br /><br />It sounds like sour grapes to me... it sounds like we have been beaten at our own game, so now we want to change the rules of the game so that we can remain on top by some other means.</comment>
		<comment id="8" responses="0">Quote: "So we find ourselves admiring an achievement that certainly couldn't have been done without the know-how of Silicon Valley...and an operating system designed mostly by the United States and Europe," Zender said."<br /><br />Why stop at OS? Why not request China to give credit for their achievement to Charles Babbage?<br />Even if OS designed in China, you're still going to find some software or hardware component tracked back to US/UK to console yourself aren't you? If it's a pretictable victory, you could've done that right?<br /><br />Give credit where deserved.</comment>
		<comment id="9" responses="1">by anonCNET November 14, 2010 11:29 AM PST<br />Actually the US has 275 computers designed to score high on an artificial benchmark. We just don't have the top one.<br /><br />Besides, it's not the size of your computer that matters. It's how you use it.<br /><br /><br />THAT'S WHAT SHE SAID!</comment>
		<comment id="10" responses="0">If the qualtiy of this supercomputer's design and execution is consistent with all the other Chinese-made hardware I deal with, there is nothing for the U.S. to worry about.</comment>
		<comment id="11" responses="1">if the us grounded half there army.. and put that money into schools, computers and social health care they would have the greatest country on earth..sadly that score falls to us igloo living suckers up north :P..<br /><br />I really don't think ppl are givving china the credit it's due.. it's the next world super power.. not the us .. not russia.. there sinking a ton of money in to r&amp;#38;d in ever field....</comment>
		<comment id="12" responses="0">One thing is for sure if were in China everyone who posted a critical remark would dead or in prison. Go China!</comment>
		<comment id="13" responses="0">I bet that they are overclocking the Intel/NV CPU&amp;#38;GPU to achieve this? ;)<br /><br />Maybe it is the same as running 3dmark? where some treakings in the drivers will make the benchmark score higher...but it does not mean it is better in running real 3d games...<br />Now where is the nt3dev guy? he should join us for everything related to China...</comment>
		<comment id="14" responses="0">Whether or not it is the fastest computer in the world is somewhat irrelevant, what is relevant is it can do what it was designed to do. It was not built to remove any super computer crowns; it was built with a very specific purpose in mind.</comment>
	</comments>
	</post>
	<post id="http://news.cnet.com/8301-13577_3-20022736-36.html?part=rss&amp;amp;subj=news&amp;amp;tag=2547-1_3-0-20">
	<title>AOL's 'Project Phoenix' e-mail overhaul is here</title>
	<body>


The newly redesigned AOL Mail, &amp;#39;Project Phoenix&amp;#39;
(Credit:
AOL)

Once ubiquitous, AOL e-mail has grown into such a punchline that the possession of an active @aol.com address is likely to result in many a playful Luddite joke. But on Sunday, AOL officially unveiled the results of "Project Phoenix," the long-anticipated overhaul of its e-mail system--and they even promise they won't make you use the @aol.com domain.
AOL's been engaging in an ongoing, across-the-board attempt to revive its flagging brand, but the timing of this particular announcement is telling. Facebook is rumored to be launching an expanded messaging service--perhaps as complex as a full-on Webmail client--in a company announcement Monday morning, so the odd Sunday debut of Project Phoenix could be an attempt to get there first--by a few hours, at least.
The full AOL Project Phoenix release will come next year, but at the moment is in a limited beta phase. Here's the lowdown: It looks a lot like Gmail's interface, with a few extra bells and whistles. There's a "quick bar" at the top for sending short e-mails, instant messages (which pop up in very Google Chat-like windows), and text messages. A side bar of "smart view" content previews attached files and maps of locations detailed in the message (AOL representatives assured that these previews only show up from confirmed contacts, so there's no chance of porn spam making mischief here). Messages open in a tabbed interface for easy flipping between messages and the main in-box.
Perhaps more interestingly, you can hook up additional in-boxes from mail providers like Gmail and Hotmail--ideally, other non-e-mail in-boxes, like Facebook messages, may be able to show up here sometime--and you also don't have to have an @aol.com in your AOL mail domain. The other domains AOL offers in the beta version include ygm.com (an abbreviation of its classic "you've got mail"), love.com, wow.com, and games.com.
That said, while the @aol.com domain may prompt snickering, people do still actually use it: AOL said in the Project Phoenix announcement that mail accounts for 45 percent of its page views.
</body>
	<comments>
		<comment id="0" responses="0">Out of all the webmail clients I use, AOL has the ugliest and slowest. I only have one because my dad forced me to get it when I was small. At least they're trying to make their awful mail look halfway decent. <br /><br />Still, even with a newer, more advanced interface, AOL has its reputation. Why get a Gmail lookalike that will still make people laugh at you when you can have the real thing? All AOL's doing is making the fogeys who are used to the way it looks angry.</comment>
		<comment id="1" responses="0">No way to get into the beta early I gather?</comment>
		<comment id="2" responses="0">What are they even doing with the AOL Mail RIA test? http://beta.mail.aol.com/32843-111/aim-2/en-us/Ria/Suite.aspx<br /><br />doesn't look like they've updated it in months ... they really need to unify/simplify their email platform. It's all over the place right now.</comment>
		<comment id="3" responses="0">Phoenix or not, AOL mail sucks up the (you know where). I can't believe it takes their servers 30 mins to an hour to process and display an email.</comment>
		<comment id="4" responses="2">Are they still around? Give it up, AOL is dead, few people even know they are still in business. They should sell their remaining assets and quit or re-brand AOL as a totally new company.</comment>
		<comment id="5" responses="0">The only modification to AOL 9.5 most of my clients want in the ability to export all of their locally-stored email to a better client.
<br />
<br />It would also be nice if it didn't constantly crash my client's PC's and/or slow them to a crawl....</comment>
		<comment id="6" responses="1">You know when they start copying someone else, it's the beginning of the end.</comment>
	</comments>
	</post>
	<post id="http://news.cnet.com/8301-17852_3-20022748-71.html?part=rss&amp;amp;subj=news&amp;amp;tag=2547-1_3-0-20">
	<title>Google engineer: Raise leaker exposed us to mugging</title>
	<body>
There are some things about which Google doesn't comment. However, it is entirely true that many Google employees are human beings with feelings, sometimes even strong ones.
So, though the company itself refused to go into detail after an employee was reportedly fired for leaking news of a $1,000 cash bonus and 10 percent raise for every one of Google's more than 23,000 employees, there are Googlies who are whispering that they'd like to say something publicly. They'd like some of the internal feelings to be made known.
What else is Technically Incorrect for if not to offer a public service?
While some Google employees offered that they were saddened at the circumstances surrounding what was another, slightly more lucrative, day at the office, others would like certain things to be fully expressed. And I do mean "fully." And "expressed."
One Google employee, in particular, has strong feelings. And they involve violence. 
This, according to him, is the insider's view: "The leaker was promptly fired because he or she selfishly and thoughtlessly put 20,000 co-workers in immediate danger of being mugged while carrying holiday bonus cash on their way home in the dark that very evening. And because the leaker directly disobeyed repeated and very explicit instructions from the top, not to leak this bonus news prematurely before evening when all workers were home safe."


(Credit:

CC Carlos Luna/Flickr)

Google gave employees the option of taking their $1,000 bonus home in cash on the day of the announcement. Which would undoubtedly have constituted a pleasant surprise for the families of many.
The engineer continued by explaining the implications of the leak to those inside the company who rely on confidentiality every day.
He told me (not via Gmail): "I would not trust that co-worker with anything important. This company's engineering practices rely heavily on being very open (among ourselves only) about most company plans, but that no-walls approach requires that we all be trustworthy and circumspect in what we say or write to those outside."
If you wondered what might have been the leaker's motivations (other than, perhaps, a job offer from Facebook or excitement about paying off his or her bookie), this Google engineer would like to shed some light.
He told me: "I think this person lacked the judgment to tell the difference between sharing really great news with friends, versus violating trust and putting others in direct danger. There was no reason for he or she to push the news out quickly via bloggers and reporters, other than vanity and misplaced loyalties."
Vanity and misplaced loyalties. Such human frailties.
</body>
	<comments>
		<comment id="0" responses="3">The former employee should go get a job at Facebook with the rest of those crooks</comment>
		<comment id="1" responses="10">Google literally gave them cash? As in $100 dollar bills? That seems pretty strange. Since when do companies pay people in greenbacks? It is usually a check or a direct deposit. Odd.</comment>
		<comment id="2" responses="5">Let me get this straight, the employees of a company that makes it's living collecting private information from its users, almost always without their permission or knowledge, are complaining their privacy has been invaded?<br /><br />Welcome to the world you helped create Google.</comment>
		<comment id="3" responses="3">So, the employees were being handed stacks of cash on their way out the door. Cash that the IRS would have no clue about had someone on the inside not spoken out. Now that guy who alerted the IRS of under the table cash has been fired?<br /><br />Google, your ability to BS the public is pathetic.</comment>
		<comment id="4" responses="0">give me a break.... googler</comment>
		<comment id="5" responses="1">Cash is SO yesterday. I would've thought automatic deposits would've been the NORM for any company, especially tech-laden, data-harvesting company like Google. Heck by now they probably have EVERYONE'S financial information, even those of us who don't work for them.</comment>
		<comment id="6" responses="2">One summer during college I worked at Kmart. Every Friday at 4pm they paid their employees in cash. I had my boyfriend meet me there to make sure I didn't get mugged.</comment>
		<comment id="7" responses="2">That is of course, ridiculous. Giving out $1000 in cash to employees is what put them at risk, not somebody talking about it. Did this person expect 20,000 people to keep a secret to prevent them being at risk?</comment>
		<comment id="8" responses="2">So the guy "exposed" Google employees to mugging? Google has no problem raping people of personal information anytime it wants (sounds like a new mission statement line to me).</comment>
		<comment id="9" responses="1">You guy's need to read between the lines... Obviously the muggers were the IRS</comment>
		<comment id="10" responses="2">Forget about the "mugging" claim, that is plain silly. <br /><br />The guy got fired, and he deserved it, for ignoring confidentiality requirement. In high-tech company, we sign agreements to not divulge confidential company information and that can include everything from high tech secrets to hiring practices. Every bit of information deemed "Company Confidential" *is* confidential. <br /><br />Professionals honor the agreements we sign. Amateurs find all sorts of foolish reasons to shirk their responsibilities. I hope this leaker has learned a hard lesson and will never again repeat this mistake.</comment>
		<comment id="11" responses="3">Funny. I've often had that much on me - and it is barely enough to pay for groceries for a family.<br />Maybe Google should move to a better neighborhood...</comment>
		<comment id="12" responses="2">I wonder if the moron who spilled the beans still got his bonus before they fired him...?</comment>
		<comment id="13" responses="0">What is a 'mugging' in the Valley? Is it a new Foursquare feature? Do you get a badge for it?</comment>
		<comment id="14" responses="0">Fire the project manager and engineer responsible for the illegal Wi-fi data.<br /><br />Google in 'significant breach' of UK data laws<br /><br />http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/technology-11684952</comment>
		<comment id="15" responses="0">That is such utter bu** sh**. If it was even remotely true there would have to be armed guards posted at ALL exterior ATMs 24/7/365. Keep drinking the Goole-Aid androids. It will help you "see" the muggers lurking behind the bushes next to the Google campus.</comment>
		<comment id="16" responses="0">That is such utter bu** sh**. If it was even remotely true there would have to be armed guards posted at ALL exterior ATMs 24/7/365. Keep drinking the Goole-Aid androids. It will help you "see" the muggers lurking behind the bushes next to the Google campus.</comment>
		<comment id="17" responses="0">Sorry about the duplicate post. CNET advised me the first "submit" didn't take.</comment>
		<comment id="18" responses="0">Folks, have you ever been to Mountain View? It is a very nice town. I lived there for 35 years, never saw any people attacking others in the parking lots and streets snatching purses or doing holdups. Come on, the employees could have carried a thousand bucks in their teeth and would have been easily able to get home safely. Where do you people live? Certainly not in Mountain View. Get real.</comment>
		<comment id="19" responses="0">Bunch of ******* - and the quoted employee should get toadie of the month.<br /><br />How can you trust or work with someone who is so quick to throw his fellow employee under the bus.</comment>
		<comment id="20" responses="0">Hey, its not like the leaker took satellite photos of where you work and where you live (including the car you drive in the driveway) and posted them on the internet. Oh crap wait...<br /><br />OK fine heres the Schmidt response to internal googol complainant....<br /><br />You could just take a different way home from work....</comment>
		<comment id="21" responses="0">Obviously, they didn't mean cash like paper money. "Cash" doesn't mean "paper money" anymore, you may read every day in a variety of contexts something like "cash back", or "cash reward", or "pay cash for house", or even "cash flowing to Wall Street" (obviously, they don't deal with truckloads of cash on Wall Street). Cash means readily available money in any form.<br />Paying taxes on "cash" bonus is not a problem, payroll department would include this payment in total in W-2 form, just like they used to do when they payed wages in cash (when it was - in 1970's?). Last thing Google needs is involvement in a large-scale tax evasion.</comment>
		<comment id="22" responses="0">The most common self dealing in U.S. businesses is officers giving themselves raises or bonuses while the shareholders get nothing. Most shareholders don't have enough say to make an impact. By the time the company coffer is empty, it's all too late.</comment>
		<comment id="23" responses="0">"...more than 23,000 employees..." What!!! Human beings work there? Based on the quality of their software and "support services", I thought no humans worked at Google at all! I thought it was all automated....</comment>
		<comment id="24" responses="0">He LEAKED with a RAISE ?<br />That`s HARD to do !</comment>
		<comment id="25" responses="0">Fear for their safety? You have to be kidding. Everyone already knows that googlies have so much cash that they use it for Kleenex. An extra K wouldn't change that balance very much - and it's not like you have people standing outside Google HQ waiting to shake down geeks for their lunch money.<br /><br />I rate the report: "Inconceivable"</comment>
		<comment id="26" responses="0">Truck drivers get this everday since every truck stop has at least a dozen magazines that make claims of truck drivers making around $70,000-$120,000 a year. The magazines are out where everybody can see them. We get asked all the time for help, (as in my car has broke down, I left my wallet at home, lost my money and I am travelling, Need some gas, etc...)The truth is the average driver makes about $35,000-$45,000 a year. Also most people think we carry lots of cash, we don't , most carry no more than about $30-$50 at a time. We are throwed under the truck by almost everyone every day.</comment>
	</comments>
	</post>
	<post id="http://news.cnet.com/8301-1023_3-20022750-93.html?part=rss&amp;amp;subj=news&amp;amp;tag=2547-1_3-0-20">
	<title>Netflix coming to Android theater--but not near you?</title>
	<body>



Netflix said this week that its instant streaming service will, indeed, be coming to mobile gadgets running Google's Android operating system--sometime early next year. But it won't be available on all such devices.
In a blog post late Friday, Greg Peters of Netflix product development said the incomplete roll out is due to the fact that there's no common way to ensure security and digital rights management across Android devices. Instead, Netflix must work one-on-one with individual handset makers to build in DRM.
"Unfortunately," Peters wrote, "this is a much slower approach and leads to a fragmented experience on Android, in which some handsets will have access to Netflix and others won't."
Peters said Netflix thinks providing its service to at least some Android users is better than nothing, adding that Netflix is continuing work with Android developers, carriers, and others to create a standard, platform-wide solution to the problem.



"Setting aside the debate around the value of content protection and DRM, they are requirements we must fulfill in order to obtain content from major studios for our subscribers to enjoy," Peters wrote.
 An Android-friendly Netflix offering has been expected for a while. In August, Gizmodo reported that Netflix was in the process of hiring an Android video playback expert.
Netflix is already available on the
iPhone and on Windows Phone 7 devices.
</body>
	<comments>
		<comment id="0" responses="8">Over and over again this is all you hear from developers,<br /><br />"Unfortunately," Peters wrote, "this is a much slower approach and leads to a fragmented experience on Android"</comment>
		<comment id="1" responses="2">Google needs to just buy netflix and be done with it!</comment>
		<comment id="2" responses="4">Netflix comes from my browser by way of flash. My N1 has flash and adobe air. Why not use the cross platform tools available? I understand the need to protect streamed rentals but how can they make such pointless blocks on phones when a computer on the same network has access.</comment>
		<comment id="3" responses="5">why do they even need DRM on a 'Netflix Quality' stream? people can *easily* pirate much better quality versions completely for free elsewhere. oh wait, this isn't Netflix's idea, it's the MPAA...</comment>
		<comment id="4" responses="1">This is total garbage. There is no security issue or fragmentation issue. Netflix works on Windows because they have a deal with Microsoft to shun Flash and use Silverlight. Netflix could build a Flash 10.1 compatible app or run through their website but they want to extort additional fees from Google to provide a dedicated app like they did with the PS3, XBOX, and Wii. Android is more secure than any Windows based PC. This is about the politics of licensing. It's right out of Hulu's playbook.</comment>
		<comment id="5" responses="3">Step 1: obtain boat-load of movies from Walmart.<br />Step 2: convert movies into .mp4 format with freely available open-source software.<br />Step 3: drop on phone and watch whenever I want because I OWN them for about the same price.<br /><br />(And no, contrary to popular belief, duplicating movies you own is NOT illegal if you do not distribute the copies and only use them as a back-up or for viewing on alternative players.)<br /><br />P.S. Anyone who says this is too hard has either never tried it or is a lazy pile who obviously hasn't ever had to actually WORK for anything.</comment>
		<comment id="6" responses="6">IMHO , one doesn't need Netflix on a cell phone. That is just plain silly. What sane person wants to watch a movie on a cell phone. Only nerds and teckies and silly teenagers.</comment>
		<comment id="7" responses="2">Is Android fragmentation the problem, or is it DRM?</comment>
		<comment id="8" responses="0">Because there's NO way we should be allowed to have DRM free non-system-hogging media streamed to our devices, right? I'll just keep enjoying my H.264/x.264 flicks with no DRM on a PC that's piping out to a 1080p screen. Who wants to seriously watch feature-length shows on a crappy smartphone screen anyway? Not this peg-legger...... yar.</comment>
		<comment id="9" responses="0">How exactly does DRM work with streaming Netflix anyway? Could a hacker record the stream, and the DRM is there to prevent that?</comment>
		<comment id="10" responses="1">I don't buy their argument. Amazon has a Kindle app for Android. Pandora has streaming audio. Both use DRM. They did not need to go to the handset makers to make this happen. I think MS just "encouraged" Netflix (it's partner) to delay the Android version to give Windows Phone 7 a head-start. There is no reason that you can't do DRM within the application. Lots of other apps are doing it.</comment>
		<comment id="11" responses="0">Tell the phone carriers to stop d**king around with the OS's of the phones and let them run as is and at their full potential without stuff locked or changed because it's on Verizon, TMobile, or AT&amp;#38;T, and we wouldn't have this problem. The carriers are the ones fragmenting the crap out of these OS's.</comment>
		<comment id="12" responses="0">I'm actually surprised it has taken Netflix this long to come up with an Android version of their service. Worse yet it's only going to be available on some devices. Bummer.<br /><br />Brett Miller<br />http://www.customsoftwarebypreston.com/android-iphone-ipad</comment>
	</comments>
	</post>
	<post id="http://news.cnet.com/8301-13924_3-20022746-64.html?part=rss&amp;amp;subj=news&amp;amp;tag=2547-1_3-0-20">
	<title>Air meets iPad</title>
	<body>
A report on Friday claimed "anecdotal evidence" of the 11.6-inch MacBook air cannibalizing the
iPad. Hmm...so, is that what Steve Jobs meant by iPad-meets-MacBook? 


MacBook meets the iPad. Either-or buying decision?
(Credit:
Apple)

This research note came to me Friday from Ashok Kumar, an analyst at Rodman &amp; Renshaw. "Signs of cannibalization: There is anecdotal evidence that the MacBook Air is cannibalizing the iPad. A fully functional notebook in a very attractive form factor may be resonating more with consumers than a content consumption only device." 
That "content consumption only device" being the iPad, of course. 
So, is this what happens when the iPad meets the 11.6-inch MacBook Air? Consumers walk away with the MacBook instead? 
If only partially true, it's an interesting twist on a trend that's actually going in the other direction. Nvidia believes next-generation Android tablets will obviate the need for traditional laptops, as tablets become more adept at multitasking and begin to approach the processing power of low-end laptops. 
And hybrids make this argument seemingly irrelevant. The Windows-based Dell Duo fuses a laptop with a tablet. If that kind of design proves popular, who needs a boring, old traditional laptop? 
For now, the smaller MacBook Air looks and feels a lot like an iPad with a built-in keyboard. Until we're well into 2011, we won't know who's cannibalizing whom. But my money is on the tablet doing the devouring. With the iPad leading the way. 
</body>
	<comments>
		<comment id="0" responses="4">Given Americans' contemporary tendency to solely consume rather than to produce, the iPad would seem to be perfect product for the (m)*****.</comment>
		<comment id="1" responses="0">If the Air is cannibalizing iPad sales it's probably because it's just the most recently released Apple product. When the iPad 2 is released the see-saw will swing back in the other direction. The iPad's been out for a little while now so of course sales will drop off a bit... especially when there has been someting shinier and newer released. Also, the holidays are fast approaching, iPad sales will probably pick back up as more holiday shopping is conducted. Consumers are waiting on the deals.
<br />
<br />I still consider the the Air a suped up netbook, but it is pretty damn nice piece of hadware. Depending on what's added to the iPad 2, either device could be equally compelling for those in the market for such devices.</comment>
		<comment id="2" responses="0">Well, as a former owner of a 12" Powerbook, this makes sense. A lot of us who loved our 12" fully functional laptops were waiting for another ultraportable in the 11-12 inch range.</comment>
		<comment id="3" responses="2">BUT?!?! the cost is like 3-4 times as much. NOT THE SAME DEMOGRAPHIC.</comment>
		<comment id="4" responses="4">Why don't they just make the Macbook Air have a multi-touch reversible screen and call it a day? Actually, they can do that and give people an option. You can get the ipad with no keyboard or the air with a keyboard. Same with the iphone.</comment>
		<comment id="5" responses="1">Apple is doing everything right except for form factors. If Apple does not do form factors herself, market will force her to.</comment>
		<comment id="6" responses="1">"as tablets become more adept at multitasking and begin to approach the processing power of low-end laptops."<br /><br />There have already been windows tablets made that have the processing power of low end laptops. im sorry, this is moot.</comment>
		<comment id="7" responses="2">Re: Apple New MacBook 11" Air
<br />
<br />YES - yes - yes, I love it and I want it BUT! i am not goiung to buy it, i want to i have the money and i did go to my Apple store here on the UWS in New York City to view it - BUT! There is NO! " Aluminum Keyboard" WHY Mr. Steve Jobs? You lost my sell.
<br />
<br />Billy Amato - NYC</comment>
		<comment id="8" responses="1">This isn't surprising, the iPad is an ergonomic nightmare. You're either breaking your left wrist holding it while bending your right one to type as you hold it in a position comfortable to view, or the opposite and craning your neck to look down as it lies flat.</comment>
		<comment id="9" responses="1">I own an iPad and really enjoy using it, but it wouldn't surprise me to see this new Macbook Air cannibalize iPad sales. Just look at the growing number of iPad cases with built-in keyboards. The tablet form factor has its advantages but eventually you get tired of holding or propping it up against something. It's fairly pricey considering it's not much more than a super-sized iPod Touch, and the on-screen keyboard just doesn't cut it for some folks. The price reduction and instant-on feature definitely make the Air pretty compelling. I think if Apple is serious about keeping the iPad around long term, it really needs to evolve into a full-fledged computer.</comment>
		<comment id="10" responses="2">One last annoyance I forgot to mention regarding the iPad is that for me, the portrait orientation is the most comfortable. But with a screen width of less than six inches, I'm constantly zooming and panning just to read the page. And some stuff (like Google's RSS Reader) doesn't allow you to zoom or change font sizes. Not to mention some apps (like Rhapsody) won't even rotate into landscape orientation.</comment>
		<comment id="11" responses="2">The problem is not the form factor but the OS. The Air runs the full OSX, you can install anything you want, and it's very flexible. iOS in the iPad may be great for a phone, but it is limited in its application, and very restricted in what you can and cannot run with it. No file manager, hard time going through attachments to emails, etc. Really why settling with something subpar and adjust your life style to it when you can have the full thing (meaning the Air)? It would be completely different if iPad would made available running OSX. But that would hardly happen, as OSX proper is just too heavy to run on the fairly basic ARM processor. <br /><br />(Obviously, the fact hat the iPad doesn't offer a webcam and no USB (both available in the Air), doesn't help either.)</comment>
		<comment id="12" responses="0">For me the Macbook Air is what the ipad had always needed to be. When the ipad was announced, everybody expect a tablet with Mac OS X. Yes, I understand that along the time the ipad had presented some benefits over the X, but we still are waiting a product more compatible and productive. Ipad as good as it is, it still being a luxury. Now check it out the macbook air. Its the ipad that we always desired on the beginning. <br /><br />Another thing: trust me, wait for the other innovations that apple has awaiting. I think that isn't a good idea to start buying macbooks air right now. Apple has presented a new tendency, a new approach and a new "technology". The next would be redesign all the macbooks, finally an SSD with the option of TRIM on the OS, imac could be touch with the introduction of launchpad, we are still waiting for the USB 3.0 needed on a portable product, lightpeak, the laptops would have an optical disk external like the macbook air and with the usb 3.0 established maybe the blu-ray could be an option. When they announce the new OS, they indirectly announce a lot of changes. I don't think that buying macbooks air (a first generation of changes, and of course not so stable, experimental, buggy and hardware problems) is a good idea with all the changes that are coming. You would have in less than a year a product not so up to date.</comment>
		<comment id="13" responses="1">I forgot something. If the macboor air its the "air meets ipad" why not expect that maybe the next generation of macbooks would have 3G/4G broadband coverage? The ipad also have it, so expect a lot of changes inside Apple. Like I said, its not a good time to spend money on this products. Maybe continue using your Compaq a little more and buy a better generation more complete of features.</comment>
		<comment id="14" responses="0">"Anecdotal evidence" - in other words who ever wrote this report was to lazy or incompetent to do any actual research and you were to lazy or incompetent to do the same for a real article.</comment>
		<comment id="15" responses="0">Before taking anything cited as coming from Ashok Kumar seriously, you might do well to review his execrable track record, as compiled by John Gruber...<br /><br />http://daringfireball.net/2010/09/kumar_track_record</comment>
		<comment id="16" responses="1">If this hypothesis is correct then I do not see Apple complaining because customer walks into store planning on spending around 600 dollars for an iPad and walks out with a thousand dollar notebook. Steve Jobs would be laughing all the way to the bank. That's not cannibalization - that is up-selling, a marketing effect that most companies aspire to but few achieve successfully.<br /><br />On the other hand there is a whole industry made up of pundits who puff up their importance by calling themselves 'analysts' who seem to be more wrong than right in guessing what is happening over at Apple. I'll take this one with the large grain of salt it deserves.</comment>
		<comment id="17" responses="1">Why not? The 11.6 is a featherweight fully functional laptop priced within reach of many consumers. The performance kick given to it by SSD should also not be underestimated. Even the slowest version will well outperform the iPad but offers a lot of the same portability and 'instant on' features. If the iPad's shortcomings when it comes to content creation and lack of connectivity options are a concern the Air offers a compelling alternative.</comment>
		<comment id="18" responses="0">"Nvidia believes next-generation Android tablets will obviate the need for traditional laptops, as tablets become more adept at multitasking and begin to approach the processing power of low-end laptops."<br /><br />That wouldn't work for me, and I suspect I'm not alone. One of the things I like about my modern laptop is that it's powerful enough that I don't need a desktop system to go along with it. Other than a Mac Mini in my entertainment system, I haven't had a desktop computer in eight years, and I do a lot of video editing, transcoding, mathematical simulation and other non-trivial computing.<br /><br />If a tablet is just "approach[ing] the processing power of low-end laptops", then it's probably not going to be suitable as an "only computer" the way that many current laptops are.</comment>
		<comment id="19" responses="0">I have "anecdotal evidence" that the sale of any single digital device often cannibalizes the sale of all other digital devices for sale at that same time, and in that same place.</comment>
		<comment id="20" responses="0">For one thing, you can't prove anything with less than a month of evidence. Secondly, who cares? The Macbook Air costs more and I'm sure Apple makes more money on it. I wouldn't really consider it a bad thing in Apple's book.</comment>
		<comment id="21" responses="0">Unless the prices of both devices become close and the battery life of the Air increases A LOT, then there will still be plenty of people pick the iPad over the Air. I thought Apple was leading the race for INCREASING battery life, then all of a sudden the Air comes out with only 5 hours? My two year old tiny Macbook gets 9 hours.</comment>
		<comment id="22" responses="0">It is nonsense to talk about cannibalization in a rapidly expanding market. Widening the product range is a wise strategy. Now they have 6 different product types so each customer can find the best for themselves. I would not be surprised to see more form factors targeting this market later. Like a smaller iPhone or iPad. They applied the same strategy to iPods. First offering just one model then diversifying into 3 form factors. This is what you do in a exploding market!</comment>
	</comments>
	</post>
	<post id="http://news.cnet.com/8301-13880_3-20022700-68.html?part=rss&amp;amp;subj=news&amp;amp;tag=2547-1_3-0-20">
	<title>Privacy concerns dog location-based services</title>
	<body>
It sounds like a sweet deal: report your location to a social network and get a coupon for discounts and prizes. The price? The possibility that advertisers and other third parties will know where you are and where you've been. A recent survey by the Pew Center's Internet &amp; American Life Project found that only 4 percent of Internet users have adopted location-based services, as Cecilia Kang reports on The Washington Post's Post Tech blog. That survey was conducted in August and September, before Facebook and Yelp joined Foursquare and Gowalla in offering coupons to users who check in when they visit participating establishments, which may include Starbucks, McDonald's, and other popular chains. (Lisa Barone describes the companies' plans on the Small Business Trends blog.) The crux of the matter for privacy advocates is that when people check in to businesses participating in social networks' coupon programs, they're trading a little of their privacy for the chance to save money. As the Electronic Privacy Information Center (EPIC) reports, third parties may have access to users' location history without the users' explicit consent. For example, Facebook application developers are able to store their own check-in data in the Facebook Places database and retrieve information from the database. But Facebook is far from the only source of "leakage" for this location data. EPIC cites an AT&amp;T research paper (PDF) that found some kind of private data leaked to third parties in all 20 of the mobile online social networks studied. The services examined include Facebook, MySpace, Twitter, Flickr, Foursquare, Yelp, and Loopt. While these services may have robust privacy policies, the advertisers and developers they deal with may be less secure. As Frederic Lardinois reported last February on the ReadWriteWeb, a site named PleaseRobMe aggregated information from several location-based services to indicate houses whose residents were away, making them easy pickings for thieves.
Keep the mobile-device trackers at bay Services such as Foursquare, Gowalla, and Facebook Places depend on location information volunteered by their users. But the trails left by mobile phones and other location-reporting devices can also be tracked by third parties without users' consent or knowledge. A white paper released by the Electronic Frontier Foundation (EFF) in August 2009 listed transit swipe-cards, electronic tolling devices such as FastTrak and EZPass, free wireless access points, and even smart parking meters as potential tracking systems. The EFF points out that location-based services can be deployed anonymously, although doing so would make the services more expensive to develop and deploy. But the researchers point out that anonymizing technologies wouldn't entirely prevent leakage of identifiable location information. For example, it's relatively easy to deduce the identity of users in areas with low population densities from little more than their GPS coordinates and a time of day.
Prevent Facebook friends from checking you in Opting out of Facebook Places requires changes to several of the service's default settings. Click Account > Privacy Settings > Customize settings. Next, choose Custom in the drop-down menu next to "Places I check in to" and select your preferred setting in the "Make this visible to" drop-down menu. Disable "Include me in 'People Here Now' after I check in." In the "Things I share" section, click Edit Settings next to "People can check me in to Places" and choose Disable from the drop-down menu in the top-right corner.


Disable the Facebook Places option that lets others check you in to locations, to prevent unknown third parties from tracking your whereabouts.
(Credit:
Screenshot by Dennis O&amp;#39;Reilly/CNET)
 Location-based services promise to make it easier to connect with family, friends, and associates and to be rewarded for being a loyal customer. But in their current form, the services make it too easy for people and organizations to access your private information without your explicit consent. While many--perhaps most--of these third parties won't misuse this information, others won't be so trustworthy. The reality of today's Web is that the personal information we volunteer to online services will be shared for profit with unknown third parties, and the services' promises of anonymity simply cannot be guaranteed. Beware what you share!
</body>
	<comments>
		<comment id="0" responses="0">I personally don't need to tell companies where I'm at every second.<br /><br />MENU &amp;gt; LOCATION SERVICES &amp;gt; OFF!!<br /><br />Thank you.</comment>
		<comment id="1" responses="0">Someone can already track you wherever you go if they wish to, and usually people wouldn't notice because they are oblivious to everything while outside their home.<br />This is a boon for parents who want to monitor where their children are and what they are doing.</comment>
		<comment id="2" responses="1">Because building trust and not being a helicopter parent are just totally outdated concepts, right? Bleh, I'm all for keeping kids safe and out of harm, but uh... monitoring where my kid is and what they're doing at any given time? That's too much for me.</comment>
		<comment id="3" responses="0">My tinfoil hat protects me at all times. Try em, they work good.</comment>
		<comment id="4" responses="0">I don't really mind third parties using info I give out, that is as long as I give it out. Tracking me without my knowledge is a bad thing but if I am giving that info out freely then let them do what they want,</comment>
		<comment id="5" responses="0">Simple - just give them the address of the nearest police station if they really insist on the data.<br /><br />Otherwise, I give them the zip code of the nearest big city to help keep the crime statistics up there.</comment>
		<comment id="6" responses="0">Nokia's Ovi Maps doesn't give out position info, at least for now. And it's a free, offline GPS app. It's such a shame Nokia persists with ancient OS and hardware.</comment>
		<comment id="7" responses="0">wow, another way for facebook to intrude on our privacy. i'd rather keep my location discreet than avail discounts and prizes. i feel like facebook is trying to take over my life. i have deactivated my facebook account and will be switching to a safer platform such as MyCube or Diaspora as soon as they launch.</comment>
		<comment id="8" responses="1">I agree with alan. It is quite amazing how facebook keeps coming up with new ways to compromise on user privacy and users fall for this as well. I too have quit facebook as it is simply too insecure to use any longer. Thanks for telling me about MyCube and Diaspora. I will have a look at them. Hopefully they will be much more secure than facebook</comment>
		<comment id="9" responses="0">Did you ever check out Whapee? Seems to be the most overlooked LBS for microblogging images.</comment>
		<comment id="10" responses="0">If I want to give my information away then that is my own prerogative. I do not need some organization trying to ruin services that they don't even use because they think I have the same beliefs that they do.</comment>
	</comments>
	</post>
	<post id="http://news.cnet.com/8301-17852_3-20022743-71.html?part=rss&amp;amp;subj=news&amp;amp;tag=2547-1_3-0-20">
	<title>Tomorrow's Miley Cyrus? A hologram live in concert!</title>
	<body>
Do you get slightly disturbed when you go to see your favorite performer live in concert and, because of your keen sense of visual synchronization, you see that they are miming?
Well, brush off your negative last-century attitude and get with the program.
In the case of Japanese singing star Hatsune Miku, the program in question is Yamaha's Vocaloid Synthesizing Technology. Oh, there's a real person's voice somewhere at the heart of it. But who needs real people when you can have a hologram that will never be photographed snorting coke in a bathroom stall, never sleeps with unsuitably older men, and, most importantly, never talks back to her record company?
As you will see from the videos I have embedded, Miku is not entirely real. Not at all, in fact. She's a hologram. Singularity Hub tells me she's the invention of a no-doubt fascinating organization called Crypton Future Media.

Real singers are reportedly not overly excited about lending their voices to this sort of venture. Which some might find strange, given how so many are terribly excited about lending their voices to Auto-Tune. 
So, Singularity Hub says that the base voice for Miku's performances comes from a cartoon voice actor.
Miku appears to be playing to ever-larger audiences. These audiences seem to get frightfully excited about a hologram who wears short skirts and suspenders and offers a sort of peculiar high-school coquettishness that some might find faintly disturbing.
One wonders if, very soon, Miley Cyrus will decide that it's a bit of a chore to do a tour, so she will hold simultaneous concerts in 40 cities worldwide, at each of which her Crypton Future Media hologram will perform.
Perhaps, in a fit of marketing magic, the promoters will announce that at one venue Cyrus will be there for real. But they will keep the identity of that venue a secret. The fascination, naturally, will lie in whether anyone manages to guess which venue that actually was.

</body>
	<comments>
		<comment id="0" responses="1">Just to be fully correct, hatsune mikus voice does not come from a cartoon. rather, her voice is part of a singing emulation program. you can feed the program any lyrics and pitch, and the voice sings it. its a very complicated program. its like getting microsoft sam to sing.</comment>
		<comment id="1" responses="1">Coming soon - Hologram Audiences to cheer on the really awful pop musicians to boost their ego and sales. :)</comment>
		<comment id="2" responses="0">My gosh. Truly disturbing.</comment>
		<comment id="3" responses="0">Super holographic party in the USA from Miley :-) cooool :-)</comment>
		<comment id="4" responses="0">Hmmmm, the next evolutionary step in pop music... Makes sense given the crap they've been feeding us since the days of Disco and Michael Jackson.<br /><br />I'll stick to following real musicians playing real instruments, thank you very much!</comment>
		<comment id="5" responses="1">What BS reporting - this is not 3d or a hologram and surely not a 3D hologram that works in a stadium. Yes there are reports of this all over the web - and the video - but this is CNET, maybe you can do more homework and understand the tech they used rather than copy and pasting this made up hype from junk websites.</comment>
		<comment id="6" responses="5">If that's a real audience in the video, this IS truly disturbing.</comment>
		<comment id="7" responses="2">"Real singers are reportedly not overly excited about lending their voices to this sort of venture. Which some might find strange, given how so many are terribly excited about lending their voices to Auto-Tune."<br /><br />That makes absolutely no sense. If a singer were to lend their voice to an animated singer, the animated singer would get credit. If a singer uses auto-tune (there is no "lending" a voice to auto-tune), the singer gets credit.</comment>
		<comment id="8" responses="1">This could only happen in Japan, no other nation would be crazy (in quite a good way) to do this.</comment>
		<comment id="9" responses="3">Could you post how this works, last time I looked holograms weren't possible or have I just jumped 10 years into the future?</comment>
		<comment id="10" responses="1">Any fans of Gorillaz out there? This is just the next step up from that. In the old days of Gorillaz, it would just be the holograms or projections on screen. But there's one thing you're all forgetting: the atmosphere. Listening to songs at home or on your mp3 player is nothing compared to being at a live concert.<br /><br />Also, it's Hatsune Miku. Not "Hatsune Kiku" or "Kune".</comment>
		<comment id="11" responses="0">So Sharon Apple from Macross Plus is now a reality?!?! Scary.</comment>
		<comment id="12" responses="4">This "concert" took place back on March 9th.<br />My question is why are sites like CNET <br />and Huntington Post picking up on this NOW?<br />If this were a TRULY DISTURBING event, <br />wouldn't someone have reported on it SOONER?</comment>
		<comment id="13" responses="0">Just thinking, but I wonder if these people know that there are loads of bands out there that play real instruments, but use Hatsune Miku (or one of the other voices) as the vocals for their songs. It encourages people to be creative and create great music without having to track down a singer. Just program it in instead!<br /><br />Also, these concerts are a compilation of songs from all kinds of bands that use the singer as their vocalist. It's not just one band using a (sarcasm quotes) "hologram" (end sarcasm quotes).</comment>
		<comment id="14" responses="0">I love Hatsune Miku. I have 5 vocaloid CD's, and a blu-ray copy of the 39's Giving Day concert mentioned above (which as someone said was way back in March).<br /><br />Regarding Miley Cyrus, didn't she already do a theater tour? I remember some of the guys at work mentioning they were taking their daughters to see it, sometime during the summer. I think it was a Fathom event.</comment>
		<comment id="15" responses="0">Miley is helping open the new Microsoft Store in Washington state.
<br />http://blog.seattlepi.com/microsoft/archives/228338.asp</comment>
		<comment id="16" responses="0">I've predicted something like this since Jurassic Park came out: CGI will take over the industry, actors will license their voice/likeness/mannerisms to studios, and never see the lot or a green screen, just take a check. And for some reason, the public will continue to pay. Heck, it's being done now, and it's good enough that we can't tell the difference.<br />Sincerely, <br />Rusty Shackelford</comment>
		<comment id="17" responses="0">I think that You should read this article. http://deliciouscakeproject.wordpress.com/2010/09/20/hatsune-miku-and-the-magic-of-make-believe/</comment>
		<comment id="18" responses="0">As excited as I am that holograms are coming along so well, why would anyone go see this? Is this any better than a CD? I guess the experience of the fellow people in the crowd, and seeing a hologram for the first time, but... it isn't really a live performance, so, I don't really understand how it will take off...</comment>
		<comment id="19" responses="0">Ok, this brings up some really mixed feelings. On one hand it's neat use of technology and it's really cool effect, but on the other, I find myself strangely aroused. It's like Betty Rubble all over again, only in 3D. She broke my heart when I was six and found out she wasn't real, but just a cartoon. Now all these years later, I'm suddenly attracted to............................wait a minute.............that wasn't Hanna Montana!</comment>
		<comment id="20" responses="1">Actually - it's not a hologram. <br />
<br />It's an image projected from below onto a glass or plastic sheet placed at 45 degrees to the audience. You can see the panel at the beginning when the cameras go off.
<br />
<br />This is a *very* easy trick to pull off and in a darkened stage, can be very realistic looking.</comment>
		<comment id="21" responses="0">The Idoru lives!</comment>
		<comment id="22" responses="0">Why does no article about this ever explain the "hologram"? It's like journalists believe that actual Star Wars style holograms have been invented and this is one of them. If this really is the first real hologram, that should be the most interesting thing because that's a HUGE breakthrough.<br /><br />Did CNN convince you rubes that the Will I Am was real??</comment>
	</comments>
	</post>
	<post id="http://news.cnet.com/8301-13924_3-20022711-64.html?part=rss&amp;amp;subj=news&amp;amp;tag=2547-1_3-0-20">
	<title>Time for an SSD? At $249 for 120GB, Intel thinks so</title>
	<body>
On Friday, Intel introduced its most competitively priced solid-state drive yet and will be selling the drive to consumers through major retail outlets. Are SSDs finally becoming a worthy upgrade? 


Intel&amp;#39;s 120GB solid-state drive goes for $249. Still pricey compared to HDDs but much more reasonable than a couple of years ago for this speedy storage technology.
(Credit:
Intel)

The Intel X25-M 120GB Solid-State Drive is set to be offered at Best Buy and Fry's Electronics for a suggested retail price of $249. Newegg is already selling the drive. Competitive SSDs would include a 128GB drive for $269 from Crucial. 
Though still pricey by traditional spinning hard disk drive standards (1 terabyte desktop HDDs can be had for less than $100), it's a dramatic change from two years ago when Intel was selling its 160GB SSD for $945. 
And now that drive is being sold at a suggested retail price of $415. 
Generally, the allure of SSDs--which use flash memory--is that they can be extremely fast, leaving traditional hard disks in the dust when reading data, and can be more practical from a pure technological standpoint. Particularly in thin laptop designs like the new MacBook Air or Sony Vaio X series that cannot accommodate the relative bulk and heat of a standard hard disk. 
Price has been the primary reason solid-state drives have failed to take the storage world by storm since their introduction to the mainstream consumer in January 2008 with the debut of the MacBook Air. That packed a 64GB SSD, sending the initial price of the high-end Air at that time to almost $3,000. 
Times have changed, of course, with the new 11-6-inch MacBook Air selling for $1,199 with a 128GB flash drive. And an increasing number of laptops from Hewlett-Packard, Dell, Toshiba, and Sony are sold with an SSD option. But it's still a pretty stark choice for many consumers. If a buyer opts for a 128GB SSD in the 13-inch MacBook Pro, the price jumps $300 over the standard higher-capacity 320GB hard disk. Add 512GB of solid-state drive storage to the 13-inch Pro, and it leaps a whopping $1,400. 
There may be a more cost-conscious alternative, however. Hybrid drives, which combine spinning disks with flash memory, are expected to become more prevalent. Seagate, for example, offers a 500GB Momentus XT hard disk with flash added for extra speed. It sells today for $129.
For its part, Intel is trying to make the migration to SSDs as smooth as possible. The Intel drive also includes a free cloning utility--Intel Data Migration Software, which assists in transferring information from the old hard drive, including operating systems, applications, documents, and personal settings. It can be downloaded free of charge here.
</body>
	<comments>
		<comment id="0" responses="8">still expensive</comment>
		<comment id="1" responses="2">Nice to see them coming down in price. For now I'm happy with my 64GB SSD running windows and most of my smaller programs on my desktop, while I have another 2TB of spinning disks storing/running everything else.<br /><br />Obviously not a practical solution for a laptop (unless it is a 17" that can fit two drives), but it's a wonderful setup for a desktop.</comment>
		<comment id="2" responses="0">OCZ 120G drives have been selling for even cheaper than this price a while now.... you don't need to get your Intel memo to write an article.<br /><br />And in fact, OCZ drives have better performance than the Intel ones, in many benchmarks check out anandtech for that.</comment>
		<comment id="3" responses="4">Too small for the price. With software and data taking up more and more space, this is a step backward in storage, even though it's a step forward in technology.<br /><br />They need a better sweet spot for me to even consider purchasing this. I'd like to see a 1TB SSD drive that is affordable (e.g., the same price they are touting the 120 for). Even a 500 GB would be OK. In a world where storage is now measured in Terabytes, this is just a teaser.</comment>
		<comment id="4" responses="1">I remember paying $400 for a 100 MB (not GB, just MB!) hard drive, back in the early 90's I believe.<br /><br />At the rate that prices are coming down, I would be surprised if SSD's don't become standard on all laptops and most desktops by the end of this decade... Great news for the end user as bootup and software load times will be dramatically improved and multitasking will be better.</comment>
		<comment id="5" responses="0">Nice price, the 80GB used to cost the price of this 120GB.</comment>
		<comment id="6" responses="0">Ah, the magic $249 pricetag that has always seems to begin the mass purchasing of any product. I wonder if these SSD drives will get down to reasonable prices ($100 for 1TB) before the next big materials breakthrough comes.</comment>
		<comment id="7" responses="0">The prices need to come down still by 50% for anyone to TRULY consider these. They're just still too expensive.</comment>
		<comment id="8" responses="1">We are very spoiled and ask for too much too soon.</comment>
		<comment id="9" responses="2">$249 / 120GB = $2.07 per gigabyte. A Western Digital Caviar Black 1TB hard drive goes for $90, just $0.09 per gigabyte. Or to look at it another way, you get 8.3 times more capacity at 36% of the cost. The SSD is fast but not cost-effective.</comment>
		<comment id="10" responses="2">No one have mentioned the WD VelociRaptor drives? At 10,000 RPM, the speed comes really close to a SSD but at a much better price. You can pick up a 600GB for about $280. 120GB SSD is too small, I can fill that up in a day.</comment>
		<comment id="11" responses="0">These are expensive compared to regular hard drivees, but in my opinion, offer the best across-the-board performance improvement. With the speeds of today's processor's and memory, you hard drive IS ABSOLUTELY the bottleneck, its just not as easy to see. If your computer is running "slow" yet your processor is not anywhere near maxed out, it's highly likely your processor is so fas that it's waiting on your hard drive. If you don't believe SSDs are worth the price difference, do yourself a favor and try one for just a few minutes. You'll be sold.</comment>
		<comment id="12" responses="0">Although I would say its a competitive price, it is yet still expensive. Until they can bring down the price of SSD's below $200, I highly doubt immediate and major acceptance.</comment>
		<comment id="13" responses="0">I have both a 128GB SSD (for my OS's and most used apps) and 500GB HDD (video, audio and whatever else storage) in my MacBook Pro. The optical drive is now external, as it is hardly ever used... and now with the upcoming Mac App Store, even less so. <br />Once you use an SSD, you just don't want to use a standard HDD again. 12 second cold boot times in OSX and 25 second boot times for Windows 7, not to mention less than a second to boot most apps (not to mention loading multiple apps simultaneously... HDD's just don't hold a candle to the SSD. <br />As with memory prices, SSD prices will continue to drop. Once it hits $0.50 per GB, the masses will flock to it, driving prices even lower.</comment>
		<comment id="14" responses="0">$100.00 for a 2 TB enterprise, 7200 RPM drive trumps this all day long. Too early still.</comment>
		<comment id="15" responses="2">I spent a lot of time getting my computer set up to where it is. For me, facing the daunting task of spending two days getting my apps all working again with the SSD running Win 7 (plus Adobe CS5 Master Collection) just ain't worth the hassle. Hopefully, prices continue to come down in time for my next computer build.. about a year or more from now.</comment>
		<comment id="16" responses="1">Why quote the price of Apple products as stunting the growth of SSDs? Pretty much everyone agrees that Apple products are priced at a premium. SSDs fit into many other computers, and Apple is no where near being the sales leader in computers. <br /><br />--mark d.</comment>
		<comment id="17" responses="0">no thanks. i'll wait the extra 40 secs to boot up.
<br />i'm patient
<br />and as far as how long they'll last.
<br />way longer than a diskdrive. <br />no moving parts and less heat.</comment>
		<comment id="18" responses="1">How much of a speed difference do SSDs offer over standard drives? I mean, when would you really notice it? Startup? Shutdown? Saving a word document? I understand the smaller size and less heat argument, but how much is the average consumer going to notice a speed boost on their computer from a SSD?</comment>
	</comments>
	</post>
	<post id="http://news.cnet.com/8301-1001_3-20022744-92.html?part=rss&amp;amp;subj=news&amp;amp;tag=2547-1_3-0-20">
	<title>Cisco hires iPhone 'antenna-gate' exec</title>
	<body>
Cisco Systems has hired the former Apple executive in charge of design and engineering for the
iPhone 4--the gadget that sparked a PR headache for Steve Jobs and Co. when its supposedly innovative antenna design proved problematic.



Mark Papermaster, 49, will oversee the creation of chips for Cisco's networking switches, an area of the company's business that accounted for a third of its total revenue in the third quarter, The Wall Street Journal reported.
The iPhone "antenna-gate" debacle eventually led to a high-profile press conference at which Apple announced it would provide free "bumper cases" to owners of the device. The cases helped prevent reception problems caused by an unconventional wraparound antenna that could be inadvertently blocked by users' hands.
The saga accounted for a bit of egg on the face of design-world darling Jobs--who in a sense was forced to slap a Band-Aid across the face of his latest supermodel gadget--and it may have been a factor in Papermaster's departure.
The executive's coming had been as unsmooth as his going: Apple had to tussle with IBM to hire Papermaster back in 2008.
On Thursday, Cisco announced its earnings and was cautious with revenue projections, owing, in part, to a drop in government spending.
Papermaster joined Cisco on Monday and will report to John McCool, the head of the company's data center, switching, and services group, the Journal reported.. </body>
	<comments>
		<comment id="0" responses="1">oh man...from now on, i need to test the Wifi antenna's of any cisco product before buying them...(Just Kidding..heard he is great engineer who excelled in chip design)...good luck dude..</comment>
		<comment id="1" responses="2">Well now we know which Network switch NOT to buy !</comment>
		<comment id="2" responses="2">It was never an issue for me, maybe it's because I live in Canada. Even if it was a flaw, it was blown WAY WAY over the top....you know the Samsung Galaxy S have worse signal reception than the iPhone? (though my friend had no problems with her phone)</comment>
		<comment id="3" responses="1">WHAT TOOK SO LONG<br />apple's ego is a present to the industry</comment>
		<comment id="4" responses="1">Good move Cisco. Finding one with clueless about "negative viral marketing from competitors" is a big step forward (seriously. The mouth piece knows everything is one you should be worry about).</comment>
	</comments>
	</post>
	<post id="http://news.cnet.com/8301-13577_3-20022714-36.html?part=rss&amp;amp;subj=news&amp;amp;tag=2547-1_3-0-20">
	<title>Why one VC believes there's more to social media</title>
	<body>
Facebook keeps getting bigger. Twitter isn't going away any time soon. Even the companies built to take advantage of these companies' social-media wiring--the Groupons and Zyngas of the world--have gotten huge in their own right. It's ubiquitous, and arguably mature.
So why does Sand Hill Road fixture Kleiner Perkins Caulfield &amp; Byers, which has spent nearly four decades investing in companies like Amazon, Google, Intel, and AOL, think it's the right time to start a fund specifically geared toward new investments in social media?
The venture firm, which had a Java-specific fund in the 1990s and launched an
iPhone development fund two years ago, launched its $250 million "sFund" for social media investments last month at Facebook's headquarters, and counts Facebook, Amazon, Zynga, and Comcast as investors and strategic partners. It's already invested in some start-ups, like pretty
iPad-oriented feed reader Flipboard and teen media-sharing site Lockerz, and some not-so-start-ups, like enterprise social media manufacturer Jive Software. What's next? CNET sat down with Bing Gordon, the Kleiner Perkins partner and former Electronic Arts executive in charge of the fund, this week in Silicon Valley to find out what's up.


Bing Gordon is the Kleiner Perkins partner and former Electronic Arts executive in charge of the firm's new social-media investments fund. 
(Credit:

Kleiner Perkins Caulfield &amp; Byers)

On how it all got started
Gordon said the sFund came to be when Kleiner Perkins' partners began looking at their in-the-works deals this spring and realized that a lot of them were, well, social.
"Last May and June we were just making an investment in Lockerz, we were deep in discussions with Jive, we were deep in discussions with Flipboard," he explained. "I can't remember when exactly they all signed but we were kind of in all those, and were realizing that we're meeting these companies, we're looking at them through a lens of how smart are they about social. Through Zynga (an existing portfolio company) and talking to some big partners of various kinds, we just realized that the number of people in the world who understand how this really works is limited. So we got some insight along the way."
On how he hopes a social-media fund will help like-minded entrepreneurs
The entrepreneurial lifestyle is often a solitary one, and so Gordon said he hopes to change that somewhat. "Being the CEO and entrepreneur is pretty damned lonely," he admitted. "The only time it's not lonely is when you've got a bunch of investors fighting to get a prom date. But other than that it's just lonesome to be in charge, so to get together with other people with the same vision on the same mission who don't compete is up-leveling and also reassuring."
There will be formal events for portfolio companies, too, something to the tune of what investor-slash-incubator programs like TechStars and Y Combinator have popularized over the past few years. "(We'll) get everyone together in a room somewhere in kind of a mini-symposium two or three times a year. That's what we've done with the iFund...we bring in outside speakers, (and there's) strong support from Apple."
On why he thinks the supposed limits of social networks are obsolete
Many arguments in favor of limits to online social networking invoke Dunbar's number, the figure proposed by anthropologist Robin Dunbar that suggests that the number of real human relationships that a given individual can have is limited to about 150. That's something that could spell less than sunny forecasts for a industry in which social connections need to keep escalating in order for profits to keep expanding in turn.
Bing Gordon's take is that those limits are going away in the first place.
"Dunbar's number is changing because of the efficiency of social networks. We're going to be able to keep 500 relationships warmed up instead of 120," Gordon said. "Social networks improve social capital so efficiently that more people are doing it. People who start using social networks don't stop. There are just too many advantages. You meet significant others, you get a job, you find out what's going on, you save time."
On how the sFund actually makes investments
No, it's not an early-stage fund or an incubator, Gordon explained. "What we said is, for the first time for Kleiner, that the sFund will invest as little as $100,000, as much as $100 million. It's a sense that there's so much going on and there's such big players at risk who need to be reinvented that we want to play at both ends."
As for the actual structure of it: "The sFund is actually two pieces. There's a set of new, limited-partner investors. That's a fund, and then there's an initiative where we carve out money from existing Kleiner Perkins funds and the two invest side-by-side. Kleiner did this in the 1990s with the Java fund."
On whether there are too many faddish social-media apps getting funding at the moment
When CNET sat down with Gordon, tech blogs and mainstream news outlets alike were (and still are, for that matter) filled with reports about the fast-growing, trendy, and often questionably viable social-media companies over which investors are going nuts. Given the low barrier to entry, social media seems like a field that can very easily attract loads of complete flops.
"It's a rising tide. On average it lifts all boats, but some boats are going to turn out to have leaks and some boats are going to have bad navigators and they're going to end up on reefs," Gordon said. He said there was similar sentiment about Kleiner Perkins' iFund. "A couple years ago when Kleiner announced its iFund, there were many skeptics--many skeptics who became late-stage investors in iFund companies. I think that's what an investment thesis is. We think this is going to be good. Other people don't. OK."
On the recent trend of start-ups "flipping" early to bigger buyers rather than trying to grow on their own
This is one where Gordon was ambiguous. Lately, there's been an apparent uptick in companies like Google and Facebook (and to a lesser extent, AOL) snapping up small social-media start-ups and often shutting them down in favor of integrating the founding team into the new parent company's executive ranks. Could any of those start-ups have had the chance to grow into real businesses, or were they getting speedy bailouts?
Gordon amusingly referred to the investor's side of this controversy as "when to hold 'em or when to fold 'em."
"I think if you start a company, and you have a vision, and you change the vision, just do it with honor," Gordon explained. "I was talking to one guy who's like, 27 years old, and he started a company, and I said, 'Dude, if this thing works you could make 10 million bucks in a year. After that it's going to be a boring company. But go do it real fast, because in your 20s to have $5 or $10 million in your pocket changes your whole life. This is not a potential Internet treasure, this is a life foundation. Run like hell. And that's what he did--I think it's just important for every person to understand their goals."
On his distaste for lazy zillionaires
Start-ups cashing out quickly might not irk Gordon, but he said he can't stand it when people cash out and zone out.
"I do have a bias against people who retire, I have to admit," he related. "I hate seeing high-value people stop. I kind of think it's a sin. I can understand it, but it's hard for me to forgive. I understand 'go fallow,' I understand being burned out, but I don't understand giving up on being productive...I just recoil when I see people who've made money and stop. It's kind of like having a sports
car that never gets driven." On one market where investments in social technology could really change things
Education reform is a hot topic, but repeated efforts to shake up the U.S. public school system have only seemed to make the dire situation more prominent. Gordon thinks it's time for private enterprise--namely, Silicon Valley--to step in, but to proceed with caution. "I'd like to get involved in the 'game-ification' of education," Gordon explained, talking about how it was evident in his years at Electronic Arts that video games with no ostensible academic slant could still manage to teach kids a thing or two. "I have mixed feelings about it, and here's why I'm mixed--every other investor thinks it's a bad idea, because they've been burned so often...What you don't want to do is get mediocre educators and mediocre technology creators teaming up thinking they deserve to be rich. But I say there's educators now who've grown up since Nintendo and on the Web who are terrific educators and terrific thinkers about technology." On his dream investment (no, really)
"I have a daughter who's a senior at Yale," Gordon said. "She's a Swahili-speaking African-studies major who wants to work in television. I would love to invest in her television production company. I think that'd be really cool." He paused. "With Tina Fey as her co-founder." </body>
	<comments>
		<comment id="0" responses="0">A Facebook friend averages out a lot less than a real friend.<br />Most of these friends are not best friends, but acquaintances who are useful for some things.</comment>
	</comments>
	</post>
	<post id="http://news.cnet.com/2300-1041_3-10005558.html?part=rss&amp;amp;subj=news&amp;amp;tag=2547-1_3-0-20">
	<title>Top-rated reviews of the week (photos)</title>
	<comments>
	</comments>
	</post>
	<post id="http://news.cnet.com/8301-17852_3-20022722-71.html?part=rss&amp;amp;subj=news&amp;amp;tag=2547-1_3-0-20">
	<title>Twitter airport bomb joker loses appeal, tweeters revolt</title>
	<body>
The British are renowned for their sense of humor. It is, indeed, one of the only reliable British exports over the last 40 years. Together with airlines, Carey Mulligan, Cadbury's chocolate.
So you might have thought that even judges in a dreary place like Doncaster, U.K. have the ability to estimate when something might be intended to be a joke.
It seems not. As Paul Chambers, the man who tweeted his frustration about the possibility of a canceled flight, has lost his appeal against what some might think is one of the more putrid convictions of recent times.
Should you have been yourself incarcerated for jestingly suggesting that the TSA's naked screeners can't afford online porn, here is what Paul Chambers tweeted about Robin Hood airport in Doncaster: "Robin Hood airport is closed. You've got a week and a bit to get your sh*t together, otherwise I'm blowing the airport sky high!!"
His tweet was seen by an airport manager, who sent it on to his manager, even though it was not deemed credible.
Naturally, it ended up before the eyes of policemen and Chambers was arrested and charged with "sending by a public communications network a message that was grossly offensive or of an indecent, obscene or menacing character contrary to Section 127 of the Communications Act 2003."


(Credit:
Screenshot: Chris Matyszczyk/CNET)

Oh, of course he was found guilty. But everyone thought that, on appeal, a judge in Doncaster might see the joke. Or, at least, sense.
Perhaps everyone believes that all kittens, in a former life, were hangmen. 
For Chambers' appeal was denied and, as if to show just how cheery the British judicial system can be (at least in Doncaster), he was ordered to pay a further 2,000 pounds in prosecution costs. 
You might well believe that Chambers' tweet wasn't particularly funny. But, as with so many pieces of communication one encounters, it would surely have been fairly clear to anyone not made of metal and foam that it was meant to be funny.
In order to make the point, his fellow tittering Twitterers decided to repeat Chambers' threat. Over and over again. Using the hashtag #IamSpartacus, they inundated the Interwebs with threats aimed at Robin Hood airport. 
I feel readers might be especially moved by a tweet from Dara O'Briain: "Robin Hood! All your base are belong to us! Somebody set up us the Bomb! #iamspartacus #butimalsoanerd"
Some might also feel uplifted by Hugh Miller's tweet: "Anyone else think this #TwitterJokeTrial has been blown up out of proportion? #IAmSpartacus."
You might have imagined that some enterprising journalists might have asked the local South Yorkshire Police whether they would attempt to prosecute all of the more than 5,000 threatening joke-tweeters.
Well, the Associated Press did. The police no doubt thought about it for a vastly long time, balancing the hope of overtime with the possibility that Doncaster might enjoy perhaps the greatest march of the reasonable since Robin Hood himself prowled the local forests, before reportedly replying: "No."
Chambers' lawyer, David Allen Green told the AP his client is mulling his next legal option.
Many might feel that those who truly intend to bomb airports don't tend to tweet about it beforehand. Still, Chambers tweeted that something good has already come out of his latest setback: "While I cannot believe this whole #iamspartacus thing, my dad texting me "Btw, iamspartacus as well" may be the coolest thing ever."
One can only hope that Britain's two-headed new government might decide to intervene in what many feel is a wrong-headed decision. I am sure there are many employees of Robin Hood airport who wish they would. Otherwise, well, who knows? 
</body>
	<comments>
		<comment id="0" responses="2">Generally speaking, I find most Tweets and Twitterers revolting anyways.</comment>
		<comment id="1" responses="0">You missed out Stephen Fry has offered to pay the court fine.</comment>
		<comment id="2" responses="5">"British humor"....another of life's oxymorons.</comment>
		<comment id="3" responses="2">Why is everything so complicated nowadays, things use to be so simple.</comment>
		<comment id="4" responses="0">OK, this is another stupid political statement from this dude.</comment>
		<comment id="5" responses="3">Really who cares? Some moron makes a joke that's not even funny, and I'm sorry how stupid do you have to be to use "bomb" and "airport" in the same sentence since 9/11 and expect the police to not come talk to you?<br /><br />Just another reason twitter needs to die already. I will be glad in a few years when Twitter is just a pop culture memory... and a bad one.</comment>
		<comment id="6" responses="2">Verbal spam. Junk texting. I have yet to see a tweet that I thought was clever. How stupid do you have to be to send tweets to the airport you are in threatening to blow it up? That's what tweeting does-it allows you to do something that under normal circumstances you would never think of doing.</comment>
		<comment id="7" responses="0">Just stupid. 0 tolerance of = 0 common sense. Can't take all this ridiculous paranoia any more. An elementary school kid gets suspended for having a butterknife in his lunch, I mean ***...</comment>
		<comment id="8" responses="1">It's not funny, and they need to make him an example. <br />A violent statement can be humorous because in our normal experience such an event is wildly ridiculous and over the top; beyond reality - hence unexpected and funny. If the violent statement matches our normal experience, it becomes a threat. Today, our normal experience is that fanatical people want to kill us in the most spectacular way possible. That is reality. Ever jokingly tell a friend, "Dude, I'm so going to kill you"? Go say that to a police officer. It's obviously humor, right?</comment>
		<comment id="9" responses="2">It was tacky, but the English are paranoid as crap &amp;#38; always have been, especially in airports. <br /><br />In 1987, when we were changing from a UK duty station back Stateside, we had an Apple 2c that we took with us at my insistence; it would be a while before the 2e got back in our possession (it takes up to a year to get military shipments of your household goods back in your possession). I wasn't about to do without a computer, even if I had to share with my husband. <br /><br />We carefully buried the ET monitor in the checked luggage, mostly to pad it even more than the bubble wrap did, but we carried the CPU with us, including the rather large power supply. I was the one who insisted on this, thus, the one carrying it. I'm female. Keep the year in mind here. I put the thing on the belt for X-Ray at Heathrow, all of a sudden, the tech bellows, "It's a bomb!" &amp;#38; ducks under the counter! I said, "It's not a bomb, it's an Apple 2c portable computer." His head came up long enough to inform me that, "Women don't use computers." I said, "OK, so I'm a guy in drag, but it's STILL a computer. If you like, I'll open it up &amp;#38; show it to you." The head popped up again, nodded, &amp;#38; disappeared. So, I unzip the thing, while everyone around backs up about 10 ft. "See?" I said, "An Apple 2 c computer. The big block you saw on the X-Ray is the power supply." The head surfaced briefly, ducked down, &amp;#38; after a few minutes (the time it took the guy to compute that a female - or a guy in drag - had really just opened up an Apple 2 c computer &amp;#38; that nothing had exploded), the head popped back up cautiously. I gently turned it all the way around so he could see it. He gingerly poked &amp;#38; prodded. During this time, the Bobbies had come by, looked at it, sighed disgustedly, &amp;#38; moved on to something worth their time &amp;#38; attention. This, of course, didn't sit too well with the techs, who apparently felt law enforcement had abandoned them to a fat cross dresser with a bomb disguised as a computer, but they eventually decided the item was harmless. Then they asked if I was really a cross-dresser, to which my husband, who hadn't been with me at first but had been close enough to view all this, said, "No. She's my wife, she's all woman, &amp;#38; she's been the vice president of the base's computer club, which she helped found, for 3 years. You English really need to get with the times. Women's Liberation has been on the map since the mid-1960s at least." The general laughter caused a red face, but he let me pass.<br /><br />There actually was a reason why the Bobbies hadn't bugged me. It was because, when someone I didn't know from a hole in the ground dumped his luggage by ours when I was alone, I called them right away. I couldn't leave mine alone without being suspect myself, &amp;#38; the presumptuous dingbat who dumped ignored my demands that he pick up his luggage per the law. The Bobbies treated the dumped luggage as a bomb &amp;#38; thanked me for attempting to stop the man &amp;#38; promptly notifying them. The idiot wasn't too smart. He was Irish, &amp;#38; at a time when there'd just been another IRA bombing (&amp;#38; 2 days after we left, there was another in the Tubes), he came back, telling them to "let up" &amp;#38;, after calling them "Ba****ds" (among other things), he called me a "B---c," threatened me with bodily harm, &amp;#38; demanded to know what right I had to call the cops. He then told them that both I &amp;#38; they needed to get a sense of humor. He was arrested on suspicion of terrorism. So, the Bobbies liked me. <br /><br />As for me, my motive was simple: I called them because I wanted to go home, not spend time in a UK jail for allowing someone I didn't know to drop off their luggage with me, esp. with an announcement running every 10 minutes telling you not to do that. As for the luggage X-Ray area, I was easy to remember. They certainly couldn't mistake me for anyone else, as I love bright colors, &amp;#38; it's hard to miss a fat lady in loud colors, esp. if she's standing in a forest of luggage &amp;#38; carrying a computer! So, they "abandoned" the baggage inspection techs to the fate of having a fat lady carry a computer through their machines.<br /><br />I thought the incident was funny, but believe me, I never let on until we were back in the US, &amp;#38; far away from airports! NO ONE has a sense of humor, not since airline hijackings started in the 1960s, but with the IRA doing its best to blow stuff up all over England back then (&amp;#38; likely now), they were already plenty paranoid. In fact, no one could greet my husband by his first name in or near an airport. His name is Jack (for those of you who don't get it, think a minute: "HI, Jack!" doesn't sound any better in an airport than tweeting that you're going to blow it to kingdom come or being Irish &amp;#38; dropping off your luggage by some unsuspecting passenger, against the rules, ignoring pleas to return, then doing a series of name calling &amp;#38; threats just after a bomb attack by the IRA).</comment>
		<comment id="10" responses="6">I enjoy British humour as much as the next bloke, but I really fail to find the joke in his tweek. And I do know that in THIS country, I'd dare not ever make such a joke, even if it was much more obvious.</comment>
		<comment id="11" responses="0">I like how the issue it being skipped to yell at other posters that live 5000 miles away through a computer lmao...<br /><br />The issue is something was possibly threatening(bad joke indeed) and terroristic threats are punishable, that simple</comment>
		<comment id="12" responses="0">well there's your problem... "Robin Hood airport is closed. You've got a week and a bit to get your sh*t together, otherwise I'm blowing the airport sky high!!"... is only 129 characters... he had 140 and for got to add the smiley faces on the end.
<br />
<br />Was he serious? realistically no, but the statement as written lacks anything related to humo(u)r, jest, sarcasm etc, and to be perfectly honest, if you haven't figured out in the last 9 years or so that people (mainly officials) are less likely to laugh of perceived threats at infrastructure you probably shouldn't be posting stupid comments like that on the internet.</comment>
		<comment id="13" responses="2">Chamber's never said it was a joke, he said, he made that statement 'due to anger and frustration'.
<br />
<br />That the airport has been closed for some time.
<br />The only person who tried the "IT was only a joke" defense was his laywers, and we all know how well that worked.
<br />
<br />The only other positive comment for this person was the arresting police man who stated that "he was only posting a comment to a small number of close friends'.
<br />
<br />Expect that 'small number' was I believe 600 people, and on a publicly available forum
<br />
<br />The UK has a very long history of terrorism, and making a statement like this IS an act of instilling terror.
<br />
<br />You dont get to make that determination, its the people who that threat is directed at that can (and only can) determine if they perceive that information as something that instill's terror. or fear.
<br />
<br />From Guy Falks to the IRA the UK has been the focus of terror attacks since before the US even existed !
<br />
<br />And if someone makes a statement that he "will blow something up", that is a threat, its not a joke...
<br />
<br />When I was very young, in the early 1960's my mother received a phone call, it was a bomb threat.. Probably just some kids playing a practicle joke.. but it scared me, and it REALLY scared my mother.
<br />
<br />That is an act of terror. it causes fear.. and the only person who can make that determination is the ones who are the focus of that threat.. <br />
<br />Ofcourse if you are no where near that airport, or not flying to that airport, you can say "its a joke", because if its NOT, its not going to directly hurt you.. you are quite happy to take on that risk that it is real, because after all if it is a real threat, its not going to kill me !!!... <br />
<br />But if you work at the airport, and you have to decide if it is real or not, the price you pay to find out that it was not a joke could be the loss of your life.. <br />
<br />He should of spent time in prison, even just 3 or 6 months. Apart from being a moron, he's instilled terror in at least some people.
<br />
<br />Oh yes, and terrorists, and bombers OFTEN inform the police before the attack, especially in the UK, where they even have special phone numbers for the IRA and such to contact police and warn of bombs.. !!</comment>
	</comments>
	</post>
	<post id="http://news.cnet.com/8301-30684_3-20022729-265.html?part=rss&amp;amp;subj=news&amp;amp;tag=2547-1_3-0-20">
	<title>Google senior execs getting 30 percent raises</title>
	<body>
Google gave all of its employees raises earlier this week, but it saved the best raises for its senior management team.





 Four of Google's seven named executive officers--Patrick Pichette, Nikesh Arora, Alan Eustace, and Jonathan Rosenberg--are getting 30 percent raises for 2011, bringing each of their base salaries to $650,000 from $500,000, Google announced in a filing with the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission late Friday. Earlier in the week, Google gave everybody else a 10 percent raise, along with a $1,000 bonus, as it tries to hang on to employees amid a talent war in Silicon Valley. Those executives are also getting hefty restricted-stock awards, with Pichette and Arora receiving $20 million, Eustace getting $10 million, and Rosenberg getting $5 million in grants and options. The numbers are interesting, considering that TechCrunch reported this week that a single Google "staff engineer" was given a restricted-stock award of $3.5 million as an incentive to remain with the search company and pass up an offer from Facebook. The Google ruling triumvirate--CEO Eric Schmidt, and co-founders Sergey Brin and Larry Page--will continue to accept a salary of $1 and did not take any additional stock rewards. Not that they really need it: together, the three control more than half of Google's outstanding stock, with Brin and Page supplementing their incomes this year by selling off shares in a diversification strategy.
</body>
	<comments>
		<comment id="0" responses="0">I knew I should have stuck with computers back in college...but noooo, I had to drink all that beer.</comment>
		<comment id="1" responses="1">Why is this news? "Company tries to retain employees."
<br />
<br />Who cares?</comment>
		<comment id="2" responses="5">Once again the workers to do the work and the executives take the biggest prize.</comment>
		<comment id="3" responses="2">Another example of corporate greed.</comment>
		<comment id="4" responses="2">Why do you need all of that money?</comment>
		<comment id="5" responses="0">Man, if I ever needed confirmation that my idea to offer up "startup worthy" developers from Latam had legs, this was it. http://ow.ly/399qw</comment>
		<comment id="6" responses="2">In the United States the top 5% control 95% of the entire nations wealth..... enough said.</comment>
		<comment id="7" responses="0">And they fired the employee who leaked the memo that revealed workers were only getting a 10% raise. Just another cash cow company, one whose primary business is profiting from knowing your every preference.</comment>
		<comment id="8" responses="0">I just don't think these sort of salary increases are appropriate in such an unstable economic time. People are being laid off all over the place, prices seem to be going up and up, even for basic food items,. and the salaries for the workers (slaves) are barely enough to manage day-to-day living. Execs awarding themselves huge bonuses seems dishonest. When times are good and everyone benefits, sure, no problem (though the amounts here are still insane). When times are tough, execs need to lead the way and batten down the hatches too.</comment>
	</comments>
	</post>
	<post id="http://news.cnet.com/8301-11128_3-20022717-54.html?part=rss&amp;amp;subj=news&amp;amp;tag=2547-1_3-0-20">
	<title>Obama climate rules face fight in Congress</title>
	<comments>
		<comment id="0" responses="4">This is good news indeed. The EPA must be stopped.</comment>
		<comment id="1" responses="2">Thank God!!! I hope they get rid of the EPA!!! Just another reason why U.S. manufactoring jobs are going to other countries. Climate change is a hoax!!!</comment>
		<comment id="2" responses="1">SO now we are treated to liberal Reuters news feeds here on CNET? Ok, we get the idea. CNET is a touchy-feely lefty organization.</comment>
		<comment id="3" responses="5">Obama needs to recognize the folly of his excuse-for-an-energy-policy, and bring back American Greatness in the Technology that they invented - namely Nuclear Energy. But Autoworkers back to work building factory produced Small Modular Reactors. If done in the same manner that Autoworkers produced Sherman Tanks in 2nd World War - within 15 yrs the USA could be 100% Green Electricity - within 30 yrs 100% Carbon Free. <br />
<br />50,000 complex 30 ton Sherman Tanks were produced during WWII - equivalent to 30,000 50 ton 25 MWe, 70 MWth Nuclear Reactors. 30,000 X 25MWe = 750 GWe, 2.1 TWth vs USA total Electricity Production of 420 GWe and total Energy Consumption of 3.3 TWth. And the whole enterprise would be paid for by eliminating Job Killing, Terrorist Funding, Iran Weapons Funding, Smoke Belching, Cancer Causing, War-provoking Oil Imports. It's a No-Brainer. Except Obama, like Bush, is subservient to the interests of Big Oil, and only puts on a show to pretend he is doing something about Oil Imports, Global Warming and Peak Oil Catastrophe.</comment>
		<comment id="4" responses="2">I'm really happy that the Republicans are gonna fight this.
<br />I dont want to live in a Beautiful, chemical free, pristine air, water, and land
<br />devoid of chemical hazards of any type.
<br />AND----- BE-------- OUT------- OF---------- WORK.</comment>
		<comment id="5" responses="1">This is awesome news. Obama has already done enough to kill jobs and ruin the economy.</comment>
		<comment id="6" responses="1">Common sense, CO2 is not a pollutant as described by the federal register. However, mercury, smog, acid rain, etc current control and monitoring requirements are necessary. You do not throw the baby out with the bath water and real pollution issues should not be lumped in with politically driven policy.<br /><br />There are other chemicals more prone to trap in heat other than CO2. Methane is 21 times more potent and CFC are thousands of times more potent that CO2. The current EPA regulation is flawed. I like many professionals in the energy sector dislike the rule, not because it is another regulation, but because it is bad regulation that seems to only be a revenue generating animal. CO2 is not a criteria pollutant, it is not a HAP or considered to be a toxic substance. Removal of CO2 from the regulation would be the first step in correcting the mistakes from both the EPA and courts. <br /><br />Common sense, American are hoping that congress will do what's best for the country and not the party.</comment>
		<comment id="7" responses="0">This crap is all political posturing. <br />Democrats have no problem sending jobs to the third world in order to appear like they're helping the environment. Republicans have no problem sending jobs to the third world if it helps corporate bottom lines. Democrats and Republicans and Libertarians, and Socialist Workers, and Whigs, and Luddites, etc. have no problem buying cheaper goods made in polluted, unregulated countries because...they are cheaper.</comment>
	</comments>
	</post>
	<post id="http://news.cnet.com/8301-17852_3-20022698-71.html?part=rss&amp;amp;subj=news&amp;amp;tag=2547-1_3-0-20">
	<title>Microsoft mocks Apple in new 'PC and Mac' ad</title>
	<body>
So you remember how Apple used to laugh at Microsoft for years and years?
You know, there was that portly chap in the glasses who couldn't quite get anything right and secretly marveled at Apple's ability to both be very clever and, well, attract a very high class of sleeping partner?
Well, Microsoft has decided to try its hand at handing it to Apple.
For look what has appeared on the Windows YouTube site. Yes, it's a
Windows 7 "I'm a PC" ad. (Oh, you might call it a video. But to me, everything is an ad, regardless of where it happens to appear.)
Here we have
Mac and PC flying on a rocket-plane made out of Andy Warhol's castoff props. Scarcely has the rocket-plane reached its cruising altitude before the Windows 7 PC shows off its buff new exterior. And, indeed, interior.
For it has something that Mac does not. No, not the adulation of Megan Fox, but the next best thing. Yes, built-in Blu-Ray.

Perhaps you are as completely mesmerized by this information as is the rather worn-out Mac in this ad. 
Perhaps the presence of built-in Blu-Ray will tip the balance for you, so that your enjoyment of "Avatar" will feel four-dimensional the next time you go on a rocket-plane to visit your relatives. 
For myself, I am reminded of reality shows. They are always better when there is a certain amount of conflict. One loud woman decides to tug at another loud woman's hair extensions on "The Bachelor." One large man steals another large man's pea puree on "Top Chef." 
These are the things that keep us excited, begging for more.
So it is quite delightful that Microsoft's former chubby, downtrodden self is standing up to the handsome, eligible Mac that began to show a little smugness beneath its dazzling beauty. (Oh, even George Clooney succumbs just once in awhile.) 
Welcome, then, to the "I'm a PC and you're an Annoyingly Popular Former High School Quarterback and Rhodes Scholar with Bulges in All the Right Places and a House on Lake Como" campaign.
May the fight be unfair, amusing, and draw just a little blood.
</body>
	<comments>
		<comment id="0" responses="10">I'm sorry but that ad is pretty lame.</comment>
		<comment id="1" responses="6">And the flame war shall begin.<br /><br /><br />Get your fire suits people.</comment>
		<comment id="2" responses="3">Nice one!</comment>
		<comment id="3" responses="1">arhh CNET, how you miss your Golden years (like 2 years ago) when stupid people (&amp;lt;-) argued over and over Mac vs. PC. Some have over 100 comments ... then the author gets a cookie = )<br /><br />unfortunately, nobody seems to care much about Mac vs. PC now. its all about Smart phones and Tablets now. @ least I'm bored of it.</comment>
		<comment id="4" responses="2">I'm a PC, and I also thought it was lame.</comment>
		<comment id="5" responses="5">I'm a PC and I approve of that :)</comment>
		<comment id="6" responses="10">Why does a Mac need a Blu Ray player when you can download movies in HD from iTunes?</comment>
		<comment id="7" responses="0">lol, that was better than the pc vs mac ads, Apple came out with !</comment>
		<comment id="8" responses="1">Almost fell asleep during that ad, it was really slow. I guess it's cool that Microsoft is starting the ad battles back up again? I'll I know is if it's not about smart phones or tablets or something like that, then only the die hard Mac vs pc people are gonna care. For me I've seen enough, moving on.</comment>
		<comment id="9" responses="8">Mac vs. PC is thankfully not as nerd-rage inducing as it used to be. That said, the ad is silly, but so were the mac ads, and I do indeed count lack of blu-ray (as well as lack of customization in general) as a deterrent for me ever getting a mac.</comment>
		<comment id="10" responses="5">Yeah, um, nothing like watching 1080p goodness via a BluRay disc on a machine with a screen that isn't 1920x1080 thus supporting BluRay native resolutions, that will spin the entire length of the flight and kill the laptop battery before the movie is finished. When the movie could be dl'd/rented/ripped, imported to a laptop (mac or pc) and played back via iTunes/VLC/Media Player, etc. But yeah, we should carry around laptops to play movies on discs. OK. Yeah, you win.</comment>
		<comment id="11" responses="0">Is this an ad for Windows 7.... Blu-Ray.... Or Avatar? Seems to hit a lot of spots there.
<br />
<br />That said, I always love stop-motion animation and the scene of notebooks riding paper airplanes down the cliff face brought a smile to my face. <br />
<br />It's a well done little video.</comment>
		<comment id="12" responses="6">Blu-Ray? Who uses that old, obsolete format? Modern data storage is solid-state, not rotary.</comment>
		<comment id="13" responses="0">I thought it was actually pretty funny...</comment>
		<comment id="14" responses="4">Not a Mac fan but anyone who thought that was funny compared to the PC vs Mac ads probably works for Microsoft's advertising division.</comment>
		<comment id="15" responses="4">I liked the look, but the writing was weak. And how many PCs come with a Blu-Ray player standard? What does a hardware upgrade have to do with Windows 7? <br /><br />Sony blew it with the Blu-Ray format when they decided to stay greedy on the pricing for hardware and software. <br /><br />Windows 7 is what Vista should have been, so I have a problem understanding why I'm expected to spend another $150 to "upgrade" to 7 to get rid of the crappy Vista that I got forced into buying with two of my PCs. <br /><br />If Apples weren't so artificially overpriced, I think they'd crush Microsoft outright.</comment>
		<comment id="16" responses="2">Um, so Microsoft hasn't noticed that Blu-Ray isn't exactly blowing up the "competition"?</comment>
		<comment id="17" responses="6">They forgot the part where the PC's battery dies after 2 hours. Oh, and as the closing credits said, Avatar is available on Blue-ray and DVD. So the Mac user can watch it on DVD.</comment>
		<comment id="18" responses="10">Funny thing is, I haven't used the drive on my iMac in 3 years and my dvd player collects dust and I won't spend any money on a BluRay player. My reason, all my content is stored on a hard drive, I almost have my entire DVD collection in HD that is streamed to my AppleTV. No need to buy discs, no need for a disc player.
<br />
<br />So MS is making fun of the Mac not having a drive that hardly anyone uses anymore, MS is lame.... Again..... and late to the game....again. Digital content with eventually take out DVD's as it did with CD's. MS and others are just lagging behind.... again.</comment>
		<comment id="19" responses="1">Really?<br /><br />Battery??? How long can the last?<br /><br />in addition to that I am not sure who carries movies any more, everything is digital.<br /><br />I was really looking forward for this commercial, but honestly.... total let down MS...</comment>
		<comment id="20" responses="1">Why do I need Blu-Ray when I can pull off the hard drive and save battery life? That makes no sense? Doesn't matter what format you are running, unless there is a reason that Microsoft 7 can't playback high-def stored to drive. Is there?</comment>
		<comment id="21" responses="2">Discs? LOL, they're SO YESTERDAY.<br /><br />I download/stream all my media.<br />Media is/will be in the Cloud.</comment>
		<comment id="22" responses="1">Hmmm. . .so if I'm picking between the X360 and PS3, should I pick the PS3 because it supports Blu-ray?</comment>
		<comment id="23" responses="1">T-mobile also released an ad like this vs iphone <br />they promote a phone that is capable of video calls over 4g network <br />then the famous ad comes. " i am a t-mobile" capable of using video calls over 4g <br />and then the Iphone comes and says i can also do facetime "over wifi like at an airport " <br /><br />hilarious.</comment>
		<comment id="24" responses="4">That was one terrible commercial. I'm not a Mac fanboy, and I do know Mac lags behind when it comes to the cutting-edge stuff like blu-ray and GPU power, but that was just plain awful. I really hope it was a fan-made ad or something, 'cause there is no way that's going to catch people's attention on TV. It took, what, an entire minute to advertise a single positive aspect of a product? Microsoft needs to pay their employees better, or beat them more.</comment>
		<comment id="25" responses="3">While I was supposed to think that Justin Long was hip and run out an buy a Mac, I had just the opposite impression. In the ads, he reminded me of a cross between a beach bum and bistro waiter still living at home.</comment>
		<comment id="26" responses="0">I kind of like the idea that a mac would use a pc to watch movies.</comment>
		<comment id="27" responses="4">Nice ad. I would like to bring my blu-ray titles with me on a trip (sorry overly compressed "HD" video doesn't count) which look nice both on my 42" 1080p tv and on my PC. It's not that Macs don't come with Blu-Ray player, but the entire OS doesn't even support them, which means you can't even buy a third-party blu-ray player and plug it in. Yes, you can take a blu-ray, and rip it, but I don't want to do that, I want to put in a disc and hit play.<br /><br />All because Steve Jobs wants people to buy stuff from his iTunes store instead of blu ray discs.<br /><br />I actually like Apple products. I have an iPod touch and a Mac Mini which I like. But I won't buy a MacBook Air to replace my portable PC until blu-ray is supported, and if it takes too long I'll just buy another PC.<br /><br />This is coming from someone who absolutely hates windows as an OS. I mostly use Solaris for real work.<br /><br />It's not just that Blu-ray is better or worse than downloads or DVD or whatever. It's that it's easy for Apple, one of the most profitable tech companies in the world and now the largest tech company on the stock market, to support this, but they refuse because they want to force the customer to do something else.</comment>
		<comment id="28" responses="2">Really blueray? They still make that? Why not just go with SSD and a digital copy of a movie so that you can watch 2 or 3 on the same battery charge.</comment>
		<comment id="29" responses="0">Good Grief, Microsoft is totally clueless! Watching movies on a laptop is like swimming laps in your hot tub. Sure you can do it, but why? Movies like Avatar were never designed for small screens and stereo sound. The home theater is the best place to watch a modern action/thriller/scifi spectacular Blue Ray disk.<br /><br />What should really scare Microsoft is that Apple is gearing up to remove the optical drives from it's laptop computers altogether. Using the space for more useful purposes - bigger battery, better cooling, more secondary storage. All the while delivering a thinner and lighter mobile computing experience.<br /><br />Microsoft is just pathetic has-been comparing itself to Apple - the new leader of the technology industry.</comment>
		<comment id="30" responses="0">"No macs were used in the making of this film"<br /><br />because we all know that practically all other videos are? What point is microsoft trying to prove here?</comment>
		<comment id="31" responses="0">I think MSFT is getting a bad deal with these Ads... they need to hire a new Ad agency. The message is basically, "We have Blue-Ray as an option... Apple doesn't" This cartoon ad just distracts from the message. In any case, sure... Mac users wouldn't mind Blue-ray as a feature... at the same time - some consider not having to carry a bunch of BR-discs around is a feature too.</comment>
		<comment id="32" responses="0">i watched the ad again... MSFT should sue whoever came up with this ad...</comment>
		<comment id="33" responses="0">The T-Mobile ad lies. T-Mobile doesn't really have 4G yet, but they go around saying it anyways. Besides, at&amp;#38;t is an awesome network, I have it and have never had the slightest problem.</comment>
		<comment id="34" responses="0">So... MS's argument is that they have built-in Blu-Ray players and Macs don't ? Sorry but that's pretty lame... I'm really not an Apple fanboy (heck I can't stand Mac OS X), but at least their Mac vs. PC commercials were witty and made valid (though nothing groundbreaking) points.</comment>
		<comment id="35" responses="2">Why would anyone want to use a blu-ray disc? It kills batteries. Just use the SD card slot, stream it or put it on the hard drive via a torrent. Surely people aren't using blu-ray in this day and age. This article is way out of touch with reality.</comment>
		<comment id="36" responses="4">Mac is designed for people with slow brain function and high fashion concern.</comment>
		<comment id="37" responses="0">Blu-Ray was designed for home theater with a large screen and 5.1 or better surround, not laptops with small screens and two tinny speakers. This is a non-issue. Also, some people like Mac, some like PC. No one is going to 'convert' because of some blogging here. PC and Mac fans, get over yourselves.</comment>
		<comment id="38" responses="0">I'm curious, so it's about laptops only?<br /><br />Okay, just wondering, but I can purchase a LaCie Blu-Ray writer for my Macs (all 35 used for programming, rendering, video, sound, etc.) or just burn an ISO and go through the very-easy networking of Snow Leopard/Leopard and burn it via Toast 10. So, by buying this extra, like I need it, my Mac now has Blu-Ray. Voila!<br /><br />However, these days, when I test a video for a client, or audio, we just use a Xbox 360's standards, and it's USB ports, and see how the videos will look. With an HDMI cable, we're able to use the Xbox 360 to go up to 1080p, and see what compression ratios are needed.<br /><br />Also, Blu-Ray is compression. Most movies are scanned at 8,192 ppi resolution. Blu-Ray wastes 50 GB, or even 25 GB, on reducing the video to an average ppi of around 1,000 or so. Then the bitrate...it's a laugh, decompressed at around 2.5 mbps to 4 mbps, rarely going higher. Same bitrate H.264 decomps at for iTunes HD content.<br /><br />If would help if people would know better by knowledge, but knowledge they lack.<br /><br />For instance, talk about the so-called "average" CNET user? Or how about Joe Sixpack?<br /><br />Joe Sixpack can't tell stereo from mono, phonograph to CD, AM to FM, SD to HD, Beta to VHS, Mac to Windows.<br /><br />(This comes from working at a videogame store for many years and being surprised how many times people asked for GoldenEye on a PlayStation, or Gran Turismo on Windows, or thinking "HD" means, simply, a 16:9 TV.)<br /><br />So, who are you talking about?</comment>
		<comment id="39" responses="10">I love the mac ad where they show the new macbook and talk about all they've learned and they show the side of the laptop with it's single usb port and an audio jack. It's as lame as them talking about watching internet TV on the mac like it's something new. <br />Only the iDorks get it.</comment>
		<comment id="40" responses="2">Really, all this ad needs is Steve Ballmer shouting at the camera and throwing chairs.</comment>
		<comment id="41" responses="0">I'm a human being and I could care less. ;-)</comment>
		<comment id="42" responses="0">I find it ironic that MS is touting Blu-ray while the XBOX 360 is still using DVDs.</comment>
		<comment id="43" responses="0">I feel like such a fool. This whole time I've been watching movies from my HD when I could have been carrying a big spindle of plastic discs around with me and enjoying all the benefits of DTS HD Master Audio through my tiny little earphones.</comment>
		<comment id="44" responses="0">I'm a PC but I would like a Mac........By the way, I have 2 desktop PC's and 2 laptops and NONE of them have BluRay. Just an added expense I don't need.</comment>
		<comment id="45" responses="0">This ad is lame.</comment>
		<comment id="46" responses="0">Lame Ad -- Lame Blu-Ray format.</comment>
		<comment id="47" responses="0">Wow this is a crappy stab at apple and what makes it worse is Microsoft probably payed a lot for the ad.Ok Microsoft time to grow some balls and trash apple. I bet if people knew apples drawbacks they would think twice before buying a mac.</comment>
		<comment id="48" responses="10">I can't believe the amount of corporate sponsored comments on this story. It's really sickening. Apple is trying really, really, hard to push the whole "Blu-ray is dead" theme, just like they tried the whole "Flash is dead" theme. This is the reality of 21st century astroturf marketing. It's just sickening that some people don't realize that what looks like real people is really Apple-sponsored PR (to be fair, MS does it too...). <br /><br />Blu-ray is not "dead", and won't be until something superior comes along. Think about it: High-quality 1080P video with 24bit surround audio (255 times the resolution), with lots of room for all kinds of extras on the disc - heck, my Bruce Lee "Enter the Dragon" Blu-ray has more hours of extras and rare footage than the actual movie - in a format that will outlive a HD crash.<br /><br />VS.<br /><br />Video that is highly compressed to be feasible to download, and audio that is only 16 bit, in a format that is DRM laden and won't play on your other devices, thus locking you into one particular company's whims. Anyone that can say this is a "superior format" is braindead. More convenient perhaps, but really it's like saying the MP3 sounds better than the CD.</comment>
		<comment id="49" responses="0">The winner is Sony.<br />Blue Ray is their baby and they must be getting paid by Microsoft for every Windows 7 license sold.<br />Pity Xbox doesn't support it.</comment>
		<comment id="50" responses="0">When you young hipsters have a job that pays you enough money to be able to watch movies on a screen larger than 42 inches you will finally understand why Blu-Ray is going to be with us for a long time.
<br />Just because you are willing to consume low quality audio and video does not mean that the rest of the world is willing to sacrifice quality on the altar of Steve Job's ego.</comment>
		<comment id="51" responses="0">Yipeee!! Microsoft finally touched 2006!!</comment>
		<comment id="52" responses="0">Sony is the graveyard of media formats. They just turned out the lights on cassette tapes, their longest running best success. They don't get the internet and they make devices that have feature bloat, promising function but serving dysfunction. Six years ago, I bought a bunch of Sony Laptops that would not make a movie worth a darn compared to my G4 iBook with iMovie, even using a Sony Digicam, and crashed constantly, finally all dying at the 3 year point -this death at end of warranty occurred in all three which makes me go hmmmmm. I've gone back to Apple and haven't looked back since.</comment>
		<comment id="53" responses="5">Os11 &amp;#38; yelond; <br />Apple shoul remove Ethernet port and use all wirelessly. Right! Do a back up of 1T of data over the wireless and let us know what happen next. Anyway, no matter what, wired is more secured than wireless.</comment>
		<comment id="54" responses="0">The ad reminds me of those old Flash Gordon movies from the 30s lol. As for the whole Blu-Ray controversy, I watch HD movies on my 46" LCD TV, not my 13" MacBook Pro, thank you vey much. I don't think I would notice the difference between a std-def movie and an HD movie on this small screen anyway. It is the ultimate non-issue.</comment>
		<comment id="55" responses="0">apple agrees with blu ray tech. apple was on the board of directors for BR disk association. I am unsure if apple is still on the board. apple wanted sony blu ray players put into their mac pros. The kicker is that apple wanted burners. this was a no no and sony offered blu ray with hd dvdr instead. Steve Jobs decided that if apple could not have BD R devices then apple would not implement it at all. Hence, no blu ray. Sony didn't care. ha<br /><br />blu ray has sold faster than dvd when it first hit. one disk can currently hold 1 tb of information. it's too bad steve decided to be a stubborn kid. maybe that is why the ad is made out of crafts. he's hoping blu ray keeps it's quality requirements up but microsoft has me questioning. that is a lot of storage for a such a simple thing. physical btw. in case your head is in the cloud. opposite downloadable content aka apple route of business. avatar. people went to the theater?? during such an innovative time? hmm..consumers truly dictate their market afterall. ;)<br /><br />oh and java isn't exactly needed anymore everyone<br />because blu ray players use it. suprise</comment>
		<comment id="56" responses="0">Blu-Ray support is now a selling point for Windows 7? Meh. The ad money would have been better spent pointing out Windows 7 is not a Vista redo - if you could do it with a straight face.</comment>
		<comment id="57" responses="1">Maybe this would be more of a real point if you could install Windows 7 on a PC with a Blu-Ray drive and play a Blu-Ray movie.<br /><br />You can't.<br /><br />You have to install 3rd party software. The software that I've seen leaves allot to be desired.<br />Yes there are licenses reasons for this, but if Microsoft taunts this as a reason to buy a Windows 7 PC than a Windows 7 PC should be able to do it, out of the box.<br /><br />Optical drives are being phased out anyways, so who cares. Just one more example of how they just don't get it.</comment>
		<comment id="58" responses="3">Apple has had 25 years to beat Windows and Worldwide Windows still runs 95% of computers.<br />Apple FAIL. And to rub salt in the wound we get this...<br />Android Phones Sweep Consumer Report Ratings, Beat Down the iPhone<br />Consumer Reports says the best phones on the market are those that use Android.<br />By Preston Gralla, Computerworld Nov 12, 2010 1:55 pm</comment>
		<comment id="59" responses="0">Hope it comes with a monitor that supports Blue Ray. Cause a player doesn't mean anything if the monitor is crap.</comment>
		<comment id="60" responses="1">Couple of things. First, a Mac is a PC. Just like Linux can be a PC, your cell phone can even be a PC. This is Windows v. MacOS.<br /><br />2nd, Blu-ray isn't truly built into Windows 7. You still have to install codecs/software to view Blu-ray which are not native to the OS.</comment>
		<comment id="61" responses="0">Unfortunately this is another prime example of Microsoft showing it's a dinosaur. I am a huge advocate of Sony and BluRay in fact I rooted for Sony to win this battle which Microsoft was completely against. Microsoft was the competitor and supported HD-DVD and that is now dead. If you look at the trends, Apple TV, NetFlix Downloads, Hulu and tablet PCs that don't have drives it all really makes sense as to the future. Platters such as DVD's and Blu-Ray are so yesterday. With my iPod I have thousands of songs all in a 3x5 inch form factor. Not shelves upon shelves of platter discs. All of my media including videos are all accessible with a single click of a button, not shuffling around shelves of BluRay discs. No more scratching cracking or losing discs. Those days are gone. Apple was the first to get rid of the floppy and I thank them for this. People freaked out about that. 5 years from now we are all going to look back and say, how silly was it that we used platters to store media when we could store everything on single iPod, iPad or on Apple TV. All instantly accessible in HD. Now it's 720P HD and not 1080P but really I can't tell the difference, I'm sorry. But one thing I do know for sure is that 1080 will eventually make its way to down-loadable content and that will seal the coffin of BluRay. In short this commercial demonstrates to me once more just how out of tune Microsoft is to the future. Sorry Sony I really like you guys but the end is near for BluRay as well. I've owned a PS3 since it's release and only purchased one BluRay, the rest of my movies were purchased as down-loadable so I could have instant access at any time.<br /><br />If Apple were smart they'd make a sequel to this video where the Apple Laptop opens iTunes and starts playing an infinite amount of music, movies, Podcasts and so on without ever needing to change platters. Platters are about annoying as batteries, nobody wants to keep replacing them. Apple is right on this one not to let us keep doing this to ourselves.</comment>
		<comment id="62" responses="2">Does anyone even realize a mac is a pc with a different operating system? My computer that i custom built that runs windows will blow any mac that exists into the water, but that doesn't mean windows is better than a mac! Everytime I hear someone say a mac is better than a pc I want to smack them because a mac is a pc!!!!!!!!!!!! PC = PERSONAL COMPUTER FOR ALL YOU PEOPLE THAT DO NOT KNOW!!!</comment>
		<comment id="63" responses="10">Funny, isn't it, that nearly every home entertainment hardware manufacturer is integrating Blu-Ray into their product lines, but because Mac's don't have a BD drive, all the mac Fanboys call it a dead and technically retarded concept. Typical.</comment>
		<comment id="64" responses="3">Not really, Macs have much better hardware and software so they operate far smoother than a PC (running Windows or Linux, etc). Apple invented the PC industry so they know what they are doing, everyone else just tries to copy them. Sure, a Windows PC is about 60% of a Mac, but unless you have the real thing, you'll never know how good personal computing can be. PC's are good for kids still running games, and blue collar workers in factories, but that's about it.</comment>
		<comment id="65" responses="0">am I the only one here who's still using the .torrent format for my movies?</comment>
		<comment id="66" responses="2">This is such a lame ad.<br /><br />For a start, the dominant brand should never recognise the challenger, it just stinks of desperation.<br /><br />Secondly, who really carries around DVDs or BluRay? I know when I travel, if it isn't on the hard risk, it doesn't go. Key is to travel lite. <br /><br />Third, battery life. BluRay takes way more processing than DVD so if many laptops would struggle to make it through a full feature on DVD, you can imagine the struggle to finish a BluRay film.<br /><br />And lets be honest, given the size and resolution of laptop screens, the benefit of Blu Ray is negated. <br /><br />PC or Mac, Blu Ray is not a feature I want or need. It's like having paddles on the wheel of a Merc S Class... it's not a sport car.</comment>
		<comment id="67" responses="1">I'd have to laugh, the mac would sit there for the rest of the flight wondering what happened at the end of the movie, because the PC ran out of batteries after 1hr 30min due to playing hi-res video from a spinning disc unit... <br /><br />Windows really was only mean't for spreadsheets... and HP/Dell/Sony etc should get a new OS supplier... ;)</comment>
		<comment id="68" responses="0">I really don't understand this article or the metaphors and comparisons to reality tv. Why would I watch a show with girls pulling hair or about stealing pureed peas? What does this have to do with the advertisement?</comment>
		<comment id="69" responses="0">Turns out the Mac is a "bag of hurt".<br />My how things have changed.</comment>
	</comments>
	</post>
	<post id="http://news.cnet.com/8301-30686_3-20022685-266.html?part=rss&amp;amp;subj=news&amp;amp;tag=2547-1_3-0-20">
	<title>Ask Maggie: Am I better off with an iPhone 3GS?</title>
	<body>
Geeks will always tell you to get the latest and greatest product on the market, but sometimes choosing a previous generation product will satisfy your needs without breaking the bank.



In this week's column I answer a question from a reader who needs a new
iPhone and can't decide whether to get the older-generation iPhone 3GS or the iPhone 4. Most technophiles would scoff at such a question. Who actually buys last year's model when this year's model is available? What do you think? I outline the pros and cons below. Feel free to add to the list in the comment section.
Ask Maggie also helps another reader who is looking to boost his Sprint cell phone signal in his home. And finally, Ask Maggie tackles yet another tax question. This time, it's all about avoiding hefty sales taxes on smartphones. Ask Maggie is a weekly advice column that answers readers' wireless and broadband questions. If you've got a question, please send me an e-mail at maggie dot reardon at cbs dot com. And please put "Ask Maggie" in the subject header.
iPhone 3GS or iPhone 4?
Dear Maggie,
I have the original iPhone. My contract is up and I'm ready for a new phone. My current iPhone only rings when it's plugged in and charging. Anyway, I've heard that the iPhone 4 has had a lot of problems. I haven't heard of many problems with the iPhone 3GS. And I was wondering if you think it's better to get the 3GS instead of the iPhone 4?
Thanks,
Brian 
Dear Brian,
This is a great question. Initially, my gut reaction to your question was to tell you to get the iPhone 4. It's the latest and greatest in technology that Apple has to offer, so why would you get the previous generation, which doesn't have all the bells and whistles? But that might just be my inner geek talking.
There is actually nothing wrong with the iPhone 3GS. In fact, the iPhone 3GS and the iPhone 4 use the same AT&amp;T 3G wireless network. While some people believe the iPhone 4 uses a faster 4G wireless network, the reality is that AT&amp;T does not have a 4G wireless network yet. And when it does, the iPhone 4 will not be able to take advantage of it. Since you have been using the original iPhone for the past couple of years, which uses AT&amp;T's slower 2.5G network, either device is going to feel like a big leap in performance for you.
In an effort to help you make your decision, I'm going to lay out the pros and cons of each device for you:
iPhone 4
Pros: The iPhone 4 comes with a slew of new hardware features that are not offered on previous generations of the iPhone. The most important update is the camera. The iPhone 4 not only has the traditional camera on the back, but it also has a front-facing camera that when used with the Face Time app allows users to video chat while in a Wi-Fi hot spot. The front-facing camera is also great for taking pictures or video of yourself. 
The updated camera has a resolution of 5 megapixels and shoots video in high-definition. And for the first time, Apple has added a flash to the camera so that you can take pictures in low light. And it has a 5x zoom that allows you to get closer to your subject when you are far away.
The other major improvement on the iPhone 4 is the high-quality Retina display. The display is one of the best in the industry offering some of the most crisp and brightest images.
Cons: As you alluded to in your question, the iPhone 4 has had some problems with dropped calls due to the construction of the antenna. Because the antenna is exposed and wraps around the phone if you put your hand over a spot near the bottom of the phone, the signal is often disrupted and calls can be interrupted.
Apple says that this is a common problem with many cell phones that have the antenna situated on the bottom of the phone. But Kent German, a senior Reviews editor at CNET, who has tested the iPhone among hundreds of other devices, said he believes the iPhone 4 antenna issues are different.
"None of the older iPhones suffered from the same antenna problems in our testing," he said. "I think those were unique to the iPhone 4."
Of course, you can use a rubber bumper on your phone, and that should alleviate the problem. But there have been other reports of minor issues with the phone including, the fact that the display screen scratches more easily. Apple stopped selling a particular sliding case because of complaints about scratched displays.
Another potential con when compared to the iPhone 3GS is that an iPhone 4 costs more. The iPhone 4 with 16GB of memory costs $199 with a two-year contract, whereas the 8GB iPhone 3GS will only set you back $99 with a two-year contract. 
iPhone 3GS
Pros: As I mentioned in the cons of the iPhone 4, the 8GB iPhone 3GS is half the price of the 16GB iPhone 4. And the 16GB iPhone 3GS is $50 less than the 16GB iPhone 4. This may not sway most people, but if you're on a tight budget, it's something to consider.
Another bit of good news is that many of the new software enhancements for the iPhone 4 came from an update to the device's iOS software. And these updates are also available for the iPhone 3GS. 
For example, multitasking was originally missing from the iPhone 3GS and other versions of the iPhone. But the iOS 4.0 released the same day the iPhone 4  went on sale offered the ability to run multiple applications at once. Another key software update in iOS 4.0 was the ability to turn the iPhone into a wireless modem. There is an additional fee associated with "tethering", but this capability had been missing from previous versions of the product. Another addition is the ability to group apps together to create home screen folders with multiple apps that helps users conserve space on the home screen display. The iPhone 3GS also offers the consolidated mailbox, so that you can merge multiple e-mail accounts. 
Cons: As mentioned before, the iPhone 3GS lacks the hardware enhancements of the iPhone 4. There is no front-facing camera, no zoom, and no flash. There is video, but it's not in high-definition. 
Another consideration is that Apple is an innovative company that is constantly moving forward technologically. It has a poor history of making sure its older products are compatible with new features it introduces in newer products. So even though many of the iOS 4.0 and subsequent updates have worked on both the iPhone 4 and iPhone 3GS, you may not be able to count on this going forward. 
"With Apple often you have to upgrade or lose out on new features," Kent German, CNET Reviews senior editor, said. "Faithful Apple fans are happy to do this, so if you get something older, the danger is that when something new comes out, you might get left behind."
 So the bottom line is that the issues you are concerned about on the iPhone can be mitigated with a rubber bumper. But if you don't care about all the fancy hardware enhancements, the iPhone 3GS would be a fine choice for you. And you wouldn't have to pay as much for it. 
And depending on how much you want to spend on a new phone, you might also want to check out refurbished iPhones from AT&amp;T. Both the iPhone 4 and iPhone 3GS are sold used on AT&amp;T's Web site for a discount. 
Boosting indoor cell coverage
Dear Maggie,
I have a BlackBerry on T-Mobile and a Droid (the original one) on Verizon. I tried the Sprint EVO 4G. I could get good coverage outdoors, but I can rarely have a full conversation inside. I live in a 1966 construction condo that is mostly earth-sheltered. Is there any technology that can boost signal strength indoors? 
 Thanks,
Nitalu
Dear Nitalu,
You are not alone in having problems getting decent cell phone reception indoors. This is a common complaint. Sprint does offer a solution. In August the company started shipping its first 3G-capable femtocells. The product called the Airave Access Point acts as a mini cell phone tower in your home. It boosts the cellular signal and uses your home broadband connection to route the voice or data session to its network.
The company has been offering a 2G version of the Airave for a couple of years. The primary difference between the two femtocells is that the earlier product only supports Sprint's 2G CDMA 1x technology, whereas the newer product supports the 3G EV-DO network.
Currently, the 3G Airave is not available for purchase. Sprint is only making the device available to people who qualify. You should check with a Sprint representative because you may actually qualify for the service. Sprint hasn't been clear about whether qualified customers will have to pay additionally for the femtocell service. Sprint told CNET in August when the product launched that they evaluate your eligibility for a free service on a case-by-case basis.
That said, Sprint is still selling its old Airave femtocells. These devices cost $99.99 retail, plus there's a $4.99 a month charge for "Enhanced Coverage." After that, you would need to activate either a $10 a month Single Line Unlimited Calling Plan or a $20 a month Multi-Line Unlimited Calling Plan for those who use family plans. 
You mentioned that you have an HTC Evo 4G phone. Currently, Sprint does not offer signal boosting for 4G. This is a particular problem for Sprint and Clearwire, the company building the 4G wireless network, because the spectrum used to build the 4G WiMax network doesn't penetrate buildings easily. But the HTC Evo 4G will fall back to 3G when 4G is not available. And if 3G isn't available it will use the 2G network. So making phone calls shouldn't be a problem, but using data might be painful unless you have Wi-Fi at home. 
Another option for improving signal strength is to get a "cell phone signal booster." There are a few companies, including Wilson Electronics, that sell devices that will boost your phone's signal strength. Wilson's latest product promises to boost the signal up to 20 times. The devices work within the 800MHz to 1900MHZ cellular spectrum bands. This covers both GSM and CDMA networks in the U.S., but it does not work with Nextel phones or GSM devices abroad. The products tend to be pricey as well. The Wilson Electronics Sleek costs $129. But unlike the Sprint 2G femtocell, it doesn't require a monthly charge.
If I were you, I'd talk to Sprint and see if you can get a 3G Airave femtocell for free. If you don't qualify, you could consider the 2G version of the product, since 2G would still allow you to make phone calls. I'd make sure to install Wi-Fi for fast data service. You could also try the Wilson Electronics Sleek, which will boost signals for people using Sprint phones as well as phones from Verizon Wireless, AT&amp;T, and T-Mobile USA.
Sales tax on a phone's list price
Hi Maggie,
My state charges sales tax for a new cell phone based upon its list price, not the subsidized purchase price when signing up for a two-year contract. 
Can I purchase a phone and a plan in another state, but have the area of primary usage based on the state in which I live? if it's possible, I'll avoid the sales tax based on the higher phone price. 
It'll be very easy to justify a weekend in Vegas with the purchase of a new phone and contract. 
Thanks,
Lester 
Dear Lester,
You are correct some states charge tax based on the unsubsidized cost of the phone. Take the iPhone as an example. Even though the advertised price of the iPhone is $199, you may actually have to pay tax on $599. In places such as California, where it has a minimum sales tax of 8.25 percent, you could pay $49.42 instead of $16.42 in sales tax. The rationale is that when you buy the iPhone for $199, you are signing a two-year service contract. As part of that sales contract you are actually paying the full price of the phone over the two year period. So the state wants its fair share of the sales tax up front.
It's a little unfair if you really think about it since the cost of the monthly service is the same regardless of whether you pay full price for the phone. Also a portion of your sales tax is not refunded if you cancel your service early. Plus, as I discussed in last week's Ask Maggie, subscribers are also charged monthly sales tax on the service.
Apple actually lists in fine print a few states that do charge tax based on the unsubsidized price. 
"In CA, MA, and RI, sales tax is collected on the unbundled price of the iPhone."
 I don't believe this list is comprehensive. I found this out myself earlier this year when I tried to replace my stolen iPhone while at a conference in Las Vegas. The saleswoman told me the phone was subject to tax on the unsubsidized price. I knew this wasn't the case in New York, where I live, so I waited and purchased my new iPhone when I got home. 
To answer your question, it is possible to travel to another state to buy a phone to get a better deal on the tax. In fact, that is why there are so many shopping malls in Northern Delaware near Maryland, Pennsylvania, and New Jersey. Delaware is one of five states that charges no sales tax. Alaska, Montana, New Hampshire, and Oregon also do not have a state sales tax.
While many people travel across state lines to shop in states with no sales tax, if you plan to use those items in a state that does have a sales tax, you are supposed to pay a "use tax" in your home state. 
As someone who grew up in Delaware, I can tell you that I've never heard of people doing this for consumer products. There's really no way for the state tax authority to know where you bought your phone. I suppose if you got audited, someone might ask where you bought your iPhone. But most people, such as myself, don't keep receipts like that. Of course, for more expensive purchases, such as
cars, which have to be registered in your home state, people still end up paying tax even if they bought the car in a tax-free state.
So my advice to you is if you live near one of the five tax-free states, buy your iPhone there and keep your existing phone number and billing address. I'm not sure the $50 or so you'd save in sales tax is really worth a special trip to Alaska or Delaware, but they are lovely places to visit. And if you are just looking for a state that charges tax on the subsidized price of the phone, do your homework before you book your ticket. 
Good luck!
</body>
	<comments>
		<comment id="0" responses="4">Actually, Maggie just a small error in the iPhone pros and cons. THe 3GS does support zoom on the camera.</comment>
		<comment id="1" responses="4">Personally I find that on occasions holding my iPhone 4 without a case increase the bars, other time it slightly decreases them. But with a case, which I bought purely because I couldn't bear to not have one, its a mental thing it just feels safer with one (but thats just because the phone is expensive). Really the anntena thing is not a problem unless you stretch your fingers to cover every line, which your not going to do.<br />Also the iPhone 4 is not curved, my old 3G (same shape/body as 3GS) is curved and it always felt like one side is bigger than the other or more curved which irritated me intensely, the iPhone 4 is simple in design which makes it great)<br />The iPhone 4 screen is the biggest reason to go for it, the resolution is amazing, I went back on my 3G to erase my content and it seemed as if the pixels were as big as buses, it actually looked ugly, also there was a noticeable green tint on my 3G.<br />Another reason to go for an iPhone 4 is that you can sell it for more money, when you want to upgrade. my 3G dropped in value about ?50 over June/July and I knew that if I didn't upgrade very soon I wouldn't be able to after the next iPhone.<br />Do not go for the 3GS, you'll regret every time you see someone with a 4.</comment>
		<comment id="2" responses="5">Well the retina display alone is worth the $50.00 difference between 16GB iPhone 4 &amp;#38; 3GS. Not to mention the 1ghz A4 processor, upgraded camera, HD video, facing camera, higher capacity battery, metal &amp;#38; glass construction. No reception issues with Otter Box case.</comment>
		<comment id="3" responses="0">Usually use taxes are only levied on those items purchased elsewhere that have to be registered and/or licensed in the state where you live, such as cars or other motor vehicles. It's about the only way any state government with its usual limited means (thank the deity of your choice for that) can track who owns what.</comment>
		<comment id="4" responses="3">I agree with Jon889.<br /><br />I'm used to the iPhone 4 (my first iPhone) and when I look at a co-worker's iPhone 3GS screen, it seems quite blurry by comparison. The Retina display for me is the single most important reason to get the iPhone 4. Unless you're blind, it's definitely worth forking out a hundred dollars. <br /><br />(think of it this way - ask yourself if in 6 months you would be willing to spend $100 to upgrade from a 3GS to a 4 - if the answer is yes or maybe, spend the $100 now 'cause you're going to be locked into a contract in 6 months!)<br /><br />As for the whole antennagate thing, well, it was blown out of proportion. I have experienced the problem first hand, then I got the bumper case and now all is good. It's such a nice phone and so expensive to replace without the contract that the question is why wouldn't one want to have at least a slim profile bumper case??<br /><br />I love my iPhone 4. :)</comment>
		<comment id="5" responses="0">Maggie, <br /><br />First and foremost, thanks for a great comparison article! A few friends of mine have asked the same question, and now I can point them to you! <br /><br />With respect to the camera on the iPhone 4, however, you said: "And it has a 5x zoom that allows you to get closer to your subject when you are far away."<br /><br />This is only a digital zoom, not an optical zoom; and there's a huge difference. To clarify: <br /><br />"... digital zoom is not really zoom, in the strictest definition of the term. What digital zoom does is enlarge a portion of the image, thus ?simulating? optical zoom. In other words, the camera crops a portion of the image and then enlarges it back to size. In so doing, you lose image quality. If you?ve been regularly using digital zoom and wondered why your pictures did not look that great, now you know." (http://www.photoxels.com/digital-photography-tutorials/optical-digital-zoom/)<br /><br />Thanks!<br />Grant Houston</comment>
		<comment id="6" responses="2">My first thought when reading the title was, "Obviously, no. You should buy an Android phone."
<br />Ahem. That aside...
<br />
<br />I've never understood femtocells. In theory, they are a great idea - mini, personal cell phone towers. Many of them offload the data to your existing Internet, effectively turning your cell phone into a VoIP phone while you're home (or visiting someone with a femtocell). It lets you connect and make calls, and it saves the phone company money because they don't need to route your call through their system - and yet, they still get your monthly check.
<br />
<br />But unfortunately, instead of handing these things out like candy and pocketing the savings, they add a monthly cost on top of that. That just doesn't make sense. I mean, I understand getting paid twice for something you don't do to begin with and all, but you can only take this so far!</comment>
		<comment id="7" responses="0">Another pro for iphone4 that was left off was its speed. It is much faster than 3GS. You'll love the difference. I would recommend iphone 4 in a heartbeat.</comment>
		<comment id="8" responses="2">"even though many of the iOS 4.0 and subsequent updates have worked on both the iPhone 4 and iPhone 3GS"<br /><br />From what I've been hearing, that's a questionable statement at best.</comment>
		<comment id="9" responses="1">If you're on a fixed budget, don't get a smart phone. 50 dollars is nothing in the grand scheme of how much you're going to pay to use the phone. If you're going to get a smart phone, spend the extra money and get the latest hardware.</comment>
		<comment id="10" responses="0">Are we still on this stupid dropped call iphone 4 antenna thing? I have had mine since its release, and have not had one dropped call. If for some reason you do have an issue, apple offers free bumpers. A friend of mine got one and it is completely clear and very thin, adding very little to the overall girth of the unit. I never got the free bumper myself.<br /><br />Unless price is an issue, always take an iphone 4 over a 3GS. End of story.</comment>
		<comment id="11" responses="0">You completely missed the key differences between the 3Gs and the 4. Yes it has a better camera, front facing camera, and a nice looking display but those are just bells and whistles. What about the behind the scene hardware improvements?<br /><br />The iPhone 4 has a faster processor then the 3Gs. Since Apple does not officially give processor specs I can't tell you for sure but many believe the iPhone 4 to have a 1 GHz processor vs 600 MHz for the 3Gs. Having a faster processor allows the apps to open and run faster. This is one of the key reasons I upgraded from a 3G to a 4. My old 3G was just WAY to slow to run the latest iOS. Apple keeps coming out with more and more software features and those updates will (like it did with the 3G) bog down a iPhone 3Gs' speed.<br /><br />The iPhone 4 has more RAM then the 3Gs. Since the latest update in the iOS allows for multitasking having more RAM will allow for more programs to be running without a performance hit. Apple has said in one of it WWDC conferences that the iPhone 4 will have 512 MB of RAM where as the iPhone 3Gs only has 256MB. This is the other key reason I upgraded from the iPhone 3G to the iPhone 4, however the 3G has even less RAM then the 3Gs (128MB vs 256MB.) Even without multitasking on my 3G I was always running out of RAM which is my guess way it was so slow, why I had so many apps crash on load, and needed to reboot the phone every so often to get it stable again.<br /><br />The iPhone 4 has a larger and longer lasting battery then the 3Gs. Even with all the extra power that the iPhone 4 has its processor uses less power. This coupled with a much larger battery size gives the iPhone 4 a longer battery life then the 3Gs. This was not an issue with my own purchase as I did not run into any battery issues with the 3G, but then again my phone was plugged in 70% of the time.</comment>
		<comment id="12" responses="0">Neither the iphone4 or 3gs has a real optical zoom. It's a digital zoom. <br /><br />I have an original 2G (8gig), a 3GS (32gig) and a 4 (32gig). The battery life of the 3GS is by far the worst and could barely make it through a typical day without charging at least once (typical means surfing the web, a few 5 minute calls, some email, etc). My iPhone4 I can stream radio for 20 minutes while I drive to work, surf, chat, email, and get through an entire day (plus 1 hour at lunch checking news), and drive home and stream another 20+ minutes and the battery is maybe 50% or 60% left. HUGE HUGE improvement. If I simply pick up my 3GS it seems to drain about 5% of the battery. <br /><br />The retina display is nice. Not a game changer for me. I switch back and forth with my 3Gs and 4 when at home in WiFi range (3gs is now a wifi only). Sure, the 4 is sharper but honestly, it really makes little difference in day to day life. <br /><br />Speed: 4 is a tad bit zippier. But not much. By comparision the old 2G is a dog but I'd be hard pressed to say the 4 is anything more than a bit faster than my 3gs.<br /><br />For me the camera (5 megapixel, HD video) + battery are the two biggest things. I really no longer have to say, "ah, I wish I had my real camera with me" when I'm with my iPhone 4 (and my real camera doesn't even do HD video!). I can also feel comfortable that the battery will get me through a morning, long day and into the evening without needing to plug in to a wall or computer. <br /><br />3gs 32gig for $99 or 4, 32gig for $299? Easy, take the 3gs.<br /><br />But anything closer than that, go for the 4.</comment>
		<comment id="13" responses="0">oh, and the cell phone coverage? Dropped connections? <br /><br />Pfft... might happen with some but I've yet to experience it. Lefty, righty, hands wrapped tightly around... I can't get it to drop a call. Wish I could sometimes :)</comment>
		<comment id="14" responses="0">Faster processor, more memory, and faster upload speeds. You are incorrect in stating the two have the same networking ability. The 4 is SIGNIFICANTLY faster in uploads and downloads due to having a newer and faster communication chip, both for 3g and WiFi. The 4 support 802.11n and not just 802.11g, and when operating over 3g, I have noticed my 4 downloads up to 4 MB and uploads up to 2, while my 3gs can barely do 2.5/768k</comment>
		<comment id="15" responses="0">@i-arman, I have a femtocell from AT&amp;#38;T (3G MicroCell) and there are no monthly charges so that is a carrier specific 'feature'. But I'm with you--it is silly for them to charge because they are getting happier customers and reducing their load on the nearby towers making a better experience for the neighbors. A win-win, and they are often using competitors bandwidth (e.g. I have Comcast)!</comment>
		<comment id="16" responses="0">I disagree that Apple "has a poor history of making sure its older products are compatible with new features it introduces in newer products."<br /><br />I had a Quicksilver tower that was 10 years old and it still ran the latest version of Final Cut.<br /><br />Just because the first generation of the phone can't run iOS4 doesn't make them have a "poor history." I doubt most phones have a lifespan of more than 3 years anyway.</comment>
		<comment id="17" responses="2">My wife looked at, held, and said "No" to the iPhone4. She didn't have a strong need for the cameras, retina display, etc. and is not a techie. She really disliked the iPhone4 form factor, i.e., flat, rectangular with sharp edges. I have to agree with her that Apple blew it when they went with the flat backed case. The 3GS and the old or new iPod Touch have a much better "feel". Maybe Apple will go back to the winning form factor, maybe not.
<br />
<br />In any case, she is unlikely to trade up her Blackberry Curve to any iPhone for now. Availability of the 3GS is still close to "zero" in Canada.</comment>
		<comment id="18" responses="0">What poor reporting CNET! The 3GS DOES have digital zoom for still images... Also iPhone 4 DOES support a faster cellular data speed as well as 802.11n Wifi, again faster than 3GS...</comment>
		<comment id="19" responses="1">Could i use an iphone4 without AT&amp;#38;T service and with wifi service, for text message ,phone calls and internet.???/</comment>
		<comment id="20" responses="0">Like many things on CNet, the article was obviously written by someone not really very knowledgeable about iPhones. And didn't bother to check facts.</comment>
		<comment id="21" responses="0">@whavier<br /><br />Absolutely!</comment>
		<comment id="22" responses="0">Article title, purest click magnet.</comment>
		<comment id="23" responses="0">Hey guys, just bought my hackintosh without the undue headaches from http://www.macsrpcs.com , I used a friend of mine?s hackintosh which he bought from the same place and these guys are awesome the best there is. I received my manual and step by step installation on how to reinstall. Been using mine for FCP, and Logic Studio.</comment>
		<comment id="24" responses="0">Its funny how people call it the iPhone 4g, thinking it meant it was gonna have 4g coverage. It means 4th generation. But thats what makes people run to android thinking the ads say it has 4g coverage/speed</comment>
		<comment id="25" responses="0">Another way to get around the sales tax on full price is to buy a refurb. For some reason the refurbs are taxed at the sale price.<br /><br />I can confirm that this works in CA since I bought my 3GS as a refurb when I upgraded from the original iPhone</comment>
		<comment id="26" responses="0">need of bumpers and glass breaking issues + more apple tax LOL</comment>
	</comments>
	</post>
	<post id="http://news.cnet.com/8301-10805_3-20022684-75.html?part=rss&amp;amp;subj=news&amp;amp;tag=2547-1_3-0-20">
	<title>Silverlight gets its own one-day developer event</title>
	<body>


(Credit:
CNET)

If there were any remaining doubts about Silverlight's importance to Microsoft, the company seems to be going out of its way to put them to rest. 
Next month Microsoft is holding a Silverlight-focused, one day event both at its Redmond campus and streamed online, which is aimed at giving developers a look at what's coming next for the Silverlight platform. The event will also offer developers hands-on training sessions showing them how to make use of the runtime in
Windows Phone 7 applications, online, and in native desktop software applications.

Microsoft is billing the event, which is part of the company's Firestarter series, as a being "just like an extra day of PDC, dedicated to Silverlight." This is of special note given Silverlight's relative absence from Microsoft's Professional Developers Conference, which took place just a few weeks ago. The move was not overlooked by developers, many of whom wanted to know how Silverlight factored into some of the latest Internet Explorer 9 platform developments that were unveiled during the company's keynote address.

The issue was later compounded during an interview with Microsoft's president of server and tools, Bob Muglia, who told ZDNet that the company's strategy with Silverlight had "shifted." Shortly thereafter, Muglia posted to Microsoft's Silverlight Team Blog in an attempt to reaffirm the company's ongoing efforts and dedication to the product, which was followed by news that Silverlight would no longer be required to use some functionality found in Bing maps.

Silverlight continues to be an integral part of Windows Phone 7 development, as the platform makes use of it in the developer tools to build applications. As such, a large portion of next month's event sessions will be focused on Microsoft's new mobile platform. 
</body>
	<comments>
		<comment id="0" responses="3">Muglia put it best in his post...<br /><br />?We think HTML will provide the broadest, cross-platform reach across all these devices. At Microsoft, we?re committed to building the world?s best implementation of HTML 5 for devices running Windows, and at the PDC, we showed the great progress we?re making on this with IE 9. ?<br /><br />Anyone who has actually worked in the enterprise and developed enterprise apps with this technology, knows you can expect increased cost and time to delivery. It's a nightmare.<br /><br />They even said it's basically the platform for their phone. They're just trying to cover their backsides...</comment>
		<comment id="1" responses="0">I work with projects that have deployments of 5,000 -10,000 users in the enterprise. Some very large and complex applications. Both in browser, and out of browser. It doesn't cut it where I work either.<br /><br />It's fine for media applications, and some small web projects - but that's about it. <br /><br />Glad you like it.</comment>
		<comment id="2" responses="0">Agreed. Makes great demoware though.</comment>
		<comment id="3" responses="1">If you're a CIO looking to over promise and under deliver, and if budgets don't matter, choose Silverlight.<br /><br />I agree with several post here (and Muglia from MS), HTML5 is the future, not proprietary plug-in technology.</comment>
	</comments>
	</post>
	<post id="http://news.cnet.com/8301-13579_3-20022691-37.html?part=rss&amp;amp;subj=news&amp;amp;tag=2547-1_3-0-20">
	<title>Going once, going twice...$161,600 for that Apple Computer?</title>
	<body>


Apple 1
(Credit:
Christie&amp;#39;s)

If you're a gadget geek with some spare change--make that a lot of spare change--here's a golden opportunity to indulge. Later this month the first Apple computer--including a letter signed by none other than Apple co-founder CEO Steve Jobs to the original owner--will go on sale at a famous London auction house.

The Christie's brochure describes the computer as a "historic relic," and judging by current technological standards, I suppose that's an accurate description. Just in case you can't remember, the Apple-1, introduced in 1976, came without a casing, power supply, keyboard, or monitor. Still, it was enough to turn Apple into a household name as it also was the first personal computer sold with a fully assembled motherboard. Back during those rollicking days of the early personal computer era, most personal computers got sold as self-assembly kits. Based on the standards of that era, this was consumer-friendliness with an underscore.

Jobs and his co-founder, Steve Wozniak, priced the first Apple-1 computers at $666.66. The machines were shipped to customers from Jobs' parents' house. Christie's says that all of the components are still in their original box. The machine will get put on the auction block November 23. Bidding is set to begin at $161,600.

Read more of "Going once, going twice...$161,600 for that Apple Computer?" at CBSNews.com.
</body>
	<comments>
		<comment id="0" responses="3">That's an awesome piece of history. I'm sure the Smithsonian will be among the bidders.</comment>
		<comment id="1" responses="1">anyone else notice the price on the comp was 666? i think steve is the devil :oP
<br />
<br />(Sarcasm off)</comment>
		<comment id="2" responses="0">I think this is too high a starting bid. It should be $66,666.66</comment>
		<comment id="3" responses="1">I wouldn't call Apple a household name. Nice piece of history, can we start the bidding a little in line with the economy, say $55.50.</comment>
		<comment id="4" responses="1">This works out to about a 17.5% annual return.</comment>
		<comment id="5" responses="1">Obligatory just another Mac that is over-priced, under-powered/featured...<br /><br />LOL J/K</comment>
		<comment id="6" responses="0">Can't wait to see how much my original iPhone will fetch in 20 years!</comment>
		<comment id="7" responses="0">Does it run Windows?</comment>
		<comment id="8" responses="0">Notice the original Apple Computers logo with the apple tree and the snake. What an awesome story! <br /><br />And yes, I don't know how Apple wouldn't be a house-hold name.</comment>
		<comment id="9" responses="1">But does it run Crysis?</comment>
		<comment id="10" responses="1">I'll bet that either Jobs or the Woz will buy it.</comment>
		<comment id="11" responses="0">I thought rollicking said rickrolling. Look at how far we've come in 34 years.</comment>
		<comment id="12" responses="0">I never had a good experience with an Apple computer .but I love my I Pod!</comment>
		<comment id="13" responses="0">Take a bite of the apple, from the tree of knowledge...</comment>
		<comment id="14" responses="0">It'd be cool to own that machine, but it's a little out of my budget...</comment>
		<comment id="15" responses="0">Who knows, maybe another 20 years my original Apple ][ might be a collectors item...</comment>
		<comment id="16" responses="0">$666.66 is not bad for that time figuring the average cost of a personal computer was from $499 to $4999</comment>
		<comment id="17" responses="1">Steve Jobs is not interested, I can guarantee you that. Why? Jobs said in an interview he is not into old stuff, he is about today and tomorrow. He also said when he returned to Apple they had a collection of old Macs on campus like a museum, it was one of the first things he got rid of.</comment>
		<comment id="18" responses="0">$161.6k to start is a LOT to ask for a computer that normally trades in the $50k range for a pristine example. Those mischievous Brits...</comment>
	</comments>
	</post>
	</posts>
