<?xml version="1.0"?>
<posts>
	<post id="http://news.cnet.com/8301-30686_3-20023708-266.html?part=rss&amp;subj=news&amp;tag=2547-1_3-0-20">
	<title>Emergency? Text 911</title>
	<body>
The Federal Communications Commission wants to bring the 911 emergency service into the 21st century with new technologies such as text messaging and automatic alerts.



In a speech Tuesday, FCC Chairman Julius Genachowski said it "is time to bring 911 into the Digital Age." He said this was important, as more and more people in the United States use cell phones. Text messaging, in particular, is an important feature to add to 911 call centers, he said. 
About 70 percent of 911 calls already come from mobile phones, he said. And as more people text instead of talk on their phones, it makes sense to add texting capabilities to the 911 emergency service. Texting is also particularly helpful for people who have disabilities.
 The chairman also noted during his speech that there are also times when talking on the phone to a 911 operator could put the caller and others in more danger. A good example of this was the Virginia Tech campus shooting in 2007. Students tried to text police by sending 911 text messages, but they were unable to reach help.
 Other elements that the FCC would like to see added to 911 service include allowing video and photos to be sent to call centers. This could help first responders get a better feel for what is happening on the ground at an emergency. Next-generation 911 service would expand the multimedia capability of the call centers.
The FCC is also proposing the use of automatic alerts that would allow cameras, environmental sensors, personal medical devices, and other gadgets to notify 911 call centers without any human intervention. This could help first responders get to a chemical spill or highway accident much faster. 
Chairman Genachowski plans to introduce a proceeding in December to seek comment from the public on improving 911 services with new technologies.
</body>
	<comments>
	</comments>
	</post>
	<post id="http://news.cnet.com/8301-11128_3-20023685-54.html?part=rss&amp;subj=news&amp;tag=2547-1_3-0-20">
	<title>Italy has largest PV solar farm in Europe</title>
	<body>


Rovigo, Italy, is a CLEAR (City and Local Environmental Accounting Reporting) town whose motto is &amp;#34;the city of change.&amp;#34;

As of November, the Italian city of Rovigo is home to the largest photovoltaic (PV) solar plant in Europe, SunEdison announced today.
SunEdison, a subsidiary of the silicon wafer manufacturer MEMC Electronic Materials, is right, but even it admits the claim comes with a qualifier by calling the 70-megawatt plant "Europe's largest single site solar farm."
For there are many large-scale solar projects both in existence and under way in Europe involving more megawatts, but very often those announcements of super-megawatt projects are really a series of smaller, interconnected PV farms spread out over a region.
Brandenburg, Germany's Finsterwalde Solar Park, for example, is considered by many to be Europe's largest solar PV plant. But it is technically a series of three interconnected plants referred to as Finsterwalde I, Finsterwalde II, and Finsterwalde III. Together they make up 81 megawatts. While Spain is also known for its aggressive adoption of solar power, the country contains mostly solar farms in the 10- to 30-megawatt range. Olmedilla Photovoltaic Park, currently Spain's largest solar PV farm, is 60 megawatts.


Rovigo, Italy's 70-megawatt PV plant is now the largest single site PV solar plant in Europe.
(Credit:
SunEdison)

So it would be fair to say that SunEdison has developed the largest PV solar plant in Europe contained in one single location. And that location is Rovigo, Italy, a small town located roughly between Bologna and Venice, which prides itself on being "the city of change."
Perhaps it should also be known as the city that quickly changes. The solar park got final approval from the Italian government in March, and was completed and connected to the Italian electric grid as of this November. The 70-megawatt PV plant is expected to generate enough electricity annually to power 17,150 homes.
Maybe the fast-tracked project had to do with the competence of SunEdison, its recent financing progress as a company, or Isolux Corsan, the Spanish construction company SunEdison commissioned to built the PV solar farm. But it's worth noting that the project also had the complete backing of the Italian government from federal through local levels. Rovigo, Italy, also happens to be a member of CLEAR (City and Local Environmental Accounting Reporting). It's an EU initiative in which member towns agree to implement environmental accounting and sustainability plans as part of standard government budget operations.
</body>
	<comments>
	</comments>
	</post>
	<post id="http://news.cnet.com/8301-1023_3-20023681-93.html?part=rss&amp;subj=news&amp;tag=2547-1_3-0-20">
	<title>Study: NASA, White House are social-media savvy</title>
	<body>
NASA and the White House are tops at using social media and the Web compared with a wide range of other public sector groups in the U.S., according to a study out today from the George Washington University School of Business and digital think tank L2.
Authored by George Washington University School of Business dean Doug Guthrie, New York University professor and L2 founder Scott Galloway, and experts from L2, the first annual Digital IQ Index for the Public Sector (PDF) measured the effectiveness of Web sites, digital marketing, social media, and mobile platform support among 100 different public sector groups.
Included were independent agencies, the executive branch, advocacy organizations, armed forces, political parties, industry associations, and multilateral organizations. Each group was given a digital IQ grade based on the strength of its online prowess.
In general, the study found that most groups in the public eye are taking advantage of digital technologies to spread their messages, but the majority are still stuck on old traditional media strategies. However, several organizations showed a savvy understanding and use of social media and the Web.


(Credit:
L2)

With a digital IQ score of 184, NASA came in first place, considered the clear leader among all public sector groups and innovative in every area covered in the study. Its Web site brings in more than 3 million people each month, while the agency boasts 600,000 Twitter followers and 150,000 Facebook fans, according to L2. NASA also takes advantage of the latest online technologies, using 3-D visualizations, streaming video, and integration with location-based social network Gowalla.
The White House came in second place with a score of 158. Pointing to online contests to help balance the budget and regular presidential addresses broadcast on YouTube, L2 cited the administration for its smart use of the Web. President Obama and members of his staff also tap into Facebook and Twitter, with several of them offering a personal touch to their postings and tweets.
The government scored big in another area. The Armed Forces category, which includes the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marines, and other branches, captured a Digital IQ of 117, the highest of any overall category.
On the downside, 51 percent of the groups studied were branded as "challenged" or "feeble" by L2. Those in the "challenged" group included the Tea Party Patriots, the Veterans of Foreign Wars, and the National Endowment for the Arts. The "feeble" list included The Department of Commerce, the National Organization for Women, and the Anti-Defamation League, all cited for weak online and social media activities.
Going forward, the study suggests that the use of the Web and social media will have a strong effect on which groups have the greatest impact.
"The advent of the social Web has fundamentally changed our nation's public sector organizations," L2 founder Galloway said in a statement. "We're likely to see a transfer in power and influence from organizations that are digitally inept to those who are digitally deft."
</body>
	<comments>
	</comments>
	</post>
	<post id="http://news.cnet.com/8301-13577_3-20023700-36.html?part=rss&amp;subj=news&amp;tag=2547-1_3-0-20">
	<title>U.K. bishop suspended for royal potshot on Facebook</title>
	<body>


Note to Twitter-happy bishops: the lady in blue is your boss.
(Credit:

CC LamrockImages/Flickr)

The Diocese of London official biography for Peter Broadbent, bishop of Willesden, explains that the man of the cloth is a season-ticket-holding football fan who appreciates good beer, so he sounds like an upstanding gentleman.
But according to a number of U.K. news outlets, Broadbent is treading in some very unholy waters these days after making remarks on Facebook about the impending nuptials of Prince William and fiancee Kate Middleton, in which he referred to the events surrounding their April 2011 wedding as "nauseating tosh," compared the couple to "shallow celebrities," and predicted the marriage wouldn't last longer than seven years.
He also tweeted, in posts that have since been removed, that the whole affair is "massively irrelevant (if an expensive frippery)."
He may well be right, and he gets points in my book for using the fantastic word "frippery." Still, it's a fairly serious matter in the U.K. Were this a U.S. clergy making comments about the younger generation of stateside spawn in the news--say, Bristol Palin on "Dancing with the Stars"--that person likely would be criticized for a mean-spirited remark but likely wouldn't be punished much. But the British monarch, Queen Elizabeth II, is also technically the head of the Church of England, so in effect, Broadbent was bad-mouthing his boss' grandson on big and far-reaching social-media sites, and that doesn't fly too well. The bishop, though he has apologized for his case of Facebook trigger-finger, has been suspended indefinitely.
"I have now had an opportunity to discuss with Bishop Peter how his comments came to be made and I have noted his unreserved apology," a statement from the Bishop of London printed by The Guardian read. "Nevertheless, I have asked him to withdraw from public ministry until further notice."
The Bishop of Willesden has apologized publicly. "I have conveyed to Prince Charles and to Prince William and Kate Middleton my sincere regrets for the distress caused by my remarks and the subsequent media attention about the forthcoming Royal Wedding," he wrote in a statement that was posted to the Diocese of London's Web site. "I recognize that the tone of my language and the content of what I said were deeply offensive, and I apologize unreservedly for the hurt caused. It was unwise of me to engage in a debate with others on a semi-public Internet forum and to express myself in such language. I accept that this was a major error of judgment on my part. I wish Prince William and Kate Middleton a happy and lifelong marriage, and will hold them in my prayers."
It's no secret that loose lips on Facebook can get you fired--clergy, it seems, are not immune to this either.
</body>
	<comments>
		<comment id="0" responses="0">Well, if it doesn't last, I'm sure his dad will know how to deal with the situation.</comment>
	</comments>
	</post>
	<post id="http://news.cnet.com/8301-13506_3-20023675-17.html?part=rss&amp;subj=news&amp;tag=2547-1_3-0-20">
	<title>Report: More than 50 3D PS3 games on the way</title>
	<body>


Playing 3D games on the PlayStation 3.
(Credit:
Jeff Bakalar/CNET)

It won't be long before the
PlayStation 3 is accommodating a slew of 3D titles, a Sony executive has reportedly told gaming publication Develop Online.
Sony Computer Entertainment Europe Studio Director Mick Hocking told Develop Online recently that Sony is currently "applying 3D to more than 20 internal games." He went on to say that third-party studios are also seeing value in creating 3D titles for the PlayStation 3.
"Overall we have more than 50 titles currently being converted into 3D, and this number if growing fast," Hocking reportedly told Develop in the interview. "Some of them are massive names. That's a really, really good sign that the industry is behind our unique message that 3D is a key element in the future of home consoles."
Unfortunately, Hocking didn't elaborate on which titles are currently being converted to 3D. But one of the most anticipated 3D releases for the PlayStation 3 is Killzone 3, which is currently in development. According to Hocking, when players "plant an explosive charge on the wall" in the game, the 3D effect makes gamers think the "charge has been placed on your TV. It's amazing."
Sony has been investing heavily in 3D both in and out of the gaming space. Earlier this year, the company updated the PlayStation 3's firmware to support 3D games. In September, it updated the PlayStation 3 again to accommodate 3D Blu-ray movie playback. The company is also heavily invested in the
3D TV market, selling sets with the technology built-in.
For now, 3D games are somewhat hard to come by. Activision's Call of Duty: Black Ops is arguably the most notable 3D title on store shelves. But if what Hocking reportedly said is true, it might not be long before a slew of 3D titles make their way to Sony's console.
Further reading:
Hands-on with PS3 in 3D
</body>
	<comments>
		<comment id="0" responses="0">The quantity seems irrelevant. I mean, PS3 got 3d. That's all you need to know. Because they have 3d it is being applied to all their future games. Is it awesome? Yes, well, maybe. I'm not a big fan of 3d but if you are it's awesome. Is the actual number relevant? Not really.</comment>
		<comment id="1" responses="0">i am still playing games on my Sinclair ZX Spectrum :)</comment>
		<comment id="2" responses="0">I'm thrilled. :)</comment>
	</comments>
	</post>
	<post id="http://news.cnet.com/8301-13506_3-20023667-17.html?part=rss&amp;subj=news&amp;tag=2547-1_3-0-20">
	<title>Nielsen: Kids want iPad for holidays</title>
	<body>


The iPad is the most desired piece of tech among 6- to 12-year-olds.
(Credit:
James Martin/CNET)

If your kids are begging for tech, the iPad might just top their holiday wish-list.
According to Nielsen, which conducted a survey in October to see which tech products American kids want through the beginning of next year, Apple's tablet sat at the top of a 17-item list, with 31 percent of children between the ages of 6 and 12 saying they want to get their hands on the device.
A computer and
Apple's iPod Touch tied for second, with 29 percent of children saying they wanted those products. Nintendo's DS took the fourth spot with 25 percent of kids eyeing the portable gaming device.
Sony's
PlayStation 3, any (non-iPhone) smartphone, and a mobile phone all tied for fifth place with 21 percent of kids having interest in those products this year. The
Apple iPhone, a television, and the as-yet released Nintendo 3DS rounded out the top 10, each with 20 percent of children's interest. An e-reader was the least popular gift this year, ranking 17th, with just 11 percent of kids saying they wanted one. Nielsen also found out what youths 13 and up are coveting. Among that group, a computer led the way with 20 percent desiring a PC or Mac. A television and a (non-iPhone) smartphone tied for the second spot with 19 percent. Apple's iPad, a Blu-ray player, and an e-reader took the next three spots with 18 percent, 17 percent, and 15 percent of teens showing interest, respectively. The Nintendo Wii ranked seventh among teens with 15 percent saying they wanted one. It was followed by the iPhone and PlayStation 3, each with votes from 13 percent of teens. Sony's PlayStation Portable was the least-desired tech product among teenagers, ranking 17th, with just 5 percent of showing interest in it. Nielsen's study follows a similar survey released last month by the Duracell Toy Report. According to that survey, nearly 40 percent of kids between the ages of 5 and 16 want an iPhone 4, iPod Touch, or iPad this holiday season. </body>
	<comments>
		<comment id="0" responses="2">yup. my 6 yo wants one. he's been using my iphone, but he won't have access to that once the new unlock comes out. not sure i can stomach the price of teh ipad. i'll be comparing the other competitors that are in the 250-300 range to see which (if any) to get. it all comes down to functionality, stability, and usability by a 6 yo that will determine which device wins. most of the apps he downloads are free mah jong so, i don't see a big problem with the kind of apps he is getting.</comment>
		<comment id="1" responses="0">My 5 year old nephew loves his dad's iPad and plays on it constantly. It doesn't surprise me at all that kids want one. I think the iPad actually tops a lot of people's wish-lists this year and I expect to see sales reflect that.</comment>
		<comment id="2" responses="1">Nook Color has been picked as the editors choice by PC Magazine. Pro reviewers of other sites (CNET, ZDNet, Engadget, AllThingsDigital, etc.) mentioned that it tested to be pretty fast for apps and PDF's, has a beautiful screen, and is a great value for the holiday season for $249.
<br />Nook Color's screen is better (less reflective) for reading than iPad's thanks to new LG screen with anti-glare coating, and it is better performing in sunlight than iPad's. Also, as it's smaller in size than iPad, the text appears sharper on Nook's screen. <br />Barnes &amp;#38; Noble special Nook SDK runs on top of the standard Android one and gives developers access to exclusive extensions and APIs for the Nook and its interface so porting Android apps is
<br />not difficult. B&amp;#38;N says it is more like optimising them for Nook than porting them.</comment>
		<comment id="3" responses="1">Ha ha. The Nook is no iPad.</comment>
		<comment id="4" responses="4">I have twin 3 year olds and we've been thinking about getting an iPad. Problem I have is watching the two of them fight over a $500 toy, only takes a few seconds for the iPad to become iBroken.</comment>
		<comment id="5" responses="3">I have a broken foot.</comment>
		<comment id="6" responses="1">Hey! eco733! I hear the Nook Color is really great - how much is it again?</comment>
		<comment id="7" responses="0">I think I'll look at a nook color. It's half the price of an iPad. if it handles ePub I may actually do more than look.</comment>
	</comments>
	</post>
	<post id="http://news.cnet.com/8301-13577_3-20023684-36.html?part=rss&amp;subj=news&amp;tag=2547-1_3-0-20">
	<title>Oops! The Facebook-Lamebook mess gets uglier</title>
	<body>


(Credit:
Lamebook)
Facebook lately has made controversial legal threats against a number of social-media sites, like Teachbook and Placebook, which it says are unlawfully capitalizing on the popularity of Facebook by using the suffix -book in their names.
But then there's Lamebook, a mischievous parody compendium of funny Facebook content that decided to sue Facebook, citing First Amendment protections, so that Facebook couldn't sue it first. TechCrunch writer Robin Wauters noticed overnight on Monday that Lamebook's Facebook fan page had been blocked, that outbound links to the site were severed, and that "like" buttons to its content were disabled.
That basically means that Lamebook was barred from taking advantage of the Facebook "graph," the communications framework that's made the social network as powerful as it is, and the fact that Facebook can block access to it so easily can be seen as setting a scary precedent. The analogy, one could say, would be Google removing a company's links from its search results if it had legal action against it. (Google does remove things like spam, to be clear.)
"Well, Facebook didn't like us sticking up for ourselves, so they shut down our fan page, are preventing any users from 'liking' us, and won't even let you share URLs with your friends if they point to Lamebook," a notice from Lamebook to its readers explained. "In light of this, be sure to follow us on Twitter so you get updated with the latest and funniest of the lame!"
But Facebook appears to have backtracked a bit in this case after initially confirming to TechCrunch's Wauters that it was barring Lamebook URLs from being linked on Facebook. Blocking the links, one executive said later in an e-mail to Wauters, went too far. "This was a mistake on our part," Chief Technology Officer Bret Taylor wrote in a notice that was posted to TechCrunch. "In the process of dealing with a routine trademark violation issue regarding some links posted to Facebook, we blocked all mentions of the phrase 'lamebook' on Facebook. We are committed to promoting free expression on Facebook. We apologize for our mistake in this case, and we are working to fix the process that led to this happening."
On the broader Lamebook lawsuit, Facebook had previously told CNET: "It's unfortunate that after months of working with Lamebook to amicably resolve what we believe is an improper attempt to build a brand that trades off Facebook's popularity and fame, they have turned to litigation. We are confident in our position and believe we will prevail in court."
</body>
	<comments>
		<comment id="0" responses="3">Face it - Facebook is the next evil online empire.</comment>
		<comment id="1" responses="0">Facebook is not going to win any lawsuit. I know years ago Microsoft tried to keep any other company from using the word Windows in their Software Titles. About the only success they had with that was suing the Linux OS Lindows.</comment>
		<comment id="2" responses="0">Facebook win? No way. These people must be ego maniacs. I mean, would Microsoft sue just because someone else used "soft" in their name. The Facebook people are not too bright.</comment>
		<comment id="3" responses="0">Another indication that Facebook is run by a bunch of ethically clueless juveniles.</comment>
	</comments>
	</post>
	<post id="http://news.cnet.com/1606-2_3-50096421.html?part=rss&amp;subj=news&amp;tag=2547-1_3-0-20">
	<title>Texting 911</title>
	<comments>
	</comments>
	</post>
	<post id="http://news.cnet.com/8301-11128_3-20023670-54.html?part=rss&amp;subj=news&amp;tag=2547-1_3-0-20">
	<title>Hertz adds more EV options</title>
	<body>


Hertz is adding 100 Coda EVs to its California rental fleet for 2011 as part of its Hertz Global EV initiative to introduce electric car options to its customers.
(Credit:
Hertz)

Starting in 2011, Hertz will offer a total of 100 Coda EV sedans to its California rental fleet, the company announced Tuesday.
Coda's four-door sedan gets between 90 and 120 miles on a single charge, and can be plugged in to a standard household outlet as well as a fast-charging EV station.
The deal is part of the Hertz Global EV program, in which the company plans over a period of time to add all-electric vehicle options, EV charging stations, and a car-sharing program to its existing rental car business.
In February, Hertz announced it was partnering with Nissan to offer the Leaf EV starting in 2011 at certain city rental locations in the U.S. and Europe. Then in September at the 2010 Annual Meeting of the Clinton Global Initiative (CGI) the auto rental giant announced its Hertz Global EV program and commitment to promoting electric vehicles.
Hertz already offers a "Green Collection" in its U.S. rental car lineup that includes the Smart ForTwo, the Toyota Prius, and the Nissan Altima hybrid, among others.
In addition to offering an EV option to rental car customers, the change provides a showcase to participating automakers and a venue through which drivers interested in leasing or owning an EV can experience an extended test drive.
Hertz' latest NeverLost GPS system informs drivers of the nearest Hertz drop-off location, in addition to offering weather updates, airport info, Yellow Pages listings, and typical GPS information. It's possible the company plans to also use the tool to inform EV drivers of the nearest available charging station.
Hertz has repeatedly said that because it already has an established network of rental locations, it is in a unique position to get its clients--consisting of "urban drivers, university students, travelers, and corporations"--interested in electric vehicles.
A recent study found that fleet buyers may have the biggest influence on whether electric vehicles are widely adopted.
</body>
	<comments>
		<comment id="0" responses="0">Awesome move Hertz! Moving forward into the EV Hybrid auto world!</comment>
	</comments>
	</post>
	<post id="http://news.cnet.com/8301-11128_3-20023678-54.html?part=rss&amp;subj=news&amp;tag=2547-1_3-0-20">
	<title>What to expect for Chevy Volt mileage</title>
	<body>


(Credit:
Martin LaMonica/CNET)


Now that the electric Nissan Leaf has gotten an official fuel economy rating, all eyes are on the Chevy Volt, the other high-profile electric vehicle soon coming to market. Although there's no definitive rating just yet, Chevy Volt drivers will experience a wide range of mileage regardless of what's on the sticker.

The Environmental Protection Agency is using "miles-per-gallon equivalent" (MPGe) as it top-line metric when evaluating battery-powered cars in order to help consumers make comparisons among gas, diesel, all-electric, and hybrid options. 





(Credit:
EPA via CNN)



In the case of the Nissan Leaf, which will be available for sale in certain states next month, that translates to an aggregate 99 MPGe between city and highway driving. The Leaf is also rated "best" for fuel economy and "best" for the environment in the midsize vehicle category.

The Chevy Volt is moved by an electric motor, too, but the power system is a hybrid that uses both a battery and a gasoline engine. It can run between 25 and 50 miles on the 16-kilowatt-hour battery and then a gasoline engine kicks in to run a generator that charges the battery.

So in theory, a driver who stays within the electric driving range of the Volt can get the same fuel economy rating as the Leaf which, according to the EPA's methodology, is about 100 miles per gallon. But once the gas engine kicks in, the
car is in "charge sustaining" mode and the miles per gallon will drop to the mid to high 30s, according to GM.

The EPA is likely to include an electric vehicle range with the Volt and an MPGe number that combines all-electric drive and the miles per gallon in charge-sustaining mode, according to GM spokesman Rob Peterson. He said GM is like "an expecting grandparent," waiting to hear the word on the Volt's fuel economy rating before it goes on sale next month.

"It's a fairly complex situation, a complex car, and a complex process by which the EPA is trying to determine mileage," he said. "Charge-sustaining fuel economy is the worst-case scenario because you're making the assumption that the car never charges or your miles per gallon is what you get after the battery depleted."

Early drivers of the Volt have experienced that range of mileage. Motor Trend found that without plugging in, the Volt gets mileage in the high 30s to low 40s. 
But when a driver is able to draw mostly from the battery, the mileage changes dramatically for the better. Lyle Dennis, who runs the GM-Volt.com Web site and is an early driver, has been able to charge twice a day and drive almost entirely on the battery, giving him a fuel economy equivalent of 168 miles per gallon equivalent on occasion.

The Volt is designed to tap its internal combustion engine once in a while so that the gasoline and oil don't get stale. About once every 30 days, the car will automatically turn on the engine and cycle through the stored gas, said Peterson. 
The ratings for the Volt and the Leaf highlight the difficulty of comparing gasoline-powered cars as new auto technologies are introduced. The EPA, which is in the process of developing new fuel economy labels, uses 33 kilowatt-hours as the equivalent of the energy in one gallon of gasoline to come up with the MPGe. It includes the pollution created by generating electricity to come up with its overall grading on the "best to worst" scale for environment.

But some electric-car enthusiasts argue that fuel economy for electric vehicles should be expressed only using kilowatt-hours, the same unit for energy used on electric bills. So instead of miles per gallon, it would be how many kilowatt-hours are used to go 100 miles, for example. Another suggestion has been cost per mile.

The sticker for the Leaf does indeed include a kilowatt-hour-per-100-mile rating at 34 and an estimated charge time. The Volt, which needs the EPA label before the car goes on sale next month, is expected to use the same format.


The electric-car all-stars come out (photos) 








</body>
	<comments>
		<comment id="0" responses="0">It is good to find proper EV tests coming along now.This tech is going to be BIG,,,but we have to 'get our fingers out'' and sort out the required infrastructure otherwise it will be the usual too little too late.If you don't believe me,,get this,,a Chinese company has just bought in the UK an electric utility company (Eon) and a british seaport company.So now they,the Chinese,have the means of mass import/export of EVs and also the infrastructure to supply the electricity!! Please do not think that we in the west can rely on our politico's to sort these threats out.They must have the right advice to make sure that we 'keep up''!!</comment>
		<comment id="1" responses="1">Is there any place on the sticker for the MPC(Miles Per Charge) rating?</comment>
		<comment id="2" responses="0">I've always wanted a coal burning car that had to send the power to me inefficiently over hundreds of miles of pipes.</comment>
		<comment id="3" responses="2">If I read it corectly, every 30 days it will empy it's tank. As I like to keap at least a half full tank incase I need it and can go well over 30 days on a single tank, it sound like the volt will not save much gas for me.</comment>
		<comment id="4" responses="0">--<br /><br />The irony of the Volt is: Anyone who can choose to blow $32K-$40K on a new car obviously doesn't need to worry about saving money on gas.<br /><br />If you really want to be frugal, buy a two-year-old Elantra or Civic.<br /><br />--</comment>
		<comment id="5" responses="0">Ratings need to keep pace with the changing technology. You can only dumb down the complex matter of energy usage so far. In case of cars like the Volt it should be easy to find on the label:<br /><br />-range on a full charge with a new battery<br />-Kwh cost to charge an empty battery with example charge cost for local Kwh price<br />- comparable Mpg on battery given certain Kwh and gasoline cost just to show people how to calculate this (you'd hope people interested in a Volt can figure this out but still)<br />-MPG city/highway when driving on the gasoline engine<br /><br /><br />Then there's the whole thing about battery depreciation. Does it age when parked and left alone? Does it age when charged and discharged? Is aging affected by hard use? Arguably MPG of gasoline engines varies with engine age as well and that's not an issue now so perhaps it can be ignored.</comment>
	</comments>
	</post>
	<post id="http://news.cnet.com/8301-1023_3-20023665-93.html?part=rss&amp;subj=news&amp;tag=2547-1_3-0-20">
	<title>Tim Berners-Lee: The Web is threatened</title>
	<body>
Turning 20 next month, the World Wide Web has become a ubiquitous part of our lives. But the freedom and open nature of the Web that we sometimes take for granted are threatened, according to its creator.
In a long article published yesterday in Scientific American, Tim Berners-Lee writes that the Web as we know it is affected by elements that have "begun to chip away at its principles."
He points a finger at social-networking sites that he says are "walling off information posted by users from the rest of the Web." Though he acknowledges that sites like Facebook and LinkedIn offer value, he criticizes their "silo" approach in which the information is self-contained and can't easily be transferred to or used on another site.

Images: Berners-Lee and the dawn of the Web 

View the full gallery

Touching on Net neutrality, he cites Internet providers that may decide to slow down traffic to Web sites with which they haven't made special deals. He also alludes to cable TV companies that now sell Internet access and are deciding whether to limit their Web-based offerings to only their own entertainment content.
Berners-Lee also takes aim at governments, both democratic and totalitarian, that violate rights and monitor online behavior, sometimes without due process. As one example, he cites the U.K.'s Digital Economy Act, which lets the British government tell an Internet service provider to cut off the Internet account of anyone suspected of copyright infringement.
As another example, Berners-Lee mentions the proposed "Combating Online Infringement and Counterfeits Act," which would have given the U.S. Justice Department the power to shut down Web sites "deemed" to be trafficking in pirated films, software, music, and other protected content. Though the bill failed to pass, its opponents have warned that the Senate will likely try again to pass it.
If uncontrolled, these activities could limit people's ability to use the Web as they do today, Berners-Lee writes.
"If we, the Web's users, allow these and other trends to proceed unchecked, the Web could be broken into fragmented islands," he writes. "We could lose the freedom to connect with whichever Web sites we want. The ill effects could extend to smartphones and pads, which are also portals to the extensive information that the Web provides."
To guard against this erosion of the Web's freedom and openness, Berners-Lee outlines principles to protect this tool.
He believes the Web must remain universal and that people should be able to publish anything online. The Web should be usable by individuals with disabilities. And it should be accessible from any device. The Web must also stay decentralized, so you don't need the OK from any central authority or organization to add a page or make a link.
The basic technology that we use to build the Web must remain free, with no royalties required, according to Berners-Lee. Open standards can better ensure the limitless nature of the Web, with anyone able to create anything--from a major Web site to a simple blog. Keeping the Web layer separate from the overall Internet is also vital since it ensures that the Internet can be improved and enhanced without any changes to the Web itself.
Finally, Berners-Lee believes legislation is needed to safeguard Net neutrality. Though he feels the Internet and Web are best served with a minimum of regulation, certain basic values sometimes require laws for their own protection and preservation.
If the basic freedom and openness of the Web are allowed to thrive, Berners-Lee sees a future with great potential respect for "basic human values."
"The goal of the Web is to serve humanity," he wrote." We build it now so that those who come to it later will be able to create things that we cannot ourselves imagine."
</body>
	<comments>
		<comment id="0" responses="0">They are blaming the wrong people. For piracy, are the people who download stuff for free really the problem? Of course not. I remember when MP3s just started it out. It was a cool feature, but I still bought CDs because I listen to music on the road. Then the MP3 PLAYER WAS RELEASED! Huge boom! Now everyone wanted in on Napster and wanted to download free music to carry around on their PORTABLE MP3 DEVICE! You wanna blame people for music piracy? Blame Apple! Blame Rio! Blame Sandisk! Blame all those people that make MP3 music piracy actually possible and efficient to do!<br /><br />Game piracy. How come some companies don't complain about piracy and others do? If you look at successful companies like Blizzard, Activision, Bioware, Nintendo, Sony, Valve... they don't complain, because they are rich! They make profit, and why? Because their games don't suck!!! And the you have companies like EA, Ubisoft, 2K, Midway, and many more complaining that people aren't buying their games anymore and piracy is to blame! No... people don't buy your games because they SUCK!!! No one like buying untested glitchy and buggy games. No one likes buying a $70 game title that can be finished in less than 8 hours when they could of just rented it for 2 days for less than $10. So many companies only release a free playable demo days or weeks after the game has launched! That's STUPID!!!! I should be able to "try before I buy" any game so that when I do cough in $70, I know I'm buying a quality game that I will enjoy and not just resell back to EBgames and only get $30 back for it!<br /><br />And social networks... not part of any, never will! Whenever I see news reports or Youtube videos of some kid crying because he/she was harassed and embaressed all over the Internet... I just laugh. I knew stuff like that would happen but people don't care. Social networks like Facebook and Myspace are as bad as just living in a house made of transparent glass! Anyone that walks by could just stare at my life, look at me, and do what they want.</comment>
		<comment id="1" responses="2">Strange morality you have, like blaming guns for murder not the criminal. Downloading valuable content without paying for it is theft, period.</comment>
		<comment id="2" responses="0">Psst! You guys may not know this offhand, but bittorrent doesn't use HTML once you get a link from a tracker. Just thought you'd want to know that.</comment>
		<comment id="3" responses="0">The First Law: Systems don't only operate as designed; they operate in every way possible.</comment>
		<comment id="4" responses="3">Ohh, look, the computer is running OS X ...</comment>
		<comment id="5" responses="1">This is the era of the 'Wild Wild Web' when rules are few and people do as they will. When in recent human history is that ever left open? Freedom exists as long as people use it responsibly... as soon as people abuse a freedom, it is open to regulation and removal for everyone. <br /><br /> Who is going to control things in the end? Well... who pays for the internet? The end consumer pays some portion of it, but lest we forget the world wide web as we know it exist because of three little letters and a punctuation mark... yep, .com, and .com represents the word 'commercial.' The internet that we have comes largely from commercial dollars pumped into it to be a portal to spread awareness for business and revenue, advertising and $$$ for companies and corporations. The whole 'information should be free,' 'wide open standards,' and the pursuit of an online world without borders is riding on the back of the beast that brought the internet to where it is. The internet may have started military, and opened the door in universities, but it's the money pushers in business that put it into every home. Don't be fooled, the internet is going in the direction that was intended... to take every opportunity to get every dollar from every possible source. Expect regulation from government to protect corporate profits, expect a money stranglehold on everything you do from ISPs (selling internet by the bandwidth use, and charging more for heavy application). Expect everything to cost you more, and give you less, and occasionally look up to tally the cost. When it gets too high for you, give it up. <br /><br /> I use my internet as my source of entertainment... I waste time on social networks, I use it as a content provider for media, I get my news from it. The moment this starts to cost me more than my subscription to my ISP or the cost of seeing ads pop up all over, I'll let it go. I won't pay my ISP extra to go over so many GB per month. I won't pay monthly fees to subscribe to every service under the sun. I won't let myself be nickeled and dimed to death for something non-essential, even though I use it so heavily, but I also won't rant about my right to have these things or what I'm losing as business and government gradually exerts their control. By the time net neutrality finally tanks, when everything you do online is recorded and scrutinized, and when every website you go to automatically docks 1 cent from your bank account as a service fee, I'll probably be out in the park flying a $2 kite with my son, and probably worlds happier for it.</comment>
		<comment id="6" responses="0">All that bloviating from my one line, Mr. Random? You take yourself far too seriously. I have no idea what RIAA is . Be assured I have my own ideas and ability to make independent judgments. I have values. I do not steal. You seem to be an apologist for theft. I disapprove of that behavior and I think it is a lazy, low-class and selfish man's way of thinking.</comment>
		<comment id="7" responses="0">All that bloviating from my one line, Mr. Random? You take yourself far too seriously. I have no idea what RIAA is . Be assured I have my own ideas and ability to make independent judgments. I have values. I do not steal. You seem to be an apologist for theft. I disapprove of that behavior and I think it is a lazy, low-class and selfish man's way of thinking.</comment>
		<comment id="8" responses="0">the web is not the internet, and the internet is not the web. Sounds like he's worried his "fame"
<br />will wain as the obvious becomes mainstream. He should have gone for box no.2 and taken the cash like Andreeson, then he could afford to create a foundation to fight for an open free global web system that can call him father.
<br />
<br />my guess soon he'll be on the Lanier, Rushkoff side of the digital divide political war, as he realizes "he" too has lost that CC feeling of daddy/mommy love. Growing up has its perks and it's responsabilties.
<br />
<br />Information should be valued. not just "free" to be valued by some other guy.
<br />
<br />www.choosecreativecommerce.wordpress.com</comment>
	</comments>
	</post>
	<post id="http://news.cnet.com/8301-11128_3-20023671-54.html?part=rss&amp;subj=news&amp;tag=2547-1_3-0-20">
	<title>Gore: U.S. corn ethanol 'was not a good policy'</title>
	<comments>
		<comment id="0" responses="9">He's now heavily invested in "2nd" generation technology that he wants us all to subsidize so he can make another bundle of money.<br /><br />When are the rest of the people going to realize what a crook this guy is?</comment>
		<comment id="1" responses="2">Adding 10% ethanol means losing 25% in gas mileage thus uses 15% more gas. So, ethanol was good for the food and gas industry, but very bad for us dumb old consumers that can't pass any legislation.<br /><br />2003 Dodge Neon - City - 27mpg on gas but with 10% ethanol just 21mpg<br />1996 Ford Explorer - City - 21mpg on gas but with 10% ethanol just 15mpg<br /><br />Do the math yourself:<br /><br />1. Fill up with "regular" gas.<br />2. Reset your trip odometer.<br />3. Near empty, fill up again, note the number of gallons.<br />4. Check the odometer, to see how far you traveled, or divide miles/gallons for mpg.<br />5. Repeat 1-4 this time with "10% ethanol" gas.<br /><br />SEE THE DIFFERENCE!!!</comment>
		<comment id="2" responses="0">And watch out for Manbearpig!!!</comment>
		<comment id="3" responses="1">"U.S. corn ethanol 'was not a good policy'"<br /><br />No (fooling), Sherlock.</comment>
		<comment id="4" responses="0">Hard to believe it took dangling chad this long to figure that out....</comment>
		<comment id="5" responses="0">Leave Gore alone people. Do you people have any idea how much is costs for a good massage?</comment>
		<comment id="6" responses="0">Has anyone started a website out there that shows service stations where you can still get actual gasoline that hasn't been gimped by ethanol? That would be pretty cool. I know I go on the hunt when it's time for my fill up. Al Gore, the Federal Government, and all the other crooks can suitcase their Ethanol.</comment>
		<comment id="7" responses="0">The only thing Gore is sorry about is, all of that tax and spend money he and Clinton could have had their paws on otherwise, if they only didn't subsidize ethanol.</comment>
		<comment id="8" responses="2">Corn and all of its derivatives in food is what has made America obese. The poorer you are the fatter you are. Sad.</comment>
		<comment id="9" responses="0">Most energy creation has a negative yield so what does it matter.</comment>
		<comment id="10" responses="1">Ethanol as a fuel is not a good idea for any number of reasons, many of which have been noted in the previous posts. Neither is Al Gore, whose use of the 'global warming crisis' to keep his name in the public eye is deplorable. Al, baby, I read your book, an exercise in the use of PowerPoint and Excel to present mostly anecdotal and empirical evidence of global warming.<br /><br />But, I digress-- we are talking about ethanol as a fuel to power internal combustion engines. A better plan is to use methanol, which can be produced by running a fuel cell in reverse, supplying it with carbon dioxide. If we use solar, wind and nuclear to provide the needed electricity, we not only stop pollution but remove the supposed global warming culprit from our atmosphere. Then, rather than using methanol as an internal combustion engine fuel, use it as a means to store and transport hydrogen for use in fuel cell powered vehicles.</comment>
		<comment id="11" responses="0">Corn = Food, not fuel. The rest of the world suffers greatly when we convert a cheap food stock to fuel... and crappy fuel at that.
<br />
<br />Hell, we suffer greatly.... the price of beef has gone through the roof since ethanol was mandated.</comment>
		<comment id="12" responses="1">"Corn baby corn" is costing us billions in debt. While "drill baby drill" won't add to the deficit.</comment>
		<comment id="13" responses="1">This relentless personal bashing of Al Gore only makes sense to me as part of the fossil fuel industries' disinformation campaign against human-caused global warming. For a politician (and I realize that's a serious hedging of what I'm about to say), Al Gore has been one of the most intelligent and far-sighted people on our national scene. He never claimed to "invent" the internet, but he played, as he said, a part in creating it by promoting it as a senator. He took up the problem of global warming long ago, a problem that 97 percent of the planet's leading climate experts agree exists. As for his financial interests, I don't think he's short of money, and it would be perverse for him not to invest in technologies that he believes will address the global warming crisis.</comment>
		<comment id="14" responses="0">Its an interesting turn of events when editor LaMonica chooses to include here Gore's mea culpa in regard to what has been a no-holds-barred, and "by any means necessary" endorsement of short-sighted, and often completely wrongheaded environmental policy. <br /><br />This one-sidedness occurs journalistically via the omission of articles with opposing opinions or outright questioning of todays "popular" environmental movement. Doing so is participation in emotion rather than more realistic, pragmatic approaches to the issues at hand. <br /><br />Kudos to Mr. LaMonica and his newly found openness.</comment>
		<comment id="15" responses="0">Why is it that scientists have concluded that man is causing global warming but meterologists can't get a daily weather forcast right? It is all a HOAX folks!!</comment>
		<comment id="16" responses="0">Well, lying to the public about fabricated "science" is generally a bad idea Gore.</comment>
	</comments>
	</post>
	<post id="http://news.cnet.com/8301-1001_3-20023660-92.html?part=rss&amp;subj=news&amp;tag=2547-1_3-0-20">
	<title>Analyst: 3.3 million RIM PlayBooks by Feb. 2012?</title>
	<body>



RIM&amp;#39;s PlayBook
(Credit:
RIM)

Research In Motion's PlayBook is garnering some enterprise and analyst attention as expectations steadily rise for the tablet.

Never mind that few folks have really played with the tablet, analysts have to model something for their spreadsheets and projections. Oppenheimer analyst Ittai Kidron was among the first to take a stab at estimating PlayBook sales.

In a nutshell, Kidron said: &amp;#149;&amp;nbsp;RIM will sell 100,000 PlayBook units in the fiscal fourth quarter ending February 28.
&amp;#149;&amp;nbsp;For fiscal 2012--a year from February--RIM will have sold 3.2 million units at an average selling price of $540.
&amp;#149;&amp;nbsp;Add it up and you'll have 3.3 million PlayBook units in the market. 
Read more of "RIM's PlayBook: 3.3 million units a smidge more than a year from now?" at ZDNet's Between the Lines.
</body>
	<comments>
		<comment id="0" responses="2">In other projections, Oppenheimer analysists predicted there will be an alien invasion of Teletubbies during Prince William's wedding on April 29, based on the same sources and guestimates used in predicting the Playbook's sales before it has been released into the wild. More to come once we have roused the analysists from his rum-swizzle brunch...</comment>
		<comment id="1" responses="5">I hope they do better than that if they expect to take on Apple, which is selling over 4 million iPads per quarter and is expected to do "as few" as 6 million this holiday quarter. I heard the Samsung is having lackluster sales. Competitors to the iPad have an uphill battle here. I'm starting to see it be more like iPod 2.0 instead of iPhone 2.0 in terms of what we might see in terms of market share.</comment>
		<comment id="2" responses="3">When will the softies release a tablet OS?
<br />I am holding out for a WP7 tablet.</comment>
		<comment id="3" responses="4">RIM can't make a quality device to save their a$$. They rely on phooey marketing to target older business people.</comment>
		<comment id="4" responses="0">It's official!!!! These analyst are on the take!!!</comment>
		<comment id="5" responses="1">Analysis on a non-existing product that has yet to be released. Of course, that never stops anyone from taking wild guesses, but that is all they are, wild guesses. Is this the same Oppenheimer of the Oppenheimer funds? Good luck with that wild guess....</comment>
		<comment id="6" responses="0">How long will it be before RIM teams up with Rupert Murdoch to start developing propaganda-spewing apps for their platform, like Apple is doing? This mistake on Apple's part might open the door to a competitor that just offers a platform and doesn't get involved in helping create controversial things. Anybody got a good Android tablet coming soon?<br /><br />This just in: sources say that I'll be selling 3 million invisible phones this spring, paid for with invisible money.</comment>
		<comment id="7" responses="0">Easy to make a WAG when there is no data to support your conclusion. Guys like this DO NOT belong in the industry.</comment>
	</comments>
	</post>
	<post id="http://news.cnet.com/2300-11386_3-10005675.html?part=rss&amp;subj=news&amp;tag=2547-1_3-0-20">
	<title>The Xbox 360 turns 5 (photos)</title>
	<comments>
	</comments>
	</post>
	<post id="http://news.cnet.com/8301-13772_3-20023645-52.html?part=rss&amp;subj=news&amp;tag=2547-1_3-0-20">
	<title>After 5 years, Xbox 360 still a big winner</title>
	<body>


On November 21, 2005, Norm Edwards became the first-ever person to buy an Xbox 360. It has now been five years since the launch of Microsoft&amp;#39;s video game console.
(Credit:
Daniel Terdiman/CNET)


If there's one thing that I recall more than any other from "Zero Hour," the 30-hour
Xbox 360 launch event on November 20 and 21, 2005, it was the sight of dozens of gamers literally passed out on beanbags, their controllers still in their hands.

Despite absolutely frigid conditions, more than 2,000 gamers showed up in Palmdale, an aerospace town about an hour northeast of Los Angeles, for the chance to be among the first ever to play and buy an Xbox 360.

And after those 30 hours, their patience was rewarded: a fleet of Best Buy trucks rolled into the giant hangar where the event was taking place, and the Xboxes flowed.


The Xbox 360 turns 5 (photos) 






Because my memories of that event are still so fresh, it's very hard for me to believe that it's been five full years since the launch of the Xbox 360--the release that heralded the first shot in the next-generation console wars among Microsoft, Sony, and Nintendo. The latter two companies would release their
PlayStation 3 and
Wii consoles a year later, in November 2006.

But back then, the PlayStation 2 was still the most dominant console on the planet, and no one had ever heard of the Wii. For its part, the Xbox 360 was an unknown--the original Xbox, released in 2001, had been a highly unprofitable loss leader, and now the world was waiting to find out if Microsoft was ready to be a real player in the console game. 
And did they succeed? By almost any measure, they did.

"Microsoft has come such a long way," said Dean Takahashi, the author of "The Xbox 360 Uncloaked," and like me, one of only three reporters there throughout the Zero Hour event. "In planning the Xbox 360, they expected to get maybe 20 million units sold in five years. In fact, they were able to do more than 40 million. This console generation has worked out far better than they thought."

By comparison, according to an article Takahashi wrote last month for VentureBeat, where he is a lead writer, Nintendo has moved 74.6 million units to date, while Sony has sold 38.9 million PS3s. 
Back then, in the fall of 2005, the question on everyone's mind was how the new Xbox would fare against Sony's PS3. After all, Sony had sold more than 100 million PS2s, and it was well understood that the PlayStation fan base gave Sony a huge advantage heading into the next-generation console wars.

But from the beginning, Sony stumbled, most visibly with supply chain issues that forced it to charge $600 for the PS3. And Microsoft, with its $400 Xbox 360, had no problem taking advantage of the PS3 fans who simply weren't willing to fork over $600.

Another area where Microsoft got an early lead was with its lineup of exclusive games. Indeed, the platform has helped spawn (or enhance) some of the biggest and most important exclusive titles in video game history--the Halo, Gears of War, and Fable franchises--and has seen titles available on multiple platforms tend to perform better on Xbox.

For their parts, the PS3 and the Wii have both had their share of blockbuster exclusives. PS3 players have had sole access to titles like the God of War and Gran Turismo franchises and those with Wiis were the only ones to be able to play New Super Mario Bros., Super Mario Galaxy, Wii Fit, and others.

Of course, back then, no one expected Nintendo's next-generation entry to be a real player. The thought was that it would be a battle for first place between the PS3 and the Xbox 360. Five years on, that seems like a quaint equation given the almost instant dominance of the Wii. Still, many people have long lumped the PS3 and the Xbox 360 together--given their high-quality graphics and immense processing power--and measured them more against each other and not against the Wii.

Impatient

If the new Sony and Microsoft console entrants were to be evaluated head-to-head, then Xbox has to be judged the winner, at least so far, despite its year head start. While the PS3 has had more success in the last year or so, the first few years of the console wars has seen the Xbox take a very big lead over Sony.

Now, with the release of its $150 Kinect motion controller, which sold more than 1 million units in its first 10 days, Microsoft is looking to solidify its position. Indeed, the company has said it now expects to sell 5 million Kinects this year alone. 
Sony, of course, also has released a new motion controller, the Move, but Takahashi said that Kinect is already winning that battle. And while everyone initially wanted to compare both Kinect and Move with Nintendo's Wii-mote controller, it's hard to equate the different controllers because the base systems are so different.

But in spite of that success, some might caution Microsoft to move slowly with Kinect--and with the rest of the Xbox platform. One of the biggest failures in the five years of the Xbox 360 is indisputably the so-called "Red Ring of Death," which caused the consoles to crash or even die. Microsoft had to pony up for a $1 billion warranty program to cover potentially faulty Xboxes, a program for which many gave the company props, but to Takahashi, the history of the Red Ring of Death illustrates an area where the company should proceed carefully.

"The Red Ring of Death exposed one of the weaknesses in the strategy of moving too fast," Takahashi said. "If Microsoft is guilty of anything, it is sometimes too impatient when it comes to getting business results."

Takahashi said that it's for that reason that Microsoft has failed to become a player in the massively multiplayer online games business, and that to date, it doesn't match up with others like Zynga or Apple in social games, smart phones, or portable music players. With that in mind, he said, sticking to the Xbox platform might well be wise.

Microsoft was not able to respond for comment for this story.

Still, it seems clear that the company has bided its time with the Xbox 360--waiting out consumers who fretted about the console's lack of integrated Wi-Fi, or its small hard drive. As Michael Pachter, a video games industry analyst with Wedbush Morgan Securities put it, the Xbox 360 has "remarkable staying power" and "didn't get made obsolete after five years."

Indeed, Pachter said that the future of the Xbox franchise looks strong, precisely because of the Kinect. "They did a phenomenal job with Kinect," Pachter said, and "got people excited about it...That's the most exciting thing going on now."

Elite and Slim

In the past, it's been seen as a truism that each new console generation lasted about five years. And by that measure, it would be time for Microsoft to come out with an all-new Xbox.

Of course, no one expects that to happen any time soon, and the same is true of both Sony and Nintnedo.

But both Microsoft and Sony have found ways to come out with new iterations of their consoles--new versions that address things like missing accessories or too-high prices--along the way. In 2007, Microsoft released the Xbox 360 Elite, which offered a 120GB hard drive--up from 20 GB on the original--as well as an HDMI (High Definition Multimedia Interface) port, an HDMI cable and a wireless remote. This year, it went even further, bringing out the Xbox 360 Slim, which offers a 250GB hard drive. Yet the price has dropped over time to $300.

Takahashi said he originally thought that the PS3 would surpass the Xbox 360 in graphics quality and that gamers would respond by buying more PS3s. "But that advantage hasn't turned out to yield any benefits for Sony," he said. "If Sony has gained ground, it is because Microsoft wasn't ambitious enough in designing a slimmer version of its console." 
Similarly, Microsoft is dominating its rivals in online services. Its Xbox Live service currently has 25 million members, and Pachter said 17 million of those are Gold members who pay $60 a year to take part in sophisticated multiplayer gaming and access a wide variety of social and multimedia content like Netflix streaming, A-list movies and TV shows, Twitter and Facebook, and more. And to Pachter, there must be something of value there because, he said, he heard very few complaints when Microsoft raised the annual price of membership from $50 to $60.

But Takahashi said that Kinect may well be Microsoft's best hedging against having to come out with an entirely new generation of console, something that may well not happen for at least two or three more years. "Kinect has certainly given [the Xbox 360] a mid-life kicker," Takahashi said. "I wasn't expecting that to happen and really thought that the company would have had to introduce a brand-new console by now."

For his part, Pachter doesn't think that's likely to be necessary for at least a couple more years. 
Yet Pachter also wonders how Microsoft, Sony, and Nintendo have managed to keep the prices for their consoles so high, what with well-equipped Xboxes and PS3s still coming in at $300 each, and the Wii still selling for $200. 
"If you'd told me in 2005 that (for the holiday season in) 2010, the three consoles would be $300 (for the core Xbox 360 Slim), $300 (for the core PlayStation 3) and $200 (for the Wii)," said Pachter, "I would have told you (that) you were on drugs. There's no way."
 </body>
	<comments>
		<comment id="0" responses="2">The Xbox is popular, that's certainly true. But is it really profitable for MSFT? What percentage of MSFT's profit does the Xbox represent? What are the margins for the Xbox?</comment>
		<comment id="1" responses="0">The Kinect is amazing, I'd keep mine for the sole purpose of video chat whioch works great. Also interesting I have bought more games since Kinect came out than I have since I got my first Xbox in 2005.</comment>
		<comment id="2" responses="0">The Kinect will be a huge hit for Microsoft. Good for them! That will help them to sell more xboxes...</comment>
		<comment id="3" responses="1">My in-laws wanted to get my kids a Wii. My wife told them to get the Kinect, now I have to share my Xbox. :(</comment>
		<comment id="4" responses="1">by kkehoe5 November 23, 2010 5:46 AM PST <br />My in-laws wanted to get my kids a Wii. My wife told them to get the Kinect, now I have to share my Xbox. :(
<br />
<br />LoL, buy a new slim and give your old 360 to them.</comment>
		<comment id="5" responses="2">PS3 is the iPhone of gaming, yeah it looks good, but long term, it doesn't hold up.</comment>
		<comment id="6" responses="0">Seems to me the winners in this are gamers. We get better and better games, and the consoles get cheaper. As for me, I have two of each of the 3 and we definitely use the PS3 the most, both for games and multi-media. The blu-ray alone makes it our favorite console, add in the better version of Netflix (much better version in my opinion), and it wins easy for us (notice I said for us, I can clearly see why for others it would be the 360). We also plan on getting a 3D TV, it should be fun to see how that works out with the PS3 for movies and games.
<br />
<br />As for the 360, I love using the Windows Media Center tied into my PC. I have a quad tuner so my 360 can be used as a DVR. May dumpy the Tivo and go exclusively with the 360 / PC combo using WMC. Geez, this generation of consoles has been great, hasn't it?
<br />
<br />I find it odd that the article says MS wins because they sold a tad more than Sony yet the PS3 came out a year later. Oh well, we like them all, and this Christmas will be great for the kids. Great deals daily at Amazon, Newegg, and other sites have me stockpiling games.
<br />
<br />I imagine it will be at least 2 years before the next gens come out, and that's fine by us. It stretches the dollar out more.</comment>
		<comment id="7" responses="5">Sony's Move has better accuracy, not as susceptible to lighting conditions, and modal control capabilities through their lighted balls (gee that sounds funny!) that Kinect lacks.</comment>
		<comment id="8" responses="5">i thought the xbox sold more because it also had a higher failure rate. So people got jipped out of an xbox and were dumb enough to buy a second one when MSFT refused to honor the warranty.<br /><br />It wasn't until later in the ring of death controversy that Microsoft conceded and extended the warranty but folx still had to pony up the cost - so they bought new ones anyway.</comment>
		<comment id="9" responses="4">The title should read: xbox 360 still a big winner only in the US. That would be a more honest title. Outside the US, the xbox 360 is not a winner, in fact, is a looser. So is obvious that an american console will have good success on the united states like it is obvious that a Japanese console will have the best success in Japan. There are 3 important markets consoles have to win over to proclaim to be the best console of a generation. Nintendo have made it and Sony too but xbox has never won over the 3 markets at the same time, US, Europe and Japan. Actually, right now, the PS3 have a better position than the xbox on 2 markets, Japan and Europe. So, when talking about xbox 360 success it is important to remember and note that the success is only on the US market, not in the whole market like Nintendo and Sony has dominated before.</comment>
		<comment id="10" responses="1">I think the XBox 360 did well and probably exceeded MS expectations. I still have not been impressed and I laugh when I hear from my students that they are on their third or fourth 360 because of failures. I have never heard that from any of my PS3 students and my PS3 is used for so much more than games (although that is why I enjoy it). The price point was an issue. I got my PS3 when Dell offered a one day sale for 299 months before it officially went down to 299. Overall, I think both systems have their pros and cons, but I know which one I prefer.</comment>
		<comment id="11" responses="0">How many of them still work after 5 years? My guess is less than 50%.</comment>
		<comment id="12" responses="8">As a die-hard PC gamer, it won't ever stop amusing me to watch people pay for gimped, shoe-horned-into-too-small-of-a-form-factor, no real amount of RAM possessing, locked down with DRM computers aka consoles. But I suppose they work for the (disturbing) amount of people that STILL couldn't put a simple tower PC together even with a "How To" in front of them, or for people with less than stellar incomes unable to buy real rigs. 1080p? I was playing at 1920x1200 (using a superior 16:10 aspect ratio to boot!) when people were talking about 720p and 1080p coming out.</comment>
		<comment id="13" responses="1">Big winner, how about big loser. Microsoft has let me down twice already as I am currently on my 3rd XBOX system. We can put a man on the moon but we can't keep my easy bake 360 from roasting itself.</comment>
		<comment id="14" responses="4">This article is entirely undermined by the fact that it calls the Kinect a success. That thing is a huge failure, no matter how the sales numbers are spun.</comment>
		<comment id="15" responses="3">I don't actually think xbox360 has been that successful when compared to the original xbox. The original launched in 2001 and support was dropped in 2005 with the release of 360. In those 4 yrs Microsoft sold 24 million xbox's. Thats 8 million/yr, if we extend that to 5 years that equals 32 million. The xbox360 in 5 yrs is at 40+ million according to this article.. Now if you add up rebought systems from the high failure rate (if you deny people rebought systems you are just delusional), rebought systems from mass bannings (last yr in Nov. MS banned over a million plus users) and rebuys from upgrading to a xbox360 slim to get away from RROD then xbox360 is barely selling better than the original xbox.</comment>
		<comment id="16" responses="2">Sony thought the PS3 would sell well based on the integrated blu-ray player. What Sony didn't predict is that people would still buy DVD in such volume still in 2010 and that movie on-demand rentals would eat into demand. Blu-ray discs high prices didn't help drive adoption either.</comment>
		<comment id="17" responses="1">"If the new Sony and Microsoft console entrants were to be evaluated head-to-head, then Xbox has to be judged the winner, at least so far, despite its year head start. While the PS3 has had more success in the last year or so, the first few years of the console wars has seen the Xbox take a very big lead over Sony."
<br />
<br />Do they make cnet blogger's fact check this BS? Your own articles puts the PS3 at 38.9 million sold vs 40 million for the Xbox 360 and yet the Xbox 360 has been out a full year longer. <br />
<br />If you went to say vgchartz.com you would see that in the fist 4 years of each console the PS3 sold more year for year than the 360. This means at some point the PS3 is going to push the 360 into 3rd place, even though the 360 has had a full year of sales time over the PS3.
<br />
<br />I have both, and think both are great, and the Wii is a great dust collector in many homes.</comment>
		<comment id="18" responses="2">Giant enemy crab!</comment>
		<comment id="19" responses="0">Interesting article that reminds us the early console game war, with PS2 and Xbox original.
<br />I remember all the experts back then claiming Microsoft have no chance, the war is over, Microsoft is too late to the game, blah, blah ....
<br />
<br />And then I realized I read similar articles only few weeks&amp;#38; days ago about the Microsoft phone.
<br />
<br />I won one of those phones (the Focus) and the more I play with it , the more I love it. Its a different type of phone just like the 360 was different type of console back then (Live). <br />
<br />Some will love it, some will not and some will hate it because its labeled "Microsoft" - just the same way the next console generation war started. <br />Its a good reminder on how patience and $$ Microsoft have when they decide to go "all in" to a certain market.</comment>
		<comment id="20" responses="0">Ring of Death:<br />1st- At least Microsoft fixed it free of charge including shipping the box ready to mail to your house. 2nd- Those xboxs have been gone for quite some time now. 3rd- Granted its subjective my friend has had 3 PS3 replacements due to HD failures losing all game saves. Just do a search on them they are all over the net. While it may not be as high Sony isn't willing to pony up and fix their problems. <br />Small difference in Console sales:<br />1st- Xbox has the highest attach rate (# of games sold per console) out of all of the consoles. 2nd- They consistently sell the most multi-platform games. 3rd-The current console games sales worldwide are: Xbox360-429.31 Million, PS3-293.11 Million, and Wii-547.82 Million. The top 30 games sales for last week are: Xbox-6.83 Million, PS3-4.00 Million, and Wii-1.62 Million. If anything Wii has a disadvantage on last weeks chart as the top selling game by a wide margin was only on Xbox &amp;#38; PS3. The last several weeks if anything look worse for PS3 and Wii as Xbox recently released two huge first party games (Halo Reach &amp;#38; Fable). Just by the numbers Wii has won the most battles but Xbox is winning the war. <br />Wii motion sensor VS PS3 Move VS Kinect:<br />Wii released an upgrade to there motion sensor not very long ago everyone knows what it does. PS3 is very accurate but can only see one or two (using two wands) points. Kinect tracks 48 points of movement and has a small delay depending on the game. The most important difference besides the obvious is that Kinect is software driven. The problem being that it taxes the system, the MAJOR advantage is that it can only get better as the software gets better. The Move, and wii motion controller are already at their peak performance. If MS wanted to it could easily replicate the glow wand by packaging a cheap led controller with the game that the kinect could track.</comment>
		<comment id="21" responses="0">awesome article!!</comment>
	</comments>
	</post>
	<post id="http://news.cnet.com/8301-31921_3-20023653-281.html?part=rss&amp;subj=news&amp;tag=2547-1_3-0-20">
	<title>Viral 'pornoscan' protest challenges TSA</title>
	<body>

A grassroots effort that began with a single Web page exhorting air travelers to decline body scans has become a full-fledged Internet sensation that has the uncommon distinction of officially irking the Transportation Security Administration.


The idea behind National Opt-Out Day is simple: on the day before Thanksgiving, when screening lines stretch so far they seem to snake back on themselves like an ouroboros, Americans should opt out of what critics call "pornoscans." Instead, they should choose a police-style pat-down instead, which will take TSA screeners far longer to complete.


TSA head John Pistole initially called the idea "irresponsible" in a statement last week. At a breakfast meeting with reporters yesterday, he moderated his criticisms and warned there was the "potential" for slowdowns if the opt-out protest is widespread.



This image of an adult man was taken using a Rapiscan Secure 1000
backscatter X-ray scanner
(Credit:
John Wild (johnwild.info))


It may be. Few federal agencies have found themselves the subject of so much public obloquy in such a short time. TSA screeners have been mocked by the cast of Saturday Night Live, lampooned in verse by Grammy-winning musician Steve Vaus, and parodied in a cartoon video. Rush Limbaugh offered this memorable call to arms: "Keep your hands off my tea bag, Mr. President."


Members of Congress are pushing back against TSA's new procedures, and White House press secretary Robert Gibbs was forced yesterday to say that TSA was not being inconsistent in its public statements. An ABC News poll found increasing public opposition to full body X-ray scanners. Last week's viral video featured John "Don't Touch My Junk" Tyner; this week's showed a young boy being screened with his shirt removed. (That video garnered more than 1.1 million views on YouTube and a response by TSA saying that "no complaints were filed" as a result of the incident.)


National Opt-Out Day began quietly enough, with a one-page Web site created by Brian Sodergren of Ashburn, Va. Then it began to rocket around Twitter and the loose confederation of anti-body screening Web sites including DontScan.us, StopDigitalStripSearches.org, and WeWontFly.com. The phrase returns over half a million hits on Google.


James Babb, who with George Donnelly co-founded the We Won't Fly grassroots group that's promoting the opt-out concept, says he's "just a regular dad" who began organizing locally a month ago after he learned the full-body scanners were coming to the nearby Philadelphia airport.


Their online effort was an instant hit. "By the third day of our Web site, we had to get a new server because it almost melted," Babb told CNET yesterday. "It totally went viral."


In a pre-Internet era, TSA could have weathered these criticisms, which would probably never have coalesced into a date and a strategy for what might be called strict civil obedience. But as the Thanksgiving travel season draws near, the reaction to TSA's new procedures has been visceral and sharply critical, aided by cell phone recordings of security line incidents, privacy and health concerns, and Web sites including the Drudge Report, which published a photograph of a hands-on examination of a nun with the caption: "THE TERRORISTS HAVE WON." (See CNET's earlier coverage.)


"If enough people (opt-out), the theory is that it'll bog down their bogus security theater," Babb says. "We don't think they have the manpower to put their hands in everyone's pants...The American people aren't going to do it. They're not going to be irradiated and they're not going to have their kids felt up."



TSA chief John Pistole tells U.S. Senate last week he wants &amp;#34;partnership&amp;#34; with flying public irked about full-body scans.
(Credit:
U.S. Senate)


That, simply put, is the difficult choice that millions of air travelers will face over the next month or so during the busy holiday season.


Not all U.S. airports have the whole-body scanners. Thanks to the federal stimulus legislation, however, TSA has been able to buy nearly 400 of the units and install them in approximately 70 airports around the country. Congress has given the TSA enough money to install 100 more machines by the end of this year, and the total is set to reach 1,000 by the end of 2011.


For its part, the TSA has continued to defend its new procedures, which offer air travelers a choice of either full-body scans or what the TSA delicately calls "enhanced patdowns." Pistole said in a statement this week that: "This has always been viewed as an evolving program that will be adapted as conditions warrant, and we greatly appreciate the cooperation and understanding of the American people." TSA also said that no changes were planned.


TSA says that approximately 34 million passengers have traveled by air since the new procedures began in late October and that less than 3 percent of travelers received the more stringent physical search that can include genital touching. If those numbers are correct, that means that about a million travelers were subjected to those procedures.


On MSNBC yesterday, Pistole said: "We are facing a determined enemy who has proven adept at building, concealing, designing bombs that are going to kill hundreds of people on one aircraft. And then they've also done the same on cargo aircraft to affect our economy." 
Pistole is not alone in warning that a pat-down, ah, slowdown isn't exactly desirable. Kent Scheidegger, legal director of the Criminal Justice Legal Foundation, calls it a "cruel way to protest for a valid cause." And the American Society of Travel Agents has said even a small number of opt-outs could cause huge delays.


Edward Hasbrouck, an author and consumer travel advocate who lives in San Francisco, says the TSA "has finally crossed the line of public tolerances for their outrages."


But, Hasbrouck adds: "That's merely a symptom of the problem that since day one, the TSA has taken the position that they should be outside the rule of law. They believe they should not be liable if they commit sexual assault." (He predicts lawsuits or prosecutions, especially in places like the San Francisco airport, where the local district attorney has promised to indict overly touchy screeners.)


"It's kind of neat to see America rising up for a change and asserting their rights as individuals, saying 'We're not slaves. You don't own us,'" says Babb, one of the opt-out day campaigners. "It's long overdue."


</body>
	<comments>
		<comment id="0" responses="3">Will the DHS put me on the Do Not Fly List if I comment on this article? Will the TSA $14 an hour, "friskers" neglect to do their duty if they aren't allowed to cop cheap feels?</comment>
		<comment id="1" responses="2">I really don't mind the scanners. <br />
<br />What pissed the F$!@ out of me, was when I got a extreme pat down on top of my scan. I was wearing normal cargo pants from Old Navy... And then after the scan the "pat down" which at least I was told up front... "I'm going be patting you on your legs all the way up to your torso"... yeah so basically I'm giong be patting down your junk. Which is pretty much exactly what happened. <br />
<br />I'm good with scanners, and was hoping that by doing that I would have escaped the patting of my junk by a TSA dude.
<br />
<br />So now I'm completely anti-scanners if they're goig to just pick people to do this to anyways... it should be one or the other. If there was something in my pockets (whihc I checked several times and there wasn't nor was there any that the tsa dude found), then I would have been more than happy to get rescanned).</comment>
		<comment id="2" responses="4">It's time to work together to put a stop to this madness. If our country is reduced to strip searching children and the elderly in the name of some illusion of safety, the terrorists have already won. Say "no", opt out of the scanner and go through the fondling line.....</comment>
		<comment id="3" responses="0">Revolution !</comment>
		<comment id="4" responses="7">I think TSA should provide special lines for those unwilling to be scanned. That way those of us without puritannical hangups wouldn't be burdened by the actions of these idiots.</comment>
		<comment id="5" responses="1">The TSA are the terrorists and we're the innocent public.</comment>
		<comment id="6" responses="1">So much for hope and change. I hope I don't get felt up, because I don't want to change my travel plans for Christmas, how's that?</comment>
		<comment id="7" responses="2">The main problem is the TSA is too reactionary. Some idiot tries a shoe bomb so they make use take off our shoes. Some idiot tries a crotch bomb, so they want to feel our crotches. Why don?t they take a holistic approach to security like every other country and rely on intelligence gathering, profiling, and technology. If Israel does not perform enhanced interrogation techniques, I mean pat-downs, why should the US have to resort to that type of tactic? <br />
<br />The TSA was established too quickly with personnel who do not have the capability to do their job, much less stay ahead of the terrorist. This federal quagmire should be disbanded, and a new agency formed that can hire people who can at least think instead of react.</comment>
		<comment id="8" responses="0">People we all should remember that we are the government and collectively the power to end all of this nonsense rests with us.</comment>
		<comment id="9" responses="0">why it wasn't a woman picture that was shown huh?</comment>
		<comment id="10" responses="1">The benefits of working for TSA are getting better and better! They don't even need to go to a strip club after work, and they don't have to pay to touch! I'm thinking about a career change...</comment>
		<comment id="11" responses="0">Declan, kudos on the use of 'obloquy' and 'ouroboros' in the space of two paragraphs.</comment>
		<comment id="12" responses="0">The better link to the TSA song/video by Steve Vaus (aka Buck Howdy) is here http://tinyurl.com/TSAtv</comment>
		<comment id="13" responses="1">I work for the TSA. And the truth is, I do enjoy this power that we have.<br />I am a little bit anti-social and awkward, and I've had the opportunity to intimately touch people that would NEVER even speak to me in public.<br />I enjoy touching your children...<br />You're probably thinking that I'm not really with the TSA, and just thought I'd make some attention-grabbing post on here.<br /><br />I'm sorry, but this it the truth. See you tomorrow...</comment>
		<comment id="14" responses="4">We're OK with 40,000 Americans dieing on our highways annually, we should be OK with a couple of airplanes a year getting blown out of the sky. Seriously. Flying is ten times safer than driving. I'm OK with it being five times safer in exchange for not living in a jack-boot police state.</comment>
		<comment id="15" responses="0">They tell us this is all necessary due to the underwear bomber, but remember that the bomber's own father called the U.S. embassy to warn that he'd be training with terrorists in Yemen. If some Fed had done his/her job, Abdulmutallab never would have made it on the plane.</comment>
		<comment id="16" responses="0">When business travelers start pushing back on their company executives about flying around the country, or world, because of how these entire mess, it will adversely effect how business is conducted in the US. That will effect the bottom line and taxes that the government gets from any profits those companies make. The only thing sacred the US government holds anymore is money. Once it effects their money, they will have a change of heart. Until that day, buy a comfortable car with good gas mileage. You're going to need it.</comment>
		<comment id="17" responses="0">I think a minor change to the design of the body scanner would make a lot of people more comfortable going through it.<br /><br />It would elongate everyone's junk a couple of inches. Everyone is happy.</comment>
		<comment id="18" responses="3">We aren't your slaves, we're not willing to let you sexually violate the bodies of over 300 million innocent men, women, and children in exchange for virtually no assurance of a possible chance to catch 3 potential terrorists every 10 years!!!<br /><br />Events like 911 will never ever happen again. The moment a terrorist stands up on the plane he will get plummeted and beaten to a bloody pulp because we all know right where plane hijacks are headed. The harm of the few passengers to protect the freedom of 300 million is a risk we are willing to take!!! Terrorists know passengers will kill them the moment they try to take over the plane, so they won't even try another attack, why bother? The government is doing a great job of attacking our freedoms on their own. The terrorists have now taken over our own government.<br /><br />"We are facing a determined enemy who has proven adept at building, concealing, designing bombs that are going to kill hundreds of people on one aircraft. And then they've also done the same on cargo aircraft to affect our economy."</comment>
		<comment id="19" responses="3">Folks, stop whining. If you don't like it, don't fly and take a train or drive. You have a choice you know.</comment>
		<comment id="20" responses="0">Ultimately, there is no security only prevention.</comment>
		<comment id="21" responses="1">And no one is talking about the radiation that the government says is perfectly safe. Do you believe that?! ANY radiation is dangerous! Don't give me that line "it's safe". Radiation is cumulative throughout your lifetime. You're already going up in a plane that will expose you to more radiation than staying on the ground, so why take an additional shot before you get on the plane? How do you know that you won't get cancer from this one teensy bit of irradiation? You don't. Maybe this is the xray that puts a kink in one piece of DNA that kills you.<br /><br />Why do we trust the government when they say it's safe?! Some dork getting paid off by the companies that make the equipment says he looked at it for two days and it looked fine to him?<br /><br />Stop being lemmings and lab rats, people! Demand your rights! No crotch grabbing unless there is a clear threat or reason to do so. Take a hint from Israel... TALK to each and every traveller. Profile Profile Profile! The nun isn't going to blow the plane up... it's more likely the Middle Eastern male between the ages of 16-35 is! The little boy with his father isn't carrying a bomb! The guy in the turban holding the Koran is more likely to be willing to blow up the plane than the great grandmother in the wheel chair! This is not bigoted or prejudice...it's statistics!<br /><br />Get real America! Stop letting them pray on your fears so that they can do what they want! McCarthyism is on it's way back!</comment>
		<comment id="22" responses="0">Last time I checked flying on a commercial airline was a voluntary act. If you do not like security screening just don't fly, don't go to the airport. Instead go to the train or bus station. Simple as that. <br /><br />As for all the indignant "Tom Payne" wannabes out there trying to fan the flames of civil unrest on this matter, I can only relate what Jame Madison once wrote about another ill advised "patriot" rebellion - "Liberty may be endangered by the abuses of liberty as well as the abuses of power."<br /><br />Declan - your journalisn or your editiors, needs some polishing, as has been noted already. You have not really presented "the facts" in a unbiased manner here. Reporting partial facts may make you a good "Yellow Journalist" but I am not sure if that is what this venue is looking for. Thanks</comment>
		<comment id="23" responses="1">Umm, creating a snarl is exactly what this event is meant to do. It is called civil disobedience. It is meant to force the government to think about its policies since nothing else seems to work. Remember when we all cringed at the idea of our airports being as strict as Israeli airports? Now they look at -us- that way. We've gone overboard. <br /><br />My form of "disobedience" is simple: even though in the past I've been a frequent personal and business flyer I now fly almost none at all. I've voted with my car and credit card. However if I had to fly tomorrow ... heck yeah I would opt out as part of voicing my disgust at how this whole thing has been going.</comment>
		<comment id="24" responses="1">How about if the TSA sets up a special pat down booth and the President, his wife, children, and every member of congress with their families be required to go through the exact same screening on live TV to set an example for the American public. I mean if it is OK for us then they should all be willing to undergo the process.<br /><br />But then our government has a real history of feeling they are exempt from the laws and regulations they spew out.</comment>
		<comment id="25" responses="0">One, TSA isn't capable of giving us an unbiased evaluation of the efficacity of their security methods. They are paid to come up with as many intrustive search measures as possible.
<br />
<br />Two, it's irrelevant how hard we make their job. THEY are the bottleneck, not the passengers refusing to be groped or irradiated.
<br />
<br />Three, legally, you can petition the airline to allow you on the plane without a search or scan. TSA does not have the legal authority to stop you from asking them. If they say no, and you refuse the search or the scan; unless they have credible reason to beleive you have committed a crime, they can not legally prevent you from leaving
<br />
<br />I work in the medical field. The numbers of people injured, maimed, crippled, or killed by malfunctioning medical x-ray machines is staggering. But those numbers are miniscule compared to the number of people that will be injured, maimed, crippled, or killed by malfunctioning airport x-ray scanners.</comment>
		<comment id="26" responses="0">*WRONG* I still have my job and I'm still scheduled to work tomorrow.<br />I guess it's true that you shouldn't blame the TSA, but the management instead.<br />Even with these new invasive, enhanced patdowns I exercise my right to common sense. Someone as old as my grandmother is probably not a terrorist. Someone with a baby is probably not a threat.<br />A six year old does not constitute a security threat and I will only pat down if my supervisor is standing by me. It really is getting kind of silly.<br /><br />I was serious about what I said earlier though...about the children.<br /><br />anyway, we've been getting special training and memorandums on how to handle the 'civil disobedience' planned for Wed. So long as the traveling public remains polite and understanding we shouldn't have any problems. It's funny, everybody on here is trash-talking the TSA. You guys are pretty mean, but you're not far off.</comment>
		<comment id="27" responses="0">Earlier there was a comment about someone that went threw the scanner and then was patted down. Are your sure that the screener didn't see something he just couldn't resist touching?</comment>
		<comment id="28" responses="0">Anyone that posts in support of these measures, really, you need to leave our country now, This is not your country - it stopped being your country when you stopped understanding what this country is all about. China, North Korea, Cuba, there's plenty of places where you'll fit in much better than here. Get your passport, book your flight, get your testicle rub, and get out. And don't come back.</comment>
		<comment id="29" responses="0">Look at the bright side. The government may have found opportunity for gainful employment for all those sexual predators, and the Church may have a new home for their wayward priests. Just be happy no one has tried to blow up a plane with something stuck up their butt.</comment>
	</comments>
	</post>
	<post id="http://news.cnet.com/8301-11128_3-20023551-54.html?part=rss&amp;subj=news&amp;tag=2547-1_3-0-20">
	<title>People Power rides 'Internet of things' to smart grid</title>
	<body>

The best path to energy-efficient electronics is connecting them to the Internet, according to People Power.

The Silicon Valley-based company today launched a system that uses embedded networking chips and Internet software, called the Energy Services Platform, to monitor and control plugged-in devices for better efficiency. It says it's working with some business partners and expects its products to be available in the first quarter of next year.




People Power is targeting manufacturers with its networking chip which can be embedded in electronic devices for remote control and monitoring.
(Credit:
People Power)


There are dozens of companies seeking to reduce waste in electronics with energy monitoring and control technologies, with many developing home energy management systems made available through utilities.

People Power, by contrast, is targeting electronics manufacturers, such as Japanese office equipment and appliance manufacturers. It has developed an embeddable networking module that will connect equipment, such as TVs and copy machines, to the Internet over a wireless network. Once connected, electronics can be monitored for power consumption and controlled to improve efficiency. 
A person could, for example, view how much electricity different plugged-in devices use, turn them on and off from a smartphone, and schedule when to turn them off. From the cloud-based energy management service, People Power can compare one home's energy usage to neighbors and provide recommendations to optimize power, said Gene Wang, the CEO and co-founder.

The company intends to make money by licensing its wireless module and providing data services, such as energy monitoring, from its hosted software. 
"We are licensing to manufacturers so we can really go mainstream," said Wang, who previously worked at Bitfone, which developed software for businesses to manage cell phones using the cell phone network. "This is best done by piggybacking manufacturers that are already there."

The company developed the wireless module, which is built around software called Open Source IPv6 Automation Network (OSIAN) that uses a communications protocol which is low-power like Zigbee but has longer range than Wi-Fi, explained Wang. The radios in the module will work with other wireless protocols, including Wi-Fi and Zigbee.

People Power said that it is partnering with other companies around its automation system, including Ricoh, although no third parties have announced plans to use the technology in products. 
In addition to giving end users more data on energy usage and remote control, the Energy Services Platform can give electronics manufacturers a better way to demonstrate improvements in efficiency, Wang said.

</body>
	<comments>
		<comment id="0" responses="1">I'm confused as to what some of the terminology actually means. For instance, <br /><br />"Once connected, electronics can be monitored for power consumption and controlled to improve efficiency"<br /><br />Just what does "controlled" mean in this case. For example, if I'm off from work one day in the middle of the week and decided to watch a movie, I may or may not be able to if the powers to be decided I'm using too much energy? If I need to iron a shirt for a customer visit at work, I need to check with the controllers first and make sure it's OK to turn on the iron? I can iron my shirt or I can watch a movie, but not both?</comment>
	</comments>
	</post>
	<post id="http://news.cnet.com/8301-13924_3-20023646-64.html?part=rss&amp;subj=news&amp;tag=2547-1_3-0-20">
	<title>Report: Samsung sells 600K Galaxy Tabs</title>
	<body>
Samsung Electronics said Sunday it had sold more than 600,000 Galaxy Tab tablets worldwide in the first month of sales, according to a report in the Korea Herald. 


The Samsung Galaxy Tab is the first major Android tablet to compete with the iPad.
(Credit:
Samsung)

The 7-inch tablet was released about a month ago and is now available in United States, Japan, South Korea, and Italy, among other countries. In South Korea, about 30,000 units have been sold through SK Telecom since November 14 when it was launched there, the newspaper said. 
The Galaxy Tab has gotten a lot of attention because it's seen as the first major Android-based rival to
Apple's iPad. 
It is currently offered with Google's Android 2.2 ("Froyo") and packs a 1GHz Samsung processor with Imagination's latest and greatest PowerVR SGX540 graphics technology. Apple's iPad, by comparison, is believed to use an older PowerVR SGX535 graphics processor with the Apple A4 processor. Like the Galaxy Tab, Apple's A4 chip runs at 1GHz. 
The Galaxy Tab also has front and rear cameras and supports Adobe Flash Player 10.1, two features completely absent on the iPad. 
Apple sold one million Wi-Fi-only iPads in the first month of sales in the U.S. (The Galaxy Tab is available with 3G.) And, to date, has sold more than 7 million iPads worldwide. Samsung is targeting 1 million Galaxy Tabs by the end of the year, according to the Korea Herald. 
</body>
	<comments>
		<comment id="0" responses="2">Great for Samsung. Seems like a very good device. <br />I must admit I still don't see what is so special about tablets, but I guess people find it useful.</comment>
		<comment id="1" responses="2">Umm, those are sales through distribution channels, not in the hands of actual consumers. Samsung is also reducing production of the Galaxy due to the fact sales to actual consumers is slow.</comment>
		<comment id="2" responses="2">Me thinks thou doth protest too much. Perchance doth thou sup upon thine apple koolaid?</comment>
		<comment id="3" responses="10">but it cost more, is smaller and uses pressure touch, how is it in the same class as the iPad?</comment>
		<comment id="4" responses="1">It's like comparing a laptop to a mac. 2 totally different animals. I have an apple itouch and the galaxy tab - both great bits of kit. Bit more freedom and function with the galaxy. 2 glaring oopsies with the ipad - no camera and no wifi sync with iTunes. I can sync iTunes to the galaxy tab. As they say "there's an app for that".</comment>
		<comment id="5" responses="6">The Galaxy has gone on sale for less than two weeks now, do not have a full months worth of numbers. Just as Android phones outsell iPhone, soon Android tablets will outsell iPad.</comment>
		<comment id="6" responses="5">Half the screen size, another iPad knockoff. Apple leads, others follow badly.</comment>
		<comment id="7" responses="1">How can u compare the sales of android phones to the iphone? android os is on how many phones out there compared to 1 phone by apple? Of course multiple android phones will outsell 1 phone.</comment>
		<comment id="8" responses="1">If Samsung did a $399 or even a $450 Wi Fi only 8G storage with exandable memory this becomes the hottest gift along side the Kinnect this Christmas. Instead they crippled their own sales with too high of a price.
<br />
<br />It's a shame played around with one, love the size , form factor etc.</comment>
		<comment id="9" responses="0">I say good for samsung/andriod on the tabs. For everyone knocking on the tab, shhhhhhs it's release will only help everyone in the end. Without competition how much do you think the Ipad 2.0 is gonna cost? not that it matters to me but I'm sure they will make it cheaper if they see people have a few other options. You gotta look at the bigger picture.</comment>
		<comment id="10" responses="0">Hmmmm--rather than intelligently discuss the merits (or lack thereof) of similar devices, these comments degenerate into a bunch of fanboy bullcrap.<br /><br />Memo to CNET. Set up two comment sections for any article that may mention any Apple product. Label one "Serious Comments" and the other "Inane Apple Fanboy And Apple Hater Comments."</comment>
		<comment id="11" responses="0">@HamLoring I agree. I may be an Apple fanboy (certified by Apple as a Mac Technician), but I prefer to stay out of the back-and-forthing that goes on in comment threads like this. If I could just read the comments that mattered, I'd be happy!<br /><br />On that note, I'd like to question the accuracy of a statement in the article:<br /><br />"Apple sold one million Wi-Fi-only iPads in the first month of sales in the U.S. (The Galaxy Tab is available with 3G.)"<br /><br />I'm sorry, but to me that made it sound like the iPad doesn't have 3G. It does. The 3G model may have not been available during that first month, but the iPad IS ALSO "available with 3G".<br /><br />If the article was worded something like "During it's first month of sales, the iPad sold one million units, and was initially only available with Wi-Fi in the U.S., to be joined later by 3G models (The Galaxy Tab was immediately available with 3G.)", then it would have made more sense.</comment>
	</comments>
	</post>
	<post id="http://news.cnet.com/8301-19413_3-20023507-240.html?part=rss&amp;subj=news&amp;tag=2547-1_3-0-20">
	<title>Cloud security is dependent on the law</title>
	<body>
I am a true believer in the disruptive value of cloud computing, especially the long term drive towards so-called "public cloud" services. As I've noted frequently of late, the economics are just too compelling, and the issues around security and the law will eventually be addressed.


(Credit:

Flickr/Brian Turner)

However, lately there has been some interesting claims of the superiority of public clouds over privately managed forms of IT, including private cloud environments. The latest is a statement from Gartner analyst Andrew Walls, pointing out that enterprises simply assume self-managed computing environments are more secure than shared public services:
"When you go to the private cloud they start thinking, 'this is just my standard old data centre, I just have the standard operational issues, there's been no real change in what we do', and this is a big problem because what this tells us is the data centre managers are not looking at the actual impact on the security program that the virtualisation induces."
"They see public cloud as being a little bit more risky therefore they won't go with it. Now the reality is, from my own experience in talking to security organisations and data centre managers around the world is that in many of these cases, you're far safer in the public cloud than you are on your own equipment."
So, Walls seems to be saying that many (most?) IT organizations don't understand how virtualization changes "security," much less cloud, and therefore those organizations would be better off putting their infrastructure in the hands of a public cloud provider. That, to me, is a generalization so broad it's likely useless. There are way too many variables in the equation to make a blanket statement for the applications at any one company, much less for an entire industry.
In fact, regardless of the technical and organizational realities, there is one element that is completely out of the control of both the customer and cloud provider that makes public cloud an increased risk: the law. Ignoring this means you are not completely evaluating the "security" of potential deployment environments.
Some laws affect data management and controlThere are two main forms of "risk" associated with the law and the cloud. The first is explicit legal language that dictates how or where data should be stored, and penalties if those conditions aren't met. The EU's data privacy laws are one such example. The U.K.'s Data Protection Act of 1998 is another. U.S. export control laws are an especially interesting example, in my opinion.
The "risk" here is that the cloud provider may not be able to guarantee that where your data resides, or how it is transported across the network, won't be in violation of one of these laws. In IaaS, the end user typically has most of the responsibility in this respect, but PaaS and SaaS options hide much more of the detail about how data is handled and where it resides. Ultimately, it's up to you to make sure your data usage remains within the bounds of the law; to the extent you don't control of key factors in public clouds, that adds risk.
The cloud lacks a case lawThe second kind of risk that the cloud faces with the law, however, is much more nefarious. There are many "grey areas" in existing case law, across the globe, with respect to how cloud systems should be treated, and what rights a cloud user has with respect to data and intellectual property.
I spoke of the unresolved issues around the U.S. Constitution's Fourth Amendment protections against illegal search and seizure, but there are other outstanding legal questions that threaten the cloud's ability to protect users at the same level that their own data center facilities would. One example that is just coming to a head is the case of EMI versus MP3tunes.com.
Three years ago, EMI sued the company and it's founder and CEO, Michael Robertson, for willful infringement of copyright over the Internet. EMI claims that MP3tunes.com and its sister site, Sideload.com (a digital media search engine), are intentionally designed to enable users to violate music copyrights.
Robertson defends the sites as simply providing a storage service to end users, and therefore protected under the "safe harbor" provisions of the Digital Millennium Copyright Act. These provisions protect online services from prosecution under the DMCA as long as they remove infringing content when notified of it's presence.
At stake here is whether any online storage service (aka "cloud storage provider") is protected by the DMCA's safe harbor provisions, or if the very ability of users to find, upload and store infringing content is grounds for legal action. Even if MP3tunes is indeed found to be promoting infringement, what are the legal tests for identifying other such services? Will a new feature available at your favorite storage cloud suddenly put your provider--or worse, your data--at risk?
Yet another has to do with ownership of the physical resources, and what protections you have against losing your systems should those systems be seized for any reason. Imagine that your cloud provider was found to have been involved in violating federal law, and the FBI decided to seize all of their servers and disks for the investigation.
In this hypothetical situation, could you get your data back? What rights would you have? According to the 2009 case of a Texas colocation provider, in which 200 systems were seized--the vast majority of which belonged to the provider's clients, not the provider under investigation--very few.
There is no single "better option" for cloudI don't want to overstate the risks here. We've worked with colocation, outsourcing and even cloud offerings for a number of years now, and there have been very few "disastrous" run-ins with the law. Providers are aware of the problem, and provide architectures or features to help stay within the law. In the long term, these issues will work themselves out and public cloud environments will grow in popularity even before they are resolved.
However, making a blanket statement that public clouds are by de facto "more secure" than private clouds is just hype that ignores key realities of our fragile, nascent cloud marketplace. Until the market matures, the question of "better security" must take into account all factors that lead to risk in any given deployment scenario. With that context in mind, public and private clouds each have their weaknesses and strengths--which may vary from company to company or even application to application.
That said, Walls made one key point that I agree with emphatically. Just because a private cloud is behind your firewall, doesn't mean you don't have additional work to do to ensure the security of a private cloud environment. Having a data center does not automatically make you "more secure" than a public cloud provider any more than a cloud vendor is automatically more secure than anything an enterprise could do themselves.
</body>
	<comments>
		<comment id="0" responses="2">Cloud computing seems to be okay for low-priority non-secure archiving right now - music, family photos, that sort of thing; but for confidential information that is sensitive to a business, it still seems risky; <br /><br />- Cloud is on 24/7, while an office machine would be shut down 14 hours out of 24, reducing the risk of hacking somewhat.<br /><br />- Off-site storage could be subject to search and seizure; the police might decide to shut down the entire server your data is on, because a criminal's data happens to be on the same system - never mind the crime was committed in New York and you're in Wyoming.<br /><br />- Off-site storage could be prone to unexpected disruptions - aside from floods, fires &amp;#38; other disasters, there's always the chance that the company will go belly up, and take your data with it - the smaller ones at least.<br /><br />No, cloud may seem cool, but I will stick with the boring routines of on-site storage, with a dedicated pocket backup drive (or two) to archive vital files and store them off-site in the event of a disaster, just as I have always done.</comment>
		<comment id="1" responses="0">The cloud is all about giving big corporations your data so they can analyse it, for example for marketing purposes, and so that law enforcement agencies can access it very easily. At present, most of the data that businesses use is locked away on their own servers which are difficult to get at without a warrant and/or hacking.<br /><br />If you want a bigger picture on where all of this centralisation of media is taking us, check out what happens next after the information age, here : http://therecursionking.blogspot.com/2010/11/information-age-what-happens-next.html</comment>
		<comment id="2" responses="0">The legal issues surrounding a cloud environment at this point make it a risky proposition. What expectation of privacy is there when your data is in a public cloud? Who owns that data, the servers, and who is responsible if the data is compromised? Etc etc. <br /><br />I'd wait until the dust settles and most of these issues have worked themselves through courts before putting anything of significant importance in any public cloud environment.</comment>
	</comments>
	</post>
	</posts>
